/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375ed90c817f0398fbe3c0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-tough-is-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How tough is the CAT?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:24:56.932Z"),
    "question" : "How tough is the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375eec0c817f0398fbe3d3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-book-for-CAT-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Must Read these Books For CAT Preparation 2020 CAT Books For Quantitative Ability:NCERT mathematics books (6-10)These books are a good way to start if one needs to clear their basics and concepts. NCERT books are best to start your CAT Preparation with only if you have a lot of time before your exam date and need to brush up on concepts before solving advanced problems else not recommended.How to Prepare for Quantitative Aptitude for the CAT by Arun SharmaThis book by Arun Sharma (publisher: Tata McGraw Hill) is very popular among CAT aspirants and really easy and simple to understand. The USP of this book is that it has 3 levels of difficulty for each topic which helps students to prepare not only for CAT but also for other exams such as NMAT, SNAP, MAT, XAT, IIFT, etc.CAT books by Arun ShContinue Reading Must Read these Books For CAT Preparation 2020 CAT Books For Quantitative Ability:NCERT mathematics books (6-10)These books are a good way to start if one needs to clear their basics and concepts. NCERT books are best to start your CAT Preparation with only if you have a lot of time before your exam date and need to brush up on concepts before solving advanced problems else not recommended.How to Prepare for Quantitative Aptitude for the CAT by Arun SharmaThis book by Arun Sharma (publisher: Tata McGraw Hill) is very popular among CAT aspirants and really easy and simple to understand. The USP of this book is that it has 3 levels of difficulty for each topic which helps students to prepare not only for CAT but also for other exams such as NMAT, SNAP, MAT, XAT, IIFT, etc.CAT books by Arun ShContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:25:16.184Z"),
    "question" : "What are the recommended books/materials for the CAT exam preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375efd0c817f0398fbe3e1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-the-use-of-a-calculator-allowed-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "A2A. You are not allowed to take calculators with you inside the hall. There is on screen calculator provided for calculation in all sections in CAT 2015. But here is the catch. The level of questions is not set hard from calculation point of view. If you know the strategy to solve the question, you will be able to solve without using the calculator faster rather than using the calculator and spend a few minutes extra unnecessarily. So, I will advice you to be really good at mental maths and seeing the problems through a different perspective, for example, analyzing DI questions which involve calculating max./ min. ratio etc, seeing max. %age change from graph kind of questions using tricks or rough approx. calculations.Use calculators when it is an ultimate necessity in CAT. For practice, d Continue Reading A2A. You are not allowed to take calculators with you inside the hall. There is on screen calculator provided for calculation in all sections in CAT 2015. But here is the catch. The level of questions is not set hard from calculation point of view. If you know the strategy to solve the question, you will be able to solve without using the calculator faster rather than using the calculator and spend a few minutes extra unnecessarily. So, I will advice you to be really good at mental maths and seeing the problems through a different perspective, for example, analyzing DI questions which involve calculating max./ min. ratio etc, seeing max. %age change from graph kind of questions using tricks or rough approx. calculations.Use calculators when it is an ultimate necessity in CAT. For practice, d Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:25:33.644Z"),
    "question" : "Is the use of a calculator allowed in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375f170c817f0398fbe4ac"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-advantages-of-giving-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Common Admission Test or CAT is a national dimension directed by the Indian Institute of Management for admission to its 20 grounds. The CAT scores are acknowledged by over a 1000 business colleges the nation over for admission to their MBA/PGDM/PGPM/EPGP programs. In spite of the fact that it is up to the competitor that when he/she is prepared for CAT, showing up in it while still in the last year of graduation has its very own preferences. We will examine a couple of here. Advantage standpoint in preparation: Preparation for CAT test in any event requires 9 a year. For an applicant examining in the last year of Graduation, it is a perfect time to plan for CAT nearby their last year. BTech, BSc and BCom understudies can get ready better since a portion of the subjects in their course; parContinue Reading Common Admission Test or CAT is a national dimension directed by the Indian Institute of Management for admission to its 20 grounds. The CAT scores are acknowledged by over a 1000 business colleges the nation over for admission to their MBA/PGDM/PGPM/EPGP programs. In spite of the fact that it is up to the competitor that when he/she is prepared for CAT, showing up in it while still in the last year of graduation has its very own preferences. We will examine a couple of here. Advantage standpoint in preparation: Preparation for CAT test in any event requires 9 a year. For an applicant examining in the last year of Graduation, it is a perfect time to plan for CAT nearby their last year. BTech, BSc and BCom understudies can get ready better since a portion of the subjects in their course; parContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:25:59.249Z"),
    "question" : "What are the advantages of giving CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375f2a0c817f0398fbe4c2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-a-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "About CAT Exam - CAT exam or the Common Admission Test is a computer-based MBA entrance test for admissions into the IIMs and several other prestigious B-Schools in the Country. CAT exam is conducted every year by the IIMs on a rotational basis and CAT exam 2019 is expected to be conducted by IIM Kozhikode. The Common Admission Test is a computer based test held in India. The test scores a candidate on the bases of Quantitative Ability, Verbal Ability and Reading Comprehension, Data Interpretation and Logical Reasoning. CAT 2019 Exam date is November 24, 2019. Common Admission Test (CAT) 2019 is the mandatory entrance exam for admission to MBA 2020 in 20 IIMs and other top MBA colleges in India. The exam is therefore referred to as IIM CAT and is conducted by IIMs on annual basis.  CAT 2019 Ex Continue Reading About CAT Exam - CAT exam or the Common Admission Test is a computer-based MBA entrance test for admissions into the IIMs and several other prestigious B-Schools in the Country. CAT exam is conducted every year by the IIMs on a rotational basis and CAT exam 2019 is expected to be conducted by IIM Kozhikode. The Common Admission Test is a computer based test held in India. The test scores a candidate on the bases of Quantitative Ability, Verbal Ability and Reading Comprehension, Data Interpretation and Logical Reasoning. CAT 2019 Exam date is November 24, 2019. Common Admission Test (CAT) 2019 is the mandatory entrance exam for admission to MBA 2020 in 20 IIMs and other top MBA colleges in India. The exam is therefore referred to as IIM CAT and is conducted by IIMs on annual basis.  CAT 2019 Ex Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:26:18.189Z"),
    "question" : "What is a CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375f3b0c817f0398fbe4d1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-happens-after-cracking-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Anisha Mukhija Once the results for CAT are out, you will receive an SMS on your registered mobile number containing your CAT score and percentile. Now the admission process for different B-schools continue in more or less a similar fashion: You receive calls from institutes based on your CV and CAT score if you have made the cut.You then have to fill the application form for colleges separately. Some colleges ask for an SOP (Statement Of Purpose) as well.Once you have applied and have submitted the SOP (for the colleges that require an SOP), you will receive a mail regarding the date and venue of the interview and the rounds which will be included in the upcoming selection process.The selection process for most of the colleges have some or all the rounds listed below:Group Discussion: You are made to sit Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:26:35.799Z"),
    "question" : "What happens after cracking CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375f4e0c817f0398fbe58d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-benefit-of-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Saurav Vatsayan Tripathi Common Admission Test (CAT) is one of the toughest entrance exam for those who desire to make a career in management and business administration i.e. MBA. This examination was started in 1950 and is conducted by the Indian Institutes of Management (IIMs) on a rotational basis. The CAT score is valid for 1 year and considered for admission by most of the top 50 B-schools. Mode of exam — Online i. e. computer based exam .  Total no of IIM's - 20 Except IIM's Some IIT's also offer MBA Courses and accept CAT Score. IIT BombayIIT DelhiIIT kanpurIIT KharagpurIIT MadrasIIT (ISM) DhanbadIIT RoorkieTIER 1 - Colleges accept CAT Score Faculty of Management Studies, Delhi - takes CAT score.Xavier Labour Research Institute, Jamshedpur - takes CAT scoreS.P. Jain Institute of Management & Research, Mumbai - SPJEContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:26:54.516Z"),
    "question" : "What is the benefit of CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375f630c817f0398fbe5a3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-eligibility-criteria-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Aman Arora CAT exam or the Common Admission Test is a computer-based MBA entrance test for admissions into the IIMs and several other prestigious B-Schools in the Country. CAT exam is conducted every year by the IIMs on a rotational basis and CAT exam 2019 is expected to be conducted by IIM Kozhikode. CAT 2019 Eligibility Criteria for General & Reserved category candidates define different percentage of marks in the qualifying graduation degree. However, there is no age bar for either category candidates to apply for IIMCAT 2019 exam.  CAT Eligibility for General & NC-OBC Candidates The candidate must hold Bachelor’s Degree with at least 50% marks or equivalent CGPA.Candidates in final year of Graduation are also eligible to apply for CAT 2019If selected, the final year candidates will be allowed to joinContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:27:15.305Z"),
    "question" : "What is the eligibility criteria for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375f760c817f0398fbe5b1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-was-the-CAT-exam-today?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the benefit of CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:27:34.262Z"),
    "question" : "How was the CAT exam today? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375f8a0c817f0398fbe676"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-fair-for-IIMs-to-grant-women-extra-marks-in-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "IIMs never grant women extra marks in CAT. Extra marks are added in shortlisting stages to the index score.  Almost everyone who has ranted below have not made it. And a lot of them who have supported it have made it. I concur this is because they have seen results. By that I mean they have seen their female classmates do well in the institute, seen them get shortlisted by so many firms these guys were rejected from. They have seen some of the top firms recruit smart clever girls left right and center with zero explanation. With a 99.99 percentile, they have watched hundreds of the same firms toss them aside. So,to the person who has posted this question and to those who have ranted below- I will say, come to a B school, and you will realize how much the industry wants girls. The industry n Continue Reading Continue Reading Rajesh Balasubramanian",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:27:54.593Z"),
    "question" : "Is it fair for IIMs to grant women extra marks in CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375f9c0c817f0398fbe68b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-the-CAT-exam-difficult?-",
    "answer" : "Is bungi jumping difficult? If you'd ask me I would say yes because I have a phobia of height. But, many people do so without any hesitation and with much pleasure.  Why there is a difference? Because the benchmark is different for different people. Similar analogy could be followed for CAT. It is not that difficult given you've studied enough and have a good mastery over the underlying concepts.  World is no different for you. Many people coming from diverse backgrounds have got into IIMs. Start preparing for it and follow these steps :  Study success stories of different people, observe what they have done that you can borrow and implement in your case. Make a study plan and follow it religiously. Yes, make it a habit. Discipline is what it takes. Keep notes of small but tricky concepts suchContinue Reading Is bungi jumping difficult? If you'd ask me I would say yes because I have a phobia of height. But, many people do so without any hesitation and with much pleasure.  Why there is a difference? Because the benchmark is different for different people. Similar analogy could be followed for CAT. It is not that difficult given you've studied enough and have a good mastery over the underlying concepts.  World is no different for you. Many people coming from diverse backgrounds have got into IIMs. Start preparing for it and follow these steps :  Study success stories of different people, observe what they have done that you can borrow and implement in your case. Make a study plan and follow it religiously. Yes, make it a habit. Discipline is what it takes. Keep notes of small but tricky concepts suchContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:28:12.337Z"),
    "question" : "Is the CAT exam difficult? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375fc50c817f0398fbe758"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-crack-the-CAT-without-attending-any-coaching-classes?-",
    "answer" : "Ravi Atal I believe this question needs to be answered so I am taking break from whatever other fields I am exploring to answer this one. This will be long, but if you intend to do it, it will be worth a read. Assumptions You need to score at least 98 percentile to be classified as “ Crack the CAT “Its OK, if you don’t have genius level intellect but you should be willing to work hard. Consequently if you have genius level intellect you can manage with average work, however greater efforts is always directly proportional to higher percentile.Declaration I am writing the names of the books/subject material which I found good, there is no ulterior motives for that. I have seen many books and materials and may have missed even more. What I am writing, is what I believe is good for an average student. Prepa Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:28:53.011Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to crack the CAT without attending any coaching classes? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375fea0c817f0398fbe77b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-syllabus-of-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "I have tried to break down the syllabus of the CAT paper in as much detail as possible in my answer below. To ease the process, I will also post a simplified version of the same captured graphically before I dive into the longer format.  Now, on to the much elaborate version :- WHAT DOES A CAT PAPER CONTAIN? The CAT basically tests a candidate’s aptitude in three areas which are divided into 3 sections as Quantitative Aptitude, Verbal Ability and the Data Interpretation-Logical Reasoning Sections. The Quantitative Aptitude(QA) is nothing but Mathematics (tests concepts that appear up till 10th grade)The Verbal Ability(VA) tests one’s basic knowledge of English language (High-School grammar, ability to read and comprehend long passages from different genres, abiContinue Reading I have tried to break down the syllabus of the CAT paper in as much detail as possible in my answer below. To ease the process, I will also post a simplified version of the same captured graphically before I dive into the longer format.  Now, on to the much elaborate version :- WHAT DOES A CAT PAPER CONTAIN? The CAT basically tests a candidate’s aptitude in three areas which are divided into 3 sections as Quantitative Aptitude, Verbal Ability and the Data Interpretation-Logical Reasoning Sections. The Quantitative Aptitude(QA) is nothing but Mathematics (tests concepts that appear up till 10th grade)The Verbal Ability(VA) tests one’s basic knowledge of English language (High-School grammar, ability to read and comprehend long passages from different genres, abiContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:29:30.531Z"),
    "question" : "What is the syllabus of the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60375ffe0c817f0398fbe794"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-myself-for-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "I will try to keep it as detailed as possible but before beginning, these were my sectional percentiles in CAT 2019: VARC: 97.80 DILR: 96.59 QA: 98.20 OA: 98.89 My profile: 10th: 10 CGPA 12th: 95.4% Graduation: 8.784 GPA I will discuss section-wise strategy for ease of reading/understanding. VARC: I mainly focused on reading a lot. Reading gradually increases speed and comprehension, two things which are very important for CAT. For reading sources, I mainly relied on the editorial section of newspapers like The Indian Express and Mint. Reading editorials not only improves comprehension skills and reading speed but also prepares one for the upcoming GDPI season by giving perspective on current happenings. Reading also assumes importance as around 24/34 questions in the VARC section are based on readin Continue Reading I will try to keep it as detailed as possible but before beginning, these were my sectional percentiles in CAT 2019: VARC: 97.80 DILR: 96.59 QA: 98.20 OA: 98.89 My profile: 10th: 10 CGPA 12th: 95.4% Graduation: 8.784 GPA I will discuss section-wise strategy for ease of reading/understanding. VARC: I mainly focused on reading a lot. Reading gradually increases speed and comprehension, two things which are very important for CAT. For reading sources, I mainly relied on the editorial section of newspapers like The Indian Express and Mint. Reading editorials not only improves comprehension skills and reading speed but also prepares one for the upcoming GDPI season by giving perspective on current happenings. Reading also assumes importance as around 24/34 questions in the VARC section are based on readin Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:29:50.206Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare myself for CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603760140c817f0398fbe854"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-improve-my-VARC-results-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Shobhit Khandelwal, CAT'16 VARC: 99.74%ileUpdated 3 years agoHow do I improve my VARC results for the CAT exam? Shobhit Khandelwal CAT’15 VA/RC: 85%ile CAT’16 VA/RC: 99.74%ile Now, what did I do differently? A brief answer would be that I developed the below mentioned four skills. I believe these four skills are must to score good in verbal section of any management entrance exam in India- 1. Above average vocabulary (including common foreign words) 2. Familiarity with varied topics and the common jargon of every topic (Economics, Philosophy, Science and Technology, Literature, etc.) 3. Skill to read and comprehend any topic in English language, even if you like it or not! I would rather define it as ‘skill of cold reading’ i.e., having no empathy/apathy towards the subject 4. Ability to answer the questions, even if you don’t understand the passage completely (believe me, it can be done) I think, if anyone develops these skil Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:30:12.279Z"),
    "question" : "How do I improve my VARC results for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603760270c817f0398fbe863"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-you-prepare-for-CAT?-Which-books-did-you-refer-to?-",
    "answer" : "For someone who has answered on CAT preparation in bits and pieces in the past, compiling all the previous inputs and answering a question like this is rather difficult. But, I’ll try to pen them down into 10 short chapters: Chapter 1 - The Beginning I was pursuing B Com (H) from Kirori Mal College and in the first semester, I got myself Arun Sharma’s QA book for CAT. Then somewhere towards the end of the first year, I purchased Arun Sharma’s other books. At that time, I knew I might need to take coaching, yet I purchased self-prep books, 6 months in advance so that: I could familiarize myself with the pattern & syllabus of the exam.I could identify my weak spots and bring them up to the mark.Chapter 2 - Six Months Later I had certainly not solved even the easiest level of questions, let alone Continue Reading For someone who has answered on CAT preparation in bits and pieces in the past, compiling all the previous inputs and answering a question like this is rather difficult. But, I’ll try to pen them down into 10 short chapters: Chapter 1 - The Beginning I was pursuing B Com (H) from Kirori Mal College and in the first semester, I got myself Arun Sharma’s QA book for CAT. Then somewhere towards the end of the first year, I purchased Arun Sharma’s other books. At that time, I knew I might need to take coaching, yet I purchased self-prep books, 6 months in advance so that: I could familiarize myself with the pattern & syllabus of the exam.I could identify my weak spots and bring them up to the mark.Chapter 2 - Six Months Later I had certainly not solved even the easiest level of questions, let alone Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:30:31.590Z"),
    "question" : "How did you prepare for CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037603b0c817f0398fbe87e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-necessary-is-coaching-for-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "If you wish to become a good cricketer, it is quite obvious that you will take coaching. Lets think of the batting talent of three players. Yuvraj Singh is exceptionally gifted, Rahul Dravid who has decent natural talent and Ravichandran Ashwin (who is primarily a bowler) with average batting skills. All three underwent coaching to become the best batsman that they can. They needed support in order to reach their highest potential in batting. What are the three most important inputs that come through a cricket coach? The first is of course ‘building the skills’ or teaching the techniques of batting (in CAT it is skills in VARC, DILR and quants). The second is the discipline to stick to a plan/schedule and to implement it. And the third and critical aspect is the mental toughness to handle p Continue Reading If you wish to become a good cricketer, it is quite obvious that you will take coaching. Lets think of the batting talent of three players. Yuvraj Singh is exceptionally gifted, Rahul Dravid who has decent natural talent and Ravichandran Ashwin (who is primarily a bowler) with average batting skills. All three underwent coaching to become the best batsman that they can. They needed support in order to reach their highest potential in batting. What are the three most important inputs that come through a cricket coach? The first is of course ‘building the skills’ or teaching the techniques of batting (in CAT it is skills in VARC, DILR and quants). The second is the discipline to stick to a plan/schedule and to implement it. And the third and critical aspect is the mental toughness to handle p Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:30:51.403Z"),
    "question" : "How necessary is coaching for CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037604c0c817f0398fbe938"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-much-time-is-sufficient-for-the-preparation-of-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "If you are good with the basics then 6–7 months else 10–12 months to be on safe side. If i had to give you generalized CAT prep plan ,then here it is- Take an diagnostic test for CAT(or solve past year paper) to know where you stand in terms of level of your Maths,English ,LR/DI .Though this has become quite repetitive in my post ,but you got to be boring ,you got to follow the routines for days & months if you wish to be successful in your CAT exam. You can maintain excel sheet and note down you strong and weak areas .You can then dedicate like 60% of time for weak areas and remaining for strong . As far as book is concerned - I will suggest CBSE NCERT book for Maths,English and Arihant for LR/DI .Though Arun Sharma is good for Maths ,but given the level of quant in past two year . I wont sug Continue Reading If you are good with the basics then 6–7 months else 10–12 months to be on safe side. If i had to give you generalized CAT prep plan ,then here it is- Take an diagnostic test for CAT(or solve past year paper) to know where you stand in terms of level of your Maths,English ,LR/DI .Though this has become quite repetitive in my post ,but you got to be boring ,you got to follow the routines for days & months if you wish to be successful in your CAT exam. You can maintain excel sheet and note down you strong and weak areas .You can then dedicate like 60% of time for weak areas and remaining for strong . As far as book is concerned - I will suggest CBSE NCERT book for Maths,English and Arihant for LR/DI .Though Arun Sharma is good for Maths ,but given the level of quant in past two year . I wont sug Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:31:08.673Z"),
    "question" : "How much time is sufficient for the preparation of the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037605f0c817f0398fbe949"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-start-preparing-for-the-CAT-exam-2017-to-get-into-IIMs-with-99-percentile?-",
    "answer" : "Other answers have covered what you should do in terms of standard approach which should be taken in order to score 99+ percentile in CAT pretty well. My approach would be a little different from them as I believe that fretting over the exam will do you more harm than good. For QA section, you should choose any one book that you believe is sufficient for you. I'd recommend the one by Arun Sharma if you need to study the basics and wish to learn some neat tricks for solving questions on QA. On the other hand, if you're good at QA and only need to brush up the basics, you can try quantitative aptitude for competitive exams by RS Agarwal. Note that the book for general maths slightly different as compared to the competitive one. And if someone tells you that RS Agarwal is not good for CAT prep Continue Reading Other answers have covered what you should do in terms of standard approach which should be taken in order to score 99+ percentile in CAT pretty well. My approach would be a little different from them as I believe that fretting over the exam will do you more harm than good. For QA section, you should choose any one book that you believe is sufficient for you. I'd recommend the one by Arun Sharma if you need to study the basics and wish to learn some neat tricks for solving questions on QA. On the other hand, if you're good at QA and only need to brush up the basics, you can try quantitative aptitude for competitive exams by RS Agarwal. Note that the book for general maths slightly different as compared to the competitive one. And if someone tells you that RS Agarwal is not good for CAT prep Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:31:27.459Z"),
    "question" : "How should I start preparing for the CAT exam 2017 to get into IIMs with 99 percentile? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603760770c817f0398fbe964"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-an-average-student-crack-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Can an average student crack CAT? Let me introduce myself. I consider myself an average student. I went to IIT (just got in, to be precise). I took CAT 4 times. I managed 99+ twice in CAT, without any coaching. My lowest sectional score was 75 percentile. With some efforts, I managed well above 99 percentile in that section in my last attempt. I have had interview calls from all IIMs except Bangalore. (No, I did not go to IIM for an MBA).  Answer in short : Yes. You can.  But, Work hard Long Answer: Firstly, I presume you want to get admission in an IIM. For that, clearing CAT will not suffice. Believe me, I got rejected in half a dozen interviews and I know 100 percentilers rejected by IIM.  Clearing CAT: As you would know, there are three sections in CAT exam. Prepare for all of them.  The Quant section was easy last time. T Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:31:51.200Z"),
    "question" : "Can an average student crack CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037609d0c817f0398fbea2d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-times-can-one-take-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Hey there, There is no limitation to no. of attempts. You can attempt this exam multiple times you wish to. There is no age limitation as well. But your score will be valid only for that year period. Every year more than 1.5 lakh aspirant register for CAT exam , close to 1–1.2 lakh sit for the exam & real competition is between 20–30k student probably a lot less than that for 10k seats in top management college. You should focus more on your CAT & other management exam preparation ,for CAT 2017 & OTHER EXAM THERE IS STILL 5 MONTHS LEFT. So to kickstart your preparation , firstly take an diagnostic test for CAT(or solve past year paper) to know where you stand in terms of level of your Maths,English ,LR/DI . Its just like pre-board where you get to know your strong and weak areas and work upon t Continue Reading Hey there, There is no limitation to no. of attempts. You can attempt this exam multiple times you wish to. There is no age limitation as well. But your score will be valid only for that year period. Every year more than 1.5 lakh aspirant register for CAT exam , close to 1–1.2 lakh sit for the exam & real competition is between 20–30k student probably a lot less than that for 10k seats in top management college. You should focus more on your CAT & other management exam preparation ,for CAT 2017 & OTHER EXAM THERE IS STILL 5 MONTHS LEFT. So to kickstart your preparation , firstly take an diagnostic test for CAT(or solve past year paper) to know where you stand in terms of level of your Maths,English ,LR/DI . Its just like pre-board where you get to know your strong and weak areas and work upon t Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:32:29.464Z"),
    "question" : "How many times can one take the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603760c30c817f0398fbeb02"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-improve-my-verbal-ability-for-the-CAT-examination?-",
    "answer" : "Narendra Patil, studied at Dwarkadas J. Sanghvi College of Engineering (2017)Answered 2 years agoHow do I improve my verbal ability for the CAT examination? Narendra Patil",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:33:07.082Z"),
    "question" : "How do I improve my verbal ability for the CAT examination? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603760e60c817f0398fbeb20"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-marks-is-a-CAT-exam-conducted-for?-",
    "answer" : "Kamlesh Chauhan, IIM Ahmedabad alumnus, MD, BfactoryAnswered 1 year ago · Author has 588 answers and 1.5M answer viewsHow many marks is a CAT exam conducted for? Kamlesh Chauhan CAT is not a single paper but an exam with 3 papers of 1 hour each without any break. The questions are for 2 formats: Multiple Choice Questions (MCQ) and Type In The Answer (TITA). The marking scheme for MCQ is +3 for correct attempts, 0 for unattempted questions and -1 for incorrect attempts. Following is the syllabus of each of the sections: Verbal Ability, VA (34 questions, 1 hour)Reading Comprehension (RC): 24 MCQ in 5 different RCs. The number of questions from each RC varies from 3 to 6.Para Jumble (PJ): 4 TITA questions: Finding the correct arrangement of 4/5 sentences to form a coherent paragraph.Odd One Out (OOO): 3 TITA questions: You have to find the sentence which is not part of the paragraph formed from given sentences. Actually, these are MCQ questions given in TITA format.PaContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:33:42.917Z"),
    "question" : "How many marks is a CAT exam conducted for? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603760fe0c817f0398fbebe6"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-increase-my-speed-while-preparing-for-the-quant-section-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How can I increase my speed while preparing for the quant section for the CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:34:06.723Z"),
    "question" : "How can I increase my speed while preparing for the quant section for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603761160c817f0398fbebf9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Where-can-I-find-free-video-lectures-for-the-CAT-exam-preparation-in-a-proper-order?-",
    "answer" : "I liked your question. You were just not asking about the CAT videos, You want to get in a proper order. Since, on youtube and other online portals there are so many videos content available related to CAT but you have mentioned one thing that is - Videos should be in a proper order. Through, you will get the chance to learn the things more clearly and detailed way. You can go here and learn the things step-by-step which is important for CAT Handakafunda- Best Online Tutorials for CAT,XAT,IIFT and GK The best part of handa ka funda is, If you stuck in some video or other tutorial. You can directly ask Ravi handa sir or other team mates. You will get the best organised free video lectures for the CAT, additionally you will get the 24*7 support. If you have any Query/You can write in comment b Continue Reading I liked your question. You were just not asking about the CAT videos, You want to get in a proper order. Since, on youtube and other online portals there are so many videos content available related to CAT but you have mentioned one thing that is - Videos should be in a proper order. Through, you will get the chance to learn the things more clearly and detailed way. You can go here and learn the things step-by-step which is important for CAT Handakafunda- Best Online Tutorials for CAT,XAT,IIFT and GK The best part of handa ka funda is, If you stuck in some video or other tutorial. You can directly ask Ravi handa sir or other team mates. You will get the best organised free video lectures for the CAT, additionally you will get the 24*7 support. If you have any Query/You can write in comment b Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:34:30.278Z"),
    "question" : "Where can I find free video lectures for the CAT exam preparation in a proper order? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603761290c817f0398fbec11"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-we-take-CAT-exam-in-2nd-year?-",
    "answer" : "Sai Yagnesh Chadalavada You can take CAT in any year of your graduation, but, only the CAT taken in your graduating year or “final” year will be valid. You could also write it any time after graduation while working. But, there should be no relaxation. I mean to say, you should either be working in a company/startup/NGO or should be studying a recognised degree. Bottom line, there's no use taking CAT in second year. You have to take it in the final year of your degree. What you could do instead is you can start preparing for CAT and answer as many mock CATs as you can. You should be able to finish answering at least 50 mock CATs one year before the actual CAT which is held in November. You have a lot of time. So, know the syllabus of CAT, have the concepts clear, start reading newspaper if you haven't done it alrea Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:34:49.725Z"),
    "question" : "Can we take CAT exam in 2nd year? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603761400c817f0398fbecd2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-top-10-sensible-hollywood-movies-must-a-student-preparing-for-CAT-exam-watch?-",
    "answer" : "Jaideep Kumar Dutta 12 Angry Men (1957): A wonderful movie that was part of my MBA curriculum, 12 Angry Men is probably the best thing you can watch on the art of negotiation and persuasion.To Kill a Mockingbird (1962): I love the book and I make no effort to hide it. The 1962 adaptation by Robert Mulligan does complete justice to the book. It's a life lesson everyone should learn. It teaches you kindness, courage, and unflinching devotion to the pursuit of justice even in the face of overwhelming odds.More about the book and what makes it great: Deepak Mehta (दीपक मेहता)'s answer to Why do you like the book 'To Kill a Mockingbird,' and why should I read it?Up in the Air (2009): As a manager (post your MBA), one of the hardest aspects of your job would be to fire people. In this movie, George Clooney will tContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:35:12.099Z"),
    "question" : "What top 10 sensible hollywood movies must a student preparing for CAT exam watch? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603761550c817f0398fbece0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-biggest-myth-about-clearing-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers What is the biggest myth about clearing the CAT exam? Well, I'm happy, to say the least. 99.96 with no prep other than the TIME test series, is pretty alright. CAT 2017 result day is not a day of rejoicing( coz it is FAR too early for that ), rather it is a day to sit down and figure out what next. I'm glad that I've received a call from IIM A, B, C, L,I and K, but for those people who keep enquiring: “wow, so admission in IIM is pretty much assured, right? “, here is where even a good percentile of 99.96 puts me, in the overall ratings race for a seat at IIM A: (Being in love with mathematics, I decided to sit down and do the actual math behind shortlisting at IIM A) CONCEPT 1: Application Rating(AR) Max: 30 , i.e 10+10+10 for class 10, class 12 and undergrad respectively ( AVG AR of top 50 applicants is 30/30) Quick Example:CGPA scores:(post conv Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:35:33.465Z"),
    "question" : "What is the biggest myth about clearing the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603761680c817f0398fbeda1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-cat-easy?-",
    "answer" : "It depends on what is easy. I would look at easy in terms of how easy it is to get into a desired college, say a top 25 MBA college, which give good placements. If you check the ratio of number of students who get into a desired college, or goal as compared to students who appear for the entrance, it definitely favours CAT. Look at any other exam including MBA CET, UPSC, Banking exam, etc, the proportion of students getting into a career of their choice is much smaller as compared to those writing CAT exam. What I have also noticed is that half the students who write CAT exam are non serious. They write the exam just for practice or without any hope as they have given up preparation. So, why is the exam considered tough. CAT is quite a different exam as compared to a lot of other entrance exam Continue Reading It depends on what is easy. I would look at easy in terms of how easy it is to get into a desired college, say a top 25 MBA college, which give good placements. If you check the ratio of number of students who get into a desired college, or goal as compared to students who appear for the entrance, it definitely favours CAT. Look at any other exam including MBA CET, UPSC, Banking exam, etc, the proportion of students getting into a career of their choice is much smaller as compared to those writing CAT exam. What I have also noticed is that half the students who write CAT exam are non serious. They write the exam just for practice or without any hope as they have given up preparation. So, why is the exam considered tough. CAT is quite a different exam as compared to a lot of other entrance exam Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:35:52.323Z"),
    "question" : "Is cat easy? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037617c0c817f0398fbedb8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-attempts-can-I-give-for-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Dear Dhanaji, There is no limit set by IIMs yet for number of attempts allowed with respect to CAT exam even there is no age limit defined. But when you start preparing for CAT don’t give yourself more than one attempt. This will keep you focused to achieve required results. Best of Luck.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:36:12.128Z"),
    "question" : "How many attempts can I give for CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603761c00c817f0398fbee9e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "CAT is one of the most popular and reputed exam for students aspiring to take admission in top management colleges in India.Students become anxious and tend to under-perform by make silly mistakes even after rigorous preparation. The key to success in this case is- Practice.  Let’s start by analyzing the pattern of the exam. The exam consists of two sections- Quantitative Aptitude & Data Interpretation; the second section is Verbal Ability & Logical Reasoning. The basic syllabus for this exam roughly corresponds to Maths and English taught in class VI- IX. So if your fundamentals are strong, you don’t need to spend much time in building up the concepts and can focus on practicing. The exam is not merely meant to test your quant and verbal skills but also on time management and stress manage Continue Reading CAT is one of the most popular and reputed exam for students aspiring to take admission in top management colleges in India.Students become anxious and tend to under-perform by make silly mistakes even after rigorous preparation. The key to success in this case is- Practice.  Let’s start by analyzing the pattern of the exam. The exam consists of two sections- Quantitative Aptitude & Data Interpretation; the second section is Verbal Ability & Logical Reasoning. The basic syllabus for this exam roughly corresponds to Maths and English taught in class VI- IX. So if your fundamentals are strong, you don’t need to spend much time in building up the concepts and can focus on practicing. The exam is not merely meant to test your quant and verbal skills but also on time management and stress manage Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:37:20.408Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603761d40c817f0398fbeeb1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-should-I-take-CAT-exam-seriously?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Why should I take CAT exam seriously? Do you have good business acumen?Are you entrepreneurial? Are you ambitious?Do you dream of being a CEO or starting your own company and making it big?Then IIMs are the right place for you. You will have all the tools you need to have a great career in the business world.What are the major parts of an MBA? EconomicsFinanceMarketingOperationsHRMInformation Systems (IT)Public policy and legal stuff.How is the methodology of an MBA course different from engineering? The case method - based on real-life business scenarios that might have occurred in the past in some other company. You read the case, come to class and discuss.Projects - You work with your professor. Establish objectives and work towards a real-life project that is part of your course.Presentations - You present your findingContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:37:40.470Z"),
    "question" : "Why should I take CAT exam seriously? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603761e80c817f0398fbef78"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-key-points-to-be-remembered-while-taking-cat-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Hi, The key points to remember and follow while writing the CAT exams in my opinion are: A. Before the starting of exam: Instructions and Guidelines for the exam: Make sure that you go through the CAT website as well as any E-Mail that is sent by the CAT administrators containing the instructions for the candidates appearing for the exam. It will have the details of what is allowed and what is not allowed. Make sure to follow this to avoid unnecessary distraction at the exam venue. Carry all the necessary documents required for you to get an admission to the venue.Details on Desktop: Once you complete the Biometric registration, you will be directed to your allocated seat, make sure to check if your details are properly mentioned. If not point it out to the concerned staff.Mouse: It is a veryContinue Reading Hi, The key points to remember and follow while writing the CAT exams in my opinion are: A. Before the starting of exam: Instructions and Guidelines for the exam: Make sure that you go through the CAT website as well as any E-Mail that is sent by the CAT administrators containing the instructions for the candidates appearing for the exam. It will have the details of what is allowed and what is not allowed. Make sure to follow this to avoid unnecessary distraction at the exam venue. Carry all the necessary documents required for you to get an admission to the venue.Details on Desktop: Once you complete the Biometric registration, you will be directed to your allocated seat, make sure to check if your details are properly mentioned. If not point it out to the concerned staff.Mouse: It is a veryContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:38:00.390Z"),
    "question" : "What are the key points to be remembered while taking cat exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603761fe0c817f0398fbef8a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-of-the-best-YouTube-channels-dedicated-to-CAT-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "There are a lot of YouTube channels that offer free content for CAT Preparation. I have used (and heard of) a few of them, and hence, would like to talk about the following (This is not ranking, it is just a list and are all of them the awesome, without being in any particular order): -  TOPMYTEST TOPMYTEST is probably the latest entrant in CAT Preparation Industry and I personally believe that they are here to stay. I like them not because of the quality/quantity of their content, but because of the type of content they post. One of my favorite series they have launched is ‘MBA Prep Talk.’ Personally, I believe that CAT is not only a knowledge game, but it is a strategy game too. And so far, they have covered quite a good deal of content in terms of strategy for CAT. Also, they are now launch Continue Reading There are a lot of YouTube channels that offer free content for CAT Preparation. I have used (and heard of) a few of them, and hence, would like to talk about the following (This is not ranking, it is just a list and are all of them the awesome, without being in any particular order): -  TOPMYTEST TOPMYTEST is probably the latest entrant in CAT Preparation Industry and I personally believe that they are here to stay. I like them not because of the quality/quantity of their content, but because of the type of content they post. One of my favorite series they have launched is ‘MBA Prep Talk.’ Personally, I believe that CAT is not only a knowledge game, but it is a strategy game too. And so far, they have covered quite a good deal of content in terms of strategy for CAT. Also, they are now launch Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:38:22.130Z"),
    "question" : "What are some of the best YouTube channels dedicated to CAT preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603762170c817f0398fbefa1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-prepare-for-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How should I prepare for the CAT?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:38:47.635Z"),
    "question" : "How should I prepare for the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037622f0c817f0398fbf068"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-best-CAT-exam-stories?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers What are some best CAT exam stories? Saw this story on Insideiim so i thought i would share it. This is my story and it is a story of hope…. “Every event has a purpose and every setback its lesson. I have realized that failure, whether of the personal, professional or even spiritual kind, is essential to personal expansion. It brings inner growth and a whole host of psychic rewards. Never regret your past. Rather, embrace it as the teacher that it is.” ― Robin S. Sharma Today is 26th April 2016, it’s 4:30 PM and the result of IIM Kozhikode has just been declared. As my trembling hands open the IIM K website my mind drifts back to the moment where it all started, The day I solved my first quant question. I still remember the sheer rush of blood and exhilaration I experienced at the prospect of preparing for CAT. “So how is it all Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:39:11.733Z"),
    "question" : "What are some best CAT exam stories? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603762460c817f0398fbf079"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-vocabulary-books-for-cat-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Best Vocabulary Tips For Cat Entrance  \"1) Read read and read- Most vocabulary words are learned from context. The more words you are exposed to, the better vocabulary you will have. While you read pay close attention to the words you don't know. First try to figure out their meaning from context, then look the words up. Read and listen to challenging material so that you will be exposed too many new words. 2) Improve your context skills- Research shows that the vast majority of words are learned from context. To improve your context skills pay close attention to how words are used. Doing a search on a word in dictionary will give you many examples of how that word is used in context. 3) Practice, practise and practise-. As soon as you learn a new word, start using it. Review your index card p Continue Reading Best Vocabulary Tips For Cat Entrance  \"1) Read read and read- Most vocabulary words are learned from context. The more words you are exposed to, the better vocabulary you will have. While you read pay close attention to the words you don't know. First try to figure out their meaning from context, then look the words up. Read and listen to challenging material so that you will be exposed too many new words. 2) Improve your context skills- Research shows that the vast majority of words are learned from context. To improve your context skills pay close attention to how words are used. Doing a search on a word in dictionary will give you many examples of how that word is used in context. 3) Practice, practise and practise-. As soon as you learn a new word, start using it. Review your index card p Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:39:34.876Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best vocabulary books for cat exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037625d0c817f0398fbf13d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-things-you-learned-only-after-appearing-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Sanjana Pareek CAT , just like other exams, is an exam where your performance on the D-Day is all that matters. How much you slogged, how many midnight lamps you burnt nobody cares. How you perform on that one day is all that matters. Below is my experience, not only with the actual CAT exam but also the months spent preparing for it. Since I tend to philosophise at times, I have been able to relate a lot of stuff I realised with the journey called Life. I have put these points below, hope you enjoy. Unpredictability: Both in 2011 and 2014 (the only years I appeared for the exam) the pattern changed from what it was the year before. 2011 they went from paper-pen to online. 2014 they increased the number of questions. Lesson learnt: CAT is unpredictable, difficulty levels change, patterns change, weightage Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:39:57.088Z"),
    "question" : "What are the things you learned only after appearing for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603762700c817f0398fbf151"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-the-CAT-exam-3-year-rule-real?-",
    "answer" : "We might have to dig a little deeper to answer this. If you go by probability, then it might look real to you, but that may not be the case. So, let us find on what does a person's selection in CAT depends. It basically boils down to the candidates quality (his/her academic profile). Now, we will see how different types of people get selected in CAT - A person with a great profile (preferably from the IITs, an MBBS or a CA), is most likely to crack CAT in his first attempt, given that he has a background in cracking tough exams and a logical mindset (by cracking i don't mean only A,B,C but maybe top 15–20 institutes). He/She doesn't need that extra push because they are well accustomed with pressure situations related to academics and can handle such strategic exams very well. A lot of my IContinue Reading We might have to dig a little deeper to answer this. If you go by probability, then it might look real to you, but that may not be the case. So, let us find on what does a person's selection in CAT depends. It basically boils down to the candidates quality (his/her academic profile). Now, we will see how different types of people get selected in CAT - A person with a great profile (preferably from the IITs, an MBBS or a CA), is most likely to crack CAT in his first attempt, given that he has a background in cracking tough exams and a logical mindset (by cracking i don't mean only A,B,C but maybe top 15–20 institutes). He/She doesn't need that extra push because they are well accustomed with pressure situations related to academics and can handle such strategic exams very well. A lot of my IContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:40:16.602Z"),
    "question" : "Is the CAT exam 3-year rule real? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603762970c817f0398fbf21c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-newspaper-should-we-read-during-CAT-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which newspaper should we read during CAT preparation?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:40:55.100Z"),
    "question" : "Which newspaper should we read during CAT preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603762ab0c817f0398fbf233"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-should-I-prepare-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "6 months of preparation is more than enough. Start now. 2-3 hours a day will do. Revise all topics in a span of 2-3 months. Devote your last 3 months to Mocks. Attempt atleast 20 mocks, analyse them, and solve again. Do revise all your mocks 2 weeks before writing actual CAT. Best of luck. 3",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:41:15.540Z"),
    "question" : "When should I prepare for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603762bf0c817f0398fbf246"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-always-be-motivated-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Patrick Dsouza Each individual is different and what motivates one may not motivate the other. There are many ways to keep yourself motivated. You need to search the best that works for you. I will list down a few based on my experience. Before I start, let me tell you that I have found it difficult to keep myself motivated. So I do have many off days where I find difficult to do my chores. But that is fine. I do not fret over it. Once I am over my lethargy, I try to begin afresh. One thing that has motivated me from time to time are the quotes I read from books. I particularly remember a couple of them. One was from a book by Dale Carnegie. He had said that don't worry about how difficult your goal is, if you work towards your goal every moment of your life, you will be successful. You may not reach your Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:41:35.879Z"),
    "question" : "How can I always be motivated for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603762d10c817f0398fbf302"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-CAT-exam-in-2-days?-",
    "answer" : "Let me share my experience of having written the CAT for fun back in 2009 or 10.  The background I am a lawyer by qualification. One evening when I was out with friends I met this one guy from IIM-B, a friend of a friend. We were chatting about our college experiences when we came upon the subject of the competitive exam. We each discussed the merits and demerits of the CAT and the law school entrance exams and he was pretty certain that the CAT was by far the more comprehensive and thereby harder of the two. So I proposed an experiment, that we would each take the other exam, just for fun, and see who does better. We did some research and as it turned out he was over age for the law school exam. Undeterred, I decided to take the CAT in any case to see what the fuss was about. D-Day With zero pr Continue Reading Continue Reading Rahul Anand",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:41:53.714Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for CAT exam in 2 days? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603762e80c817f0398fbf319"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-does-one-improve-reading-speed-for-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "CAT speed reading holds relevance in both the verbal and the non verbal sections of CAT. Verbal Section: The idea to keep understanding the paragraphs and to keep moving on. You are supposed to understand, “WHAT are you reading?” and not delve much into “WHY and HOW” of it. Keep the context in mind, speed read the rest and let the core flow. This is the basis of central idea based reading. This saves time and helps you run through a passage in one go. Let me explain this in a few steps for a VRC: Start reading: Identify the subjectSpeed read the paragraph keeping the subject in mindWhen you end the para: Think “What did I read about the subject?”Summing up points 1 and 3, it is like identifying the: Subject: Predicate while speed reading the paragraph. I call this central idea formation similContinue Reading CAT speed reading holds relevance in both the verbal and the non verbal sections of CAT. Verbal Section: The idea to keep understanding the paragraphs and to keep moving on. You are supposed to understand, “WHAT are you reading?” and not delve much into “WHY and HOW” of it. Keep the context in mind, speed read the rest and let the core flow. This is the basis of central idea based reading. This saves time and helps you run through a passage in one go. Let me explain this in a few steps for a VRC: Start reading: Identify the subjectSpeed read the paragraph keeping the subject in mindWhen you end the para: Think “What did I read about the subject?”Summing up points 1 and 3, it is like identifying the: Subject: Predicate while speed reading the paragraph. I call this central idea formation similContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:42:16.135Z"),
    "question" : "How does one improve reading speed for CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603762fc0c817f0398fbf32b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-shortcuts-useful-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Aditi Manchanda I hope this helps Multiplication  Multiply 2 digit numbers by 11:  52 * 11 =572 Here the Middle digit in the answer is the sum of digits in the question(5+2) Multiply 2 digit no.s ending in 181*91 step 1: Multiply digits in tens place            8*9=72step 2: Add the digits in tens place            8+9=17step 3: Place the result from step 2 next to result from step 1 (if a 2 digit no. is obtained in step 2, add its tens' digit to the no. obtained in step 1)            737 (or 720+17)step 4: Place 1 at the end of the no. obtained in step 3            81*91=7371 Multiply numbers between 11 & 19:13*14=182 step 1: Add the larger no. to the rightmost digit of the other number            14+3=17step 2: suffix a zero at the end of the no. obtained            170step 3: Add the Product of  Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:42:36.035Z"),
    "question" : "What are some shortcuts useful in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037630e0c817f0398fbf3ec"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-mistakes-that-should-be-avoided-while-preparing-for-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Patrick Dsouza, CAT 100th percentile 6 times. Faculty at Patrick100Answered January 11, 2021 · Author has 738 answers and 6M answer viewsWhat are the mistakes that should be avoided while preparing for the CAT? Patrick Dsouza Some of the common mistakes are Move away from school methods for solving sums as early as possible. Students are so used to school methods for solving quant sums, that they keep using it when they try to practice. Later they find it difficult to change these methods and hence find CAT and other aptitude exams difficult.For Verbal students focus on solving exercises instead of Reading. Reading is the most important part of preparation for CAT, but unfortunately a lot of students do not read regularly and hence face difficult at the later stage.For DILR students focus more on books. But equally important is to focus on building ability to solve logic sums of any kind as the sums that come in CAT are quite unpredictable. Students should focus on solving puzzles like Sudoku, Hidato, or puzzlesContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:42:54.539Z"),
    "question" : "What are the mistakes that should be avoided while preparing for the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603763220c817f0398fbf403"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-must-be-your-mindset-to-crack-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "The CAT is one of the most difficult admission tests notonly in India, but also in the world. With an applicationacceptance rate of less than 2%, it is important to have awell-rounded CAT preparation plan that covers academic aswell as extra-curricular milestones that can serve as acompass in your journey towards your dream managementcollege. Here are some tips:1. A STITCH IN TIME, SAVES NINE. This is an awfully common phrase that means that it is always a good thing to do something when the time is right, rather than later, when you are already behind schedule. This is true for CAT preparation as well and is an important CAT exam tip . One should start preparing for CAT at least a year in advance if not earlier, and should ensure that regular practice and learning is done as it is Continue Reading The CAT is one of the most difficult admission tests notonly in India, but also in the world. With an applicationacceptance rate of less than 2%, it is important to have awell-rounded CAT preparation plan that covers academic aswell as extra-curricular milestones that can serve as acompass in your journey towards your dream managementcollege. Here are some tips:1. A STITCH IN TIME, SAVES NINE. This is an awfully common phrase that means that it is always a good thing to do something when the time is right, rather than later, when you are already behind schedule. This is true for CAT preparation as well and is an important CAT exam tip . One should start preparing for CAT at least a year in advance if not earlier, and should ensure that regular practice and learning is done as it is Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:43:14.231Z"),
    "question" : "What must be your mindset to crack CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603763360c817f0398fbf412"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-start-my-preparation-of-CAT-at-home-online?-",
    "answer" : "Akshay Raj, Voracious reader  I CAT 19-99.81Updated 7 months ago · Author has 332 answers and 2.9M answer viewsHow can I start my preparation of CAT at home online? Akshay Raj Ok. It is going to be a long read so just hang on for sometime( coffee might help). Let me provide with some checklists for your journey ahead: Join one or more preferably two mock test series of IMS combined with TIME/CL.Purchase Arun Sharma’s Quant book.Download some novels from the internet. (if you want I can provide you reading list).Download a sudoku gaming app on your mobile or if you are a little old school you can find them in Hindu or IE newspaper.Now we are done with the checklist. Let’s start the journey now. I want you to be brave and attempt a mock (it is preferred that you give CAT 2017 or CAT 2018) paper only. By doing this exercise you will come to know about your current status. Most probably you will have one or worse two weak sections and a relatively stronger section wh Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:43:34.392Z"),
    "question" : "How can I start my preparation of CAT at home online? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603763480c817f0398fbf4d3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-times-is-CAT-held-in-a-year?-",
    "answer" : "CAT examination is only conducted once annually. In fact, it is conducted within a period of 21 days. The aspirant can select the date and timing of the exam, which suits them the most. To give the CAT exam, one has to register for it first. The application forms are given out in the month of August or September and the exam is held in October or November The results are declared in January and the shortlisting by IIMs/Colleges start from February onwards. The interviews for IIMs/Colleges are scheduled to be between March and April and the Final admission call from IIMs/Colleges is generally made between April-June.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:43:52.493Z"),
    "question" : "How many times is CAT held in a year? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603763700c817f0398fbf4f7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Who-can-apply-for-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Riya Malhotra CAT Eligibility Criteria - Please check the detailed Eligibility criteria of CAT 2017. Aspirants should have passed and obtained Bachelor’s Degree in any discipline from a recognised University or Institute.The minimum percentage of aggregate marks or equivalent CGPA to be obtained or secured by the applicants is 50 for General category candidates and 45 for reserved category candidates.Final year graduation students are also eligible to appear for the exam provided they fulfill the Bachelor’s degree cutoff and other factors within the stipulated schedule given by IIMs and other participating institutes. For more queries, comment me. Don’t forget to Upvote :) Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:44:32.841Z"),
    "question" : "Who can apply for the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603763830c817f0398fbf511"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Did-all-MBA-universities-require-the-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "CAT is the common admission test which is conducted by IIMs collectively every year to admit candidates in MBA courses across India not only in IIMs but other colleges as well. If you do not wish to appear for CAT, that is totally ok. There are many institutes that admit candidates even without CAT score. It is however advisable, that if you wish to join top B-Schools you should attempt for CAT once. If not CAT, then go for MAT, SNAP, XAT etc to get admission.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:44:51.674Z"),
    "question" : "Did all MBA universities require the CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603763980c817f0398fbf5ce"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-a-science-student-do-the-CAT-exam-after-12th?-",
    "answer" : "CAT is a national level competitive exam conducted every year for getting admissions in IIMs and other b-schools. It neither gives a special preference or restricts students of any particular stream. So, students from all fields like science, commerce and arts can appear for CAT. Through CAT, IIMs and other b-schools offers MBA/PGDM programme which is a post graduate course. So, one of the eligibility criteria for giving CAT is that the candidate has to pass their Bachelor's degree with at least 50% (for General Category and candidates from NC- OBC caste). For SC/ST and Differently Abled (DA) candidates, the percentage required is 45%. A common doubt is there among the final year students planning on giving CAT regarding their eligibility for the CAT Exam. The final year students of all Bache Continue Reading CAT is a national level competitive exam conducted every year for getting admissions in IIMs and other b-schools. It neither gives a special preference or restricts students of any particular stream. So, students from all fields like science, commerce and arts can appear for CAT. Through CAT, IIMs and other b-schools offers MBA/PGDM programme which is a post graduate course. So, one of the eligibility criteria for giving CAT is that the candidate has to pass their Bachelor's degree with at least 50% (for General Category and candidates from NC- OBC caste). For SC/ST and Differently Abled (DA) candidates, the percentage required is 45%. A common doubt is there among the final year students planning on giving CAT regarding their eligibility for the CAT Exam. The final year students of all Bache Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:45:12.968Z"),
    "question" : "Can a science student do the CAT exam after 12th? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603763af0c817f0398fbf5dd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-preparation-strategy-for-reading-comprehension-in-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the best preparation strategy for reading comprehension in CAT?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:45:35.582Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best preparation strategy for reading comprehension in CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603763c30c817f0398fbf69d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-websites-for-CAT-exam-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are the best websites for CAT exam preparation?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:45:55.137Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best websites for CAT exam preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603763dc0c817f0398fbf6b7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-qualify-if-I-get-0-marks-in-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers 4",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:46:20.541Z"),
    "question" : "Can I qualify if I get 0 marks in CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603763f20c817f0398fbf6cc"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Do-I-need-to-apply-to-each-MBA-college-separately-even-if-I-qualify-my-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Ansuman Bhattacharjee is right. For most other colleges, you need to apply separately. When you are filling any of these test forms, like CAT/XAT, the form requires that you select the colleges that you are applying for. If you want to apply to a different college, you need to fill the forms.  The best way to do this is to make a list of all the colleges that you want to apply for, and then keep an eye out on their respective websites for any notification/application form. (If you have enrolled with a test prep company/coaching institute, they should keep a lookout and inform you.) Mohammad Anees",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:46:42.611Z"),
    "question" : "Do I need to apply to each MBA college separately even if I qualify my CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037640b0c817f0398fbf792"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-Cat-cut-off?-",
    "answer" : "Shashank Prabhu A2A Too broad a question in my opinion. Institutes have cut-offs, exams don’t. Will try to build an answer that encompasses most of the situations though. Disclaimer: These are the general trends and historical benchmarks. Don’t take these as exact values and use it purely as reference points. If there is some mistake that I have made, suggest an edit and I will look into it. All cutoffs have been written from the frame of reference of general candidates Old IIMs with a good profile (90–90–80): Anything around 98.5 - 99 percentile (with all sectionals above 85 percentile to be on the safer side) should give you a fair shot at these institutes Old IIMs with an average profile (80–80–70): The more the merrier. There aren’t any guarantees even at a high 99. For the sake of benchmarking though, yo Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:47:07.786Z"),
    "question" : "What is Cat cut off? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603764470c817f0398fbf879"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-main-reason-to-not-qualify-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the main reason to not qualify for the CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:48:07.658Z"),
    "question" : "What is the main reason to not qualify for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037645c0c817f0398fbf889"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-exam-pattern-of-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Puja .Answered 3 years agoWhat is exam pattern of CAT? Puja . The pattern of CAT 2017 exam is released soon after the notification. This helps students prepare for the exam based on the pattern. The salient features of the exam pattern are as follows: 1} Mode of Exam: Computer-Based Test 2} Duration of Exam: 180 minutes (3 hours) 3} Name of Sections: Reading comprehension & Verbal AbilityQuantitative AbilityLogical Reasoning & Data Interpretation4} Total number of questions to be answered: 100 questions 5} Type of Questions: MCQ and Essay based 6} Time to complete each section: 60 minutes (1 hour) The Division of questions among each section is as follows: 1} Reading Comprehension and Verbal Ability (Total: 34 Questions) Number of MCQs: 24Number of Non-MCQs: 102} Data Interpretation and Logical Reasoning (Total: 32 Questions) Number of MCQs: 24Number of Non-MCContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:48:28.462Z"),
    "question" : "What is exam pattern of CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603764710c817f0398fbf8a2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-your-list-of-English-Vocabulary-for-CAT-Exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is your list of English Vocabulary for CAT Exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:48:49.032Z"),
    "question" : "What is your list of English Vocabulary for CAT Exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603764830c817f0398fbf95e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-crack-the-CAT-exam-without-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How do I crack the CAT exam without preparation?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:49:07.994Z"),
    "question" : "How do I crack the CAT exam without preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603764970c817f0398fbf96f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-was-CAT-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Anuvrat Dutta, Astt. Manager (Academics), Career Launcher, JamshedpurAnswered 3 years agoHow was CAT 2017? Anuvrat Dutta CAT 2017 Slot 1 Analysis & Cutoff CAT 2017 did not throw up any surprises wrt the paper format. The level of difficulty of the paper changed this year as compared to last year. While VARC continued to be easy, DILR was more difficult than last year with sets that took more time to solve as well. Quant was also easier and similar to CAT 2015 in level and marginally easier than 2016. On first impressions, an overall raw score of around 160 should fetch a student a 99%ile in CAT 2017. LRDI would not be the differentiator this year, since all students would be lumped in smaller categories. Quant, being easy, would play the role of differentiator. CAT 2017 Verbal Ability and Reading Comprehension Analysis This section seemed like a repeat of last year’s paper. However, an aware student would have  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:49:27.878Z"),
    "question" : "How was CAT 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603764ac0c817f0398fbf981"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-channels-on-YouTube-are-the-best-to-subscribe-to-while-somebody-is-seriously-preparing-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "__Probably Youtube isn't exactly the best place to learn about management__ But some Of the few there are, you should check out_ @Takshzila Shikshak :-: A very well structure and exhaustive resource that replicates the offline classroom model. They cover the entire range of topics for CAT and other MBA entrance exams in India - quantitative ability, vocabulary, logic, reasoning, reading comprehension, grammar, data sufficiency and data interpretation.Other similar resources include_2IIM Online CAT PreparationCareer EndeavourBYJU'S (company)@CareerLauncher@Handakafund**Or maybe some other new groups like_ __Minute MBA by onlinemba__ Illustrated lessons primarily on entrepreneurship, people management, and innovations.__harvard business review__ Touching on the nuances of business - strategy formContinue Reading __Probably Youtube isn't exactly the best place to learn about management__ But some Of the few there are, you should check out_ @Takshzila Shikshak :-: A very well structure and exhaustive resource that replicates the offline classroom model. They cover the entire range of topics for CAT and other MBA entrance exams in India - quantitative ability, vocabulary, logic, reasoning, reading comprehension, grammar, data sufficiency and data interpretation.Other similar resources include_2IIM Online CAT PreparationCareer EndeavourBYJU'S (company)@CareerLauncher@Handakafund**Or maybe some other new groups like_ __Minute MBA by onlinemba__ Illustrated lessons primarily on entrepreneurship, people management, and innovations.__harvard business review__ Touching on the nuances of business - strategy formContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:49:48.084Z"),
    "question" : "What channels on YouTube are the best to subscribe to while somebody is seriously preparing for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603764c00c817f0398fbfa44"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-a-final-year-student-write-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Yes, definitely. I am in my final year of engineering and i going to appear for CAT 2020. While filling out the application, in the graduation part, it will ask you whether you are in your final year or you have completed your graduation. After selecting the former option, you just have to fill out the details regarding your undergrad. You will have to enter the bachelor's percent till 6th semester. You will need an undertaking signed by your dean or HoD while appearing for the interviews after the exam. 6",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:50:08.404Z"),
    "question" : "Can a final year student write the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603764d40c817f0398fbfa55"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-CAT-exam-in-one-week?-",
    "answer" : "Prasad Sawant Thanks for the A2A. If you haven't done anything so far, you can't expect a miracle in a week. Your preparation should be mock driven more than anything else. Take as many tests as you can in this time frame. So your schedule for these seven days can be: Day 1: Read quant concepts. Start to end. + Go through past CAT papers 2000-2008Day 2: Read verbal concepts. Start to end. + Go through past CAT papers 2000-2008Day 3: Revise quant concepts. Start to end. + 1 full length mock + Go through past CAT papers 2000-2008Day 4: Revise verbal concepts. Start to end. + 1 full length mock + Go through past CAT papers 2000-2008Day 5: 1 full length mock + Three sectional tests + analysis + Go through past CAT papers 2000-2008Day 6: 1 full length mock + Three sectional tests + analysis + Go through pa Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:50:28.191Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for CAT exam in one week? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037650c0c817f0398fbfb33"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-a-BA-student-take-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Can a BA student take the CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:51:24.003Z"),
    "question" : "Can a BA student take the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037651d0c817f0398fbfb44"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-some-helpful-guidance-for-the-preparation-of-the-2017-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Renjith Regi There is no best method of preparation. Each CAT topper will tell you a different way of preparing for the exam. It depends a lot on your grasping ability, how strong your basics are and of course the amount of effort you are ready to put in. There are a few things that I have observed to be common. They are as follows:- They take a lot of mock exams. Most of them take a minimum of 50 mock tests before the CAT exam.Most of them start their preparation early - most of them start by Jan or before.Based on this, I think you can use the below set of points and prepare accordingly. You should complete preparation of basic concepts by end of June.Target solving atleast 10000 CAT level questions by the time your write your exam.Make sure that you note down the amount of time you take to solve a quesContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:51:41.888Z"),
    "question" : "What is some helpful guidance for the preparation of the 2017 CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603765320c817f0398fbfc07"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-we-crack-CAT-in-first-attempt?-",
    "answer" : "Rahul Gupta yes you can. I am IIM - A student, i cracked cat in my first attempt only. The first thing you need to do is have a unshakable belief that you can ace the CAT because you will see lots of ups and downs in these few months so it’s really important to not to loose focus. Hard Work is the key to success!Stick with this strategy throughout your preparations and success will follow you. Believe in your strategy and more importantly in yourself. Next you need is a strategy or a game plan for next few months. No one can tell you whats the best way to prepare for for you but there are some basic guidelines which will help you find your way. Quantitative Aptitude and Data Interpretation: Practice is the key here. There are hardly any topics which take more than 2 hours to complete. But without practici Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:52:02.045Z"),
    "question" : "Can we crack CAT in first attempt? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603765440c817f0398fbfc17"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-success-key-to-crack-the-CAT-exam-for-an-MBA?-",
    "answer" : "Been there done that ;) The wisdom of learning from failure is incontrovertible.One can only learn from failure than success. Assuming you know what books to opt for, what the syllabus is, what different sections are there, and all other facile things. I, here, will give you some insight knowledge. Some deep secrets. 2017 my first attempt. 3rd year of college,5th sem. Gowing with the flow, having no idea of “ what’s next”. And then a sudden enlightenment from the person I idealise, got me to this. M B A Before jumping to my percentile, I’ll tell you what I did wrong, so you can save your time and energy on what NOT to do. 1.) I gave up at the end - i started in the month of june. I was so happy and excited when i started my cat prep journey. I was on cloud nine.seriously. So happy that finally I a Continue Reading Been there done that ;) The wisdom of learning from failure is incontrovertible.One can only learn from failure than success. Assuming you know what books to opt for, what the syllabus is, what different sections are there, and all other facile things. I, here, will give you some insight knowledge. Some deep secrets. 2017 my first attempt. 3rd year of college,5th sem. Gowing with the flow, having no idea of “ what’s next”. And then a sudden enlightenment from the person I idealise, got me to this. M B A Before jumping to my percentile, I’ll tell you what I did wrong, so you can save your time and energy on what NOT to do. 1.) I gave up at the end - i started in the month of june. I was so happy and excited when i started my cat prep journey. I was on cloud nine.seriously. So happy that finally I a Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:52:20.357Z"),
    "question" : "What is the success key to crack the CAT exam for an MBA? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603765550c817f0398fbfc28"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Are-keys-allowed-inside-CAT-exam-centres?-",
    "answer" : "No. You can’t take anything that contains metal (keys, jewelry etc) inside the exam center. You can only take your CAT admit card and a valid original photo identity proof (like PAN card, Aadhar card, Voter ID, Driving License, Passport etc ) of yourself. Except these two things you are not allowed to take anything inside the CAT exam hall. All the best for your exam. Ajay Shukla",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:52:37.563Z"),
    "question" : "Are keys allowed inside CAT exam centres? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603765690c817f0398fbfceb"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-was-the-level-of-CAT-exam-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Mukul Vashishtha 9",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:52:57.972Z"),
    "question" : "What was the level of CAT exam 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037657d0c817f0398fbfcfe"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-strategies-have-you-adopted-to-clear-the-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "Rishi Iyer Thanks for A2A. Over the recent years CAT has been moving over to a harder Quant and DI/LR sections and relatively easier to score Verbal ability section. Hence your performance in the VA section will have the most impact in your overall percentile. This is where many of the students who start studying for CAT go wrong. They put in a disproportionately high amount of efforts in preparing for the Quant section. I feel this is because as a society when it comes to education, we have been made to believe that maths is more critical than english. Things like “Bachha maths me achha hai. Engineering me daal do bahut scope hai” reinforce our sense of importance for maths. But when it comes to CAT proficiency in english, especially reading english is what plays a decisive role in your score. Keeping Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:53:17.520Z"),
    "question" : "What strategies have you adopted to clear the CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603765900c817f0398fbfd0f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-crack-the-CAT-exam-in-1-year?-",
    "answer" : "Arihant Joshi One year is more than enough for CAT. Having said that it also depends on your current level of aptitude. If you have never read a single book in your life and don’t even read magazines or newspapers then you might have to work really hard. If you understand the basic concepts of quantitative aptitude well , like even if you are good at a high school level 3–4 months of preparation is enough. Verbal takes more time to improve compared too any other section. CAT at the end is all about strategy, focus and speed. If you are thinking of one year it might might be a good idea to join some online classes. From my experience i can suggest joining iQuanta. Its one of the best institutes for CAT and the founder is literally a Math Wiz. For Quantitative aptitude i would say only three words. Practice Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:53:36.435Z"),
    "question" : "How do I crack the CAT exam in 1 year? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603765b80c817f0398fbfde2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-algebraic-identities-are-required-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Some of the important algebraic identities required in every competitive exam.  Thanks…… Shivam Khilar",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:54:16.919Z"),
    "question" : "What algebraic identities are required for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603765cc0c817f0398fbfdf4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-is-the-CAT-exam-in-2015?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Himanshi Wadhwani 3",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:54:36.563Z"),
    "question" : "When is the CAT exam in 2015? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603765f10c817f0398fbfec6"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-age-limit-to-appear-for-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Pratik Shah Gollapalli Sai",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:55:13.804Z"),
    "question" : "What is the age limit to appear for CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603766040c817f0398fbfed4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-steps-one-should-follow-to-ace-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Garima Rawat Make a habit of reading (and understanding things in one go). You shouldn’t have to read it twice or thrice to understand it! You can rather read slow. Gradually increase your speed. BEING ABLE TO UNDERSTAND EVERYTHING IS THE KEY!Solve 2 RCs daily. Increase this gradually. Most importantly, review them once you know your mistakes.For LRDI, solve as many question sets as you can. Make sure you don’t do LRDI from one source only. Use multiple sources for this as LRDI is the trickiest section. They almost NEVER repeat questions in LRDI.For quant, keep solving topic wise questions (use timer). Also, make it a habit to revise all the formulae every once in a while. DON’T FOCUS MUCH ON SHORT TRICKS!You should be habitual of using the interface. Thus make sure you take A VERY GOOD TEST SERIES.MakContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:55:32.132Z"),
    "question" : "What are the steps one should follow to ace the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603766140c817f0398fbfee9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Where-can-I-download-CAT-exam-books?-",
    "answer" : "I figured out that there are few books on Amazon. I think they will help you on getting a good score on this exam. Sharma, Arun: 9789339205126: Amazon.com: Books How to Prepare for Data Interpretation for CAT eBook: Arun Sharma: Kindle Store Arun Sharma: 9789352606948: Amazon.com: Books Sinha: 9789332528826: Amazon.com: Books 9789352602261: Amazon.com: Books Good luck! Hitanshu Malhotra",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:55:48.979Z"),
    "question" : "Where can I download CAT exam books? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603766420c817f0398fbffb7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-a-few-apps-which-can-help-me-prepare-for-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are a few apps which can help me prepare for the CAT?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:56:34.055Z"),
    "question" : "What are a few apps which can help me prepare for the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603766530c817f0398fbffd2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-dirty-secrets-of-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "One of the dirtiest of them all is the misconception that “If you can score 95 by moderately studying for CAT, you can easily get a 99 if you study hard for the exam” It doesn’t work that way. The journey from 95 to 98 is far easier than the journey from 98 to 99. Everybody wants to be in that safe zone of 99 percentile to secure the maximum calls from Top B-Schools and the game changes at a marginal score difference of mere 1 question. CAT exam is specifically designed to trap you into multiple attempts by putting you in that dilemma that you “may” have missed it by a small margin this year & thus tempting you to try it, all over again, in the years to come. The complacency in the attitude, while scoring mocks and getting good marks, hurt a lot of my friends on the D-Day, while one of my frie Continue Reading One of the dirtiest of them all is the misconception that “If you can score 95 by moderately studying for CAT, you can easily get a 99 if you study hard for the exam” It doesn’t work that way. The journey from 95 to 98 is far easier than the journey from 98 to 99. Everybody wants to be in that safe zone of 99 percentile to secure the maximum calls from Top B-Schools and the game changes at a marginal score difference of mere 1 question. CAT exam is specifically designed to trap you into multiple attempts by putting you in that dilemma that you “may” have missed it by a small margin this year & thus tempting you to try it, all over again, in the years to come. The complacency in the attitude, while scoring mocks and getting good marks, hurt a lot of my friends on the D-Day, while one of my frie Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:56:51.531Z"),
    "question" : "What are the dirty secrets of the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603766650c817f0398fc008a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-has-the-CAT-exam-changed-your-life?-",
    "answer" : "Parag Nawani",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:57:09.425Z"),
    "question" : "How has the CAT exam changed your life? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037667c0c817f0398fc009e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-good-approach-to-build-vocabulary-for-cracking-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Shobhit Khandelwal CAT’15 VA/RC: 85%ile CAT’16 VA/RC: 99.74 %ile, and very good scores in verbal section in IIFT, NMAT, MICA, and SNAP in 2016. and I would attribute this to drastic increase in my vocabulary, and hence, my reading speed and comprehension. This is what I suggest to improve vocabulary - A daily read of ‘Editorial Section (On website: Opinion->LEAD)’ of ‘The Hindu’ newspaper. And it is not just reading, it’s also important how you read it. Here is a brief to it- Do not read it from the newspaper, rather read it on your laptop/tablet. As you will start reading it, you will come across at least 5 words, in the article for which you wouldn’t have known the meaning. A common tendency is to search for their meaning , try to fit in the context and move on with reading. Now, this is what everyone does, but Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:57:32.353Z"),
    "question" : "What are some good approach to build vocabulary for cracking CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603766900c817f0398fc0163"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-the-difficult-level-of-RBI-grade-B-exams-in-comparison-to-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "There is no comparison in between CAT and RBI GRADE B, although many cat aspirants those who have completed PGDM as well as those who are Preparing attempt this exam in huge number because favorable exam pattern. I think you are comparing only the Difficulty level of paper of these two exams but there are other factors too like competition level, Difficulty level of exam, Cut off, Selection Procedure, Rate of Selection etc. In CAT Exam you have some 19 IIMs + Various other Institutions but in RBI GRADE B, there are Only 162 Seats with minimum 3–4 lakhs Applicants from various backgrounds. Did you know, RBI only select some 10–15 thousands top students for RBI GRADE B mains exam and in that not more than 5–6 hundreds for interview and only 162 gets final selection, which compromises of Couple  Continue Reading There is no comparison in between CAT and RBI GRADE B, although many cat aspirants those who have completed PGDM as well as those who are Preparing attempt this exam in huge number because favorable exam pattern. I think you are comparing only the Difficulty level of paper of these two exams but there are other factors too like competition level, Difficulty level of exam, Cut off, Selection Procedure, Rate of Selection etc. In CAT Exam you have some 19 IIMs + Various other Institutions but in RBI GRADE B, there are Only 162 Seats with minimum 3–4 lakhs Applicants from various backgrounds. Did you know, RBI only select some 10–15 thousands top students for RBI GRADE B mains exam and in that not more than 5–6 hundreds for interview and only 162 gets final selection, which compromises of Couple  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:57:52.120Z"),
    "question" : "How is the difficult level of RBI grade B exams in comparison to CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603766a70c817f0398fc017a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the CAT?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:58:15.329Z"),
    "question" : "What is the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603766bb0c817f0398fc018b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-myself-for-CAT-exams-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Avi Singh 6 months is adequate for CAT preparation if you are focused. Let’s first walk through what you need to keep in mind while preparing a specific section. For Quantitative Aptitude -Practice on a daily basis and do your calculation using the memorized tables, tips and tricks that you know. -Clear your basics and concepts when you start preparing. -The books you need are:  For Verbal Ability -Read newspapers, magazines and everything else you can lay your hands on. -Focus on article-based questions. -The books you need are:  For Logical Reasoning/Data interpretation -Solve previous years’ questions to know what kind of questions you can expect. -The books you need are:  You can break down your preparation phase-wise: First Phase: -Go through syllabus, exam pattern and structure well. -Gather everything you need Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:58:35.613Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare myself for CAT exams 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603766cc0c817f0398fc0248"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "CAT is the Common Admission Test for admission to MBA/PGDM programs in 20 Indian Institutes of Management (IIMs) and other top MBA colleges like FMS Delhi, MDI Gurgaon, SPJIMR Mumbai, IMI New Delhi, IMT Ghaziabad, and hundreds of other top MBA colleges in India. IIMs will offer admission on the basis of CAT 2020 only and will not accept any other test score. There are more than 155 cities and more than 400 venues where CAT 2020 will be conducted in India. Indian Institutes of Technology (IITs) and an Indian Institute of Science (IISC) also use CAT for admission to their Management programs Eligibility to Appear in CAT 2020A candidate with a minimum of 50% marks in graduation can appear in CAT 2020. A final year student in graduation can also appear in CAT conducted by IIMs. However, there is no age limit to apply and appear in CAT 2020.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:58:52.402Z"),
    "question" : "How is the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603766f10c817f0398fc026b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Where-can-I-get-CAT-question-papers-of-the-previous-years?-",
    "answer" : "Hey there.. It's very important to solve past year question papers to have an idea about how the exam is and what is the structure of the questions. But you should know that CAT exam conducting bodies never releases papers online after the http://exam.So all the sites that mention that they have past year papers are all memory based papers not the exact papers.Still you can practice them to have better idea about the exam. Here are some of the sites from which you can download these papers. Official websites of coaching classes like IMS,TIMES,CETKING,BYJUS,BULLSEYEJagran josh.comExamsCorner.comhttp://Mbarandezvous.comcracku.inHope this helps.. Cheers.☺",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:59:29.938Z"),
    "question" : "Where can I get CAT question papers of the previous years? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603767050c817f0398fc0284"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-crack-the-CAT-in-20-days?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is it possible to crack the CAT in 20 days?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T08:59:49.207Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to crack the CAT in 20 days? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603767160c817f0398fc0341"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-a-student-from-humanities-crack-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Yeah! Sure. People from any graduation background can go for it since management or managerial decision making is applicable in any field. Any graduate can go for CAT on meeting the eligiblity criterion. It is as follows :- The candidate must hold a Bachelor’s Degree, with at least 50% marks or equivalent CGPA[45% in case of the candidates belonging to Scheduled Caste (SC), Scheduled Tribe (ST) and Persons With Disability (PWD) categories], awarded by any University or educational institution as incorporated by an Act of the Parliament or State legislature in India ordeclared to be deemed as a University under Section 3 of the UGC Act, 1956, or possess an equivalent qualification recognized by the Ministry of HRD, Government of India, India.The percentage of marks obtained by the candidate woContinue Reading Yeah! Sure. People from any graduation background can go for it since management or managerial decision making is applicable in any field. Any graduate can go for CAT on meeting the eligiblity criterion. It is as follows :- The candidate must hold a Bachelor’s Degree, with at least 50% marks or equivalent CGPA[45% in case of the candidates belonging to Scheduled Caste (SC), Scheduled Tribe (ST) and Persons With Disability (PWD) categories], awarded by any University or educational institution as incorporated by an Act of the Parliament or State legislature in India ordeclared to be deemed as a University under Section 3 of the UGC Act, 1956, or possess an equivalent qualification recognized by the Ministry of HRD, Government of India, India.The percentage of marks obtained by the candidate woContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:00:06.973Z"),
    "question" : "Can a student from humanities crack the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037673f0c817f0398fc0362"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Where-do-they-pick-up-questions-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Megh Shah",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:00:47.340Z"),
    "question" : "Where do they pick up questions for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603767550c817f0398fc0425"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-quantitative-aptitude-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How do I prepare for quantitative aptitude for the CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:01:09.250Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for quantitative aptitude for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037677d0c817f0398fc044d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-months-required-for-CAT-exam-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  There’s only a few months left for CAT 2017. How do I start preparing from scratch to score above 90%?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:01:49.819Z"),
    "question" : "How many months required for CAT exam 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603767930c817f0398fc050b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Are-5-months-sufficient-to-prepare-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Are 5 months sufficient to prepare for the CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:02:11.114Z"),
    "question" : "Are 5 months sufficient to prepare for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603767a80c817f0398fc051b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-tough-CA-or-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which is tough CA or CAT?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:02:32.403Z"),
    "question" : "Which is tough CA or CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603767bc0c817f0398fc05e0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-rough-sheets-are-provided-this-time-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "It depends on the centre where you are taking the exam. In our centre, initially we were provided with only one sheet and were told that we will be getting extra sheets when we require. Obviously it would sound strange. You dont expect solving 50 quant questions and some LR questions using one sheet. To this we decided to let the invigilators know the concern and then they provided us with one more sheet of paper before the exam. Our point was simply a logical point that 1 sheet of paper would be totally used within 20 to 30 mins and if more than 10 people require paper at the same time then surely some would be wasting around 1 min to get a sheet as number of invigilators was 2 to 3 and i am pretty sure that wasting 1 minute in this kind of exams matters a lot (at least for the serious  Continue Reading It depends on the centre where you are taking the exam. In our centre, initially we were provided with only one sheet and were told that we will be getting extra sheets when we require. Obviously it would sound strange. You dont expect solving 50 quant questions and some LR questions using one sheet. To this we decided to let the invigilators know the concern and then they provided us with one more sheet of paper before the exam. Our point was simply a logical point that 1 sheet of paper would be totally used within 20 to 30 mins and if more than 10 people require paper at the same time then surely some would be wasting around 1 min to get a sheet as number of invigilators was 2 to 3 and i am pretty sure that wasting 1 minute in this kind of exams matters a lot (at least for the serious  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:02:52.154Z"),
    "question" : "How many rough sheets are provided this time in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603767ce0c817f0398fc05f4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-preparation-strategies-for-CAT-exam-along-with-graduation?-",
    "answer" : "Try to give as many mocks as possible. Mocks are the most important preparation tool in your arsenal against CAT. Prepare for CAT along with your placement studies (I'm an engineer, so I can say this for people in final year of engineering.) Analysing mocks is just as important, which tells you your problem areas and the topics you need to work hard at. Do not take anything for granted and never let any mock throw you off. But, take it as a precautionary measure. I gave my CAT a day after my penultimate exam in semester 7 of engineering. After giving the exam, I came back and gave the last exam 2 days later. A month prior to CAT, I left studying for it because of farewell festivities and lab exams and end sem exams. Thus, when I went to give my CAT, I was as fresh faced as possible. I'm not sayi Continue Reading Try to give as many mocks as possible. Mocks are the most important preparation tool in your arsenal against CAT. Prepare for CAT along with your placement studies (I'm an engineer, so I can say this for people in final year of engineering.) Analysing mocks is just as important, which tells you your problem areas and the topics you need to work hard at. Do not take anything for granted and never let any mock throw you off. But, take it as a precautionary measure. I gave my CAT a day after my penultimate exam in semester 7 of engineering. After giving the exam, I came back and gave the last exam 2 days later. A month prior to CAT, I left studying for it because of farewell festivities and lab exams and end sem exams. Thus, when I went to give my CAT, I was as fresh faced as possible. I'm not sayi Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:03:10.557Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best preparation strategies for CAT exam along with graduation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603767e20c817f0398fc0605"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-a-link-to-download-PDFs-of-logical-reasoning-for-the-CAT-exam-by-Arun-Sharma?-",
    "answer" : "Rajesh Balasubramanian, 100th percentile,CAT 2017, 2014, 2012, 2011. Online.2iim,comAnswered 4 years ago · Author has 489 answers and 5.1M answer viewsWhere can I get a PDF of Arun Sharma's CAT preparation? Rajesh Balasubramanian You can ping him and request him for it. Apart from this, any copy procured from any other source would constitute copyright infringement. :-) I know the issue of intellectual property is not taken seriously in India. At least not half as seriously as it should be. Good books for CAT sell at as low as Rs. 300, that is perhaps lunch money for two days for most CAT aspirants. I would strongly urge you to buy the damn book. Perhaps the cost shelled out might guilt-trip you into preparing more seriously as well. And there is no substituting that. Sorry if I got a bit carried away on IP theft. I often (too often for my blood pressure) find 2IIM questions on many other websites and it riles me up no end. There are gazillion free questions available on the web as well (In fact, the 2IIM website list Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:03:30.402Z"),
    "question" : "What is a link to download PDFs of logical reasoning for the CAT exam by Arun Sharma? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603767f60c817f0398fc061e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-has-IIM-Lucknow-conducted-CAT-exams-before?-",
    "answer" : "I think it did conduct on the year 2007. Or maybe 2009. Or maybe never. How does it matter dude? Focus on preparation and don't let those factors which you can't control sidetrack you. Mohammad Shavez",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:03:50.746Z"),
    "question" : "When has IIM Lucknow conducted CAT exams before? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037681b0c817f0398fc06e8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-is-CAT-considered-a-tough-test?-",
    "answer" : "A very simple and genuine answer to your question is that ‘Nothing is easy or difficult in life, it is all about your belief’. If you believe that something is difficult, then it will start getting more and more difficult day-by-day. If you believe that something is easy, then it will start getting more and more easy day-by-day. The decision is in your hands, so choose wisely!!! For more information about the CAT Exam (top institutes that accept the GMAT score, eligibility criteria, syllabus, paper pattern, timelines, test-taking strategies, etc…), you may visit the QDS Pro website. Ujjwal Jyoti",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:04:27.376Z"),
    "question" : "Why is CAT considered a tough test? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603768460c817f0398fc07be"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-stay-motivated-for-the-GATE-and-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "Hi friend… Motivation is more important to have effective preparation for competitive exams. Motivation you can get from seeing a video or listening to a speech but it won’t stay for long time, it just helps you setting goal but won’t last through out your preparation. For continuous motivation, have a thing that related to your family/ your previous job struggles/ things happened in your past… Let me share my inspiration, My father is a daily labour, I started coaching with my brother help… So I had these things on a paper in my room and had a glance to it every day. One more way is to think about your status after clearing the exam with good rank, whenever you feel tired/ depression. ALL THE VERY BEST",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:05:10.673Z"),
    "question" : "How do I stay motivated for the GATE and CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603768590c817f0398fc07ce"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-standard-questions-asked-in-a-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Thanks for A2A. I'll answer this question keeping CAT'15 in mind. For the first time there was calculator provided in CAT so obviously calculation intensive were not asked. But there two kinds of questions: MCQ- Regular questions with 4 options and 1 correct choice.TITA Questions- Type In The Answer question. You had to type the answer in these questions.There were three sections with 1 hour each. Now a section wise analysis: Verbal Ability(VA) & Reading Comprehension(RC)- Total of 34 question with 24 from RC and 10 from VA. RC questions were MCQ with easy to read passages and relatively simple questions. But all the questions in VA were TITA with para jumbles, select the odd statement out.Logical Reasoning & Data Interpretaion: Undoubtedly the toughest section in CAT'15. It had 32 questions.Continue Reading Thanks for A2A. I'll answer this question keeping CAT'15 in mind. For the first time there was calculator provided in CAT so obviously calculation intensive were not asked. But there two kinds of questions: MCQ- Regular questions with 4 options and 1 correct choice.TITA Questions- Type In The Answer question. You had to type the answer in these questions.There were three sections with 1 hour each. Now a section wise analysis: Verbal Ability(VA) & Reading Comprehension(RC)- Total of 34 question with 24 from RC and 10 from VA. RC questions were MCQ with easy to read passages and relatively simple questions. But all the questions in VA were TITA with para jumbles, select the odd statement out.Logical Reasoning & Data Interpretaion: Undoubtedly the toughest section in CAT'15. It had 32 questions.Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:05:29.176Z"),
    "question" : "What are the standard questions asked in a CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037686e0c817f0398fc07e8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-stay-calm-from-the-CAT-exam-pressure?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How do I stay calm from the CAT exam pressure?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:05:50.274Z"),
    "question" : "How do I stay calm from the CAT exam pressure? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603768820c817f0398fc08a4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-of-the-important-tricks-used-for-solving-the-quants-section-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Patrick Dsouza I usually analyse the mocks of my students and give them individual feedback with regards to the strategy that they should adopt. Analysing the mocks, I have seen a lot of issues with the way students attempt the maths section. Some of the common flaws are Some students spend a lot of time on the initial questions that they do not have enough time to see all the questions in the section. This is the worst mistake that students make. A lot of times in the exam there are sitters in the questions that you have left. Missing out on them is missing out on valuable marks. I remember when I had gone to write CAT for the first time during my college days, the last 5 questions were absolutely simple. But quite a few of my friends were not able to reach there and so missed out on crucial marks in theContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:06:10.289Z"),
    "question" : "What are some of the important tricks used for solving the quants section in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603768a60c817f0398fc08c4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-the-overall-experience-of-taking-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "A lot of students face a lot of anxiety on the day of the CAT exam, so here is a detailed outline of what happens the THE DAY! The CAT exam is extremely well organised however one has to follow all the rules and regulations and ensure that all the procedures are completed on the day of the exam. The moment you enter your test center there are volunteers who guide you to the desks where you verification is done. You are requested to present your Admit Card and photo ID here and they stamp it. You are then suppose to deposit your belongings and are allowed to carry only your photo ID and admit card, generally you also have to go through a list and find out in which lab you are suppose to give the exam. Post this you are required to go through frisking and security to ensure that none of the cand Continue Reading A lot of students face a lot of anxiety on the day of the CAT exam, so here is a detailed outline of what happens the THE DAY! The CAT exam is extremely well organised however one has to follow all the rules and regulations and ensure that all the procedures are completed on the day of the exam. The moment you enter your test center there are volunteers who guide you to the desks where you verification is done. You are requested to present your Admit Card and photo ID here and they stamp it. You are then suppose to deposit your belongings and are allowed to carry only your photo ID and admit card, generally you also have to go through a list and find out in which lab you are suppose to give the exam. Post this you are required to go through frisking and security to ensure that none of the cand Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:06:46.977Z"),
    "question" : "How is the overall experience of taking the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603768ec0c817f0398fc0a5c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-people-in-the-99th-percentile-prepare-for-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "I took the CAT examination in 2019 and was fortunate to be able to score 99.96 percentile. Section-wise I scored:- VARC: 99.62 DILR: 99.92 Quant: 99.59 I decided to prepare for CAT in January 2019 which was the beginning of my 6th semester of Engineering. At my college (NITK), TIME offered weekend classes at a discounted rate within our campus itself. I joined them at that time and attended them regularly. They would be 2–3 hours each on Saturday and Sunday or 4 hours on any one of them. However, I didn't do anything else apart from attending those classes. I had my internship in May when I realized I should start preparing seriously but, I couldn't do so till it ended in July. Once, I was back from my internship, I took my first mock test and scored 95 percentile. It seemed good at first but, s Continue Reading I took the CAT examination in 2019 and was fortunate to be able to score 99.96 percentile. Section-wise I scored:- VARC: 99.62 DILR: 99.92 Quant: 99.59 I decided to prepare for CAT in January 2019 which was the beginning of my 6th semester of Engineering. At my college (NITK), TIME offered weekend classes at a discounted rate within our campus itself. I joined them at that time and attended them regularly. They would be 2–3 hours each on Saturday and Sunday or 4 hours on any one of them. However, I didn't do anything else apart from attending those classes. I had my internship in May when I realized I should start preparing seriously but, I couldn't do so till it ended in July. Once, I was back from my internship, I took my first mock test and scored 95 percentile. It seemed good at first but, s Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:07:56.015Z"),
    "question" : "How did people in the 99th percentile prepare for the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037690e0c817f0398fc0a7e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-Prepare-for-the-CAT-exam-within-12-months?-",
    "answer" : "First let’s see ways to prepare for CAT examination without being worried or over zealous for the upcoming online test.•\tFocus on Known TopicsOne month is left for the CAT exam, hence, one should focus on only such topics in which he/she is comfortable with. This applies during the exam as well, where instead of trying all the given questions, one should answer only those in which one is comfortable with.•\tPrepare from old papers and mocks:Every CAT aspiring student must prepare well before taking the final online test. Studying and preparing from the previous years' papers are a good try always in order to get an idea on the exam. Also, mock exams help in assessing one's proficiency on the subjects, therefore one must be alert and sincere in trying out the tests before taking the fina Continue Reading First let’s see ways to prepare for CAT examination without being worried or over zealous for the upcoming online test.•\tFocus on Known TopicsOne month is left for the CAT exam, hence, one should focus on only such topics in which he/she is comfortable with. This applies during the exam as well, where instead of trying all the given questions, one should answer only those in which one is comfortable with.•\tPrepare from old papers and mocks:Every CAT aspiring student must prepare well before taking the final online test. Studying and preparing from the previous years' papers are a good try always in order to get an idea on the exam. Also, mock exams help in assessing one's proficiency on the subjects, therefore one must be alert and sincere in trying out the tests before taking the fina Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:08:30.985Z"),
    "question" : "How can I Prepare for the CAT exam within 12 months? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769260c817f0398fc0b40"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-much-does-an-average-student-score-in-a-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How much does an average student score in a CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:08:54.642Z"),
    "question" : "How much does an average student score in a CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769390c817f0398fc0b58"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-okay-to-start-preparing-for-CAT-exam-at-26?-",
    "answer" : "why not, if u are really passionate about MBA u can start preparing for CAT at the age of 26, age is not a barrier for u, your passion towards MBA and the hard work u are willing to put in are the key factors for CAT not the age Every year many students join IIMs some might be freshers, some with 2-5 years of experience. 5 year of work experience would mean that they have an age of 26-27 so I think your question regarding age is clear. There are students in my batch who even got married, one person has a work experience of 8 years. If they are doing it u can also do it and its completely OK. Stop worrying about your age and concentrate on CAT especially MOCKS ALL THE BEST!!!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:09:13.554Z"),
    "question" : "Is it okay to start preparing for CAT exam at 26? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037694f0c817f0398fc0b6c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-application-is-best-for-cat-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Well it's not application but website : tenaday.co.inBasically you can practice 10 questions daily in limited time and they will give your all India percentile and  performance based on total number of participants that took the test. The level of questions are good. Hope it helps.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:09:35.748Z"),
    "question" : "Which application is best for cat exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769620c817f0398fc0c28"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-section-wise-best-books-to-prepare-for-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are the section-wise best books to prepare for CAT?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:09:54.890Z"),
    "question" : "What are the section-wise best books to prepare for CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769870c817f0398fc0c4c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Should-I-take-one-more-chance-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "At the very beginning let me congratulate you that you have atleast thought of giving it another shot. It's quite a question hovering over minds of all the serious CAT takers. Now,the matter of fact is that your question does not mention the number of your previous CAT attempts and the percentile range you managed to put yourself in. So, for the sake of answering it easily, I assume that you have taken it once and managed to secure a decent but no-so-satisfactory percentile. If that's the case, it's an absolute yes in my opinion. If not, you can still think of attempting it provided you are confident enough and desperate to kill that animal. However ,it's you who has to decide wisely and frame your career. CAT is just another animal in a dense jungle. You can pretty much think of hunting the o Continue Reading At the very beginning let me congratulate you that you have atleast thought of giving it another shot. It's quite a question hovering over minds of all the serious CAT takers. Now,the matter of fact is that your question does not mention the number of your previous CAT attempts and the percentile range you managed to put yourself in. So, for the sake of answering it easily, I assume that you have taken it once and managed to secure a decent but no-so-satisfactory percentile. If that's the case, it's an absolute yes in my opinion. If not, you can still think of attempting it provided you are confident enough and desperate to kill that animal. However ,it's you who has to decide wisely and frame your career. CAT is just another animal in a dense jungle. You can pretty much think of hunting the o Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:10:31.201Z"),
    "question" : "Should I take one more chance for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037699a0c817f0398fc0c67"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Are-there-any-scholarships-after-clearing-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Ajay Zener 13",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:10:50.920Z"),
    "question" : "Are there any scholarships after clearing the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769ae0c817f0398fc0d23"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-difficult-for-non-engineers-to-crack-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Patrick Dsouza There are two perspectives out here. One is difficulty in getting into a good B school and second is getting a good percentile. In terms of getting into a good B school, non engineers have an edge over engineers as they are given additional diversity points during selection. They end up getting calls at a lower percentile. In IIM A there were 130+ non engineering students in the 2018–19 and 2019–2020 batches. About getting a good percentile. It has been seen that most of the top percentilers are engineers. But that does not mean that non engineers cannot score high. Every year I have a few non engineers who score really high. Last year I had a Commerce student (BFM) from a local commerce college (Mulund College of Commerce) scoring 99.89%ile in CAT and getting admission to IIM A. Similarly t Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:11:10.376Z"),
    "question" : "Is it difficult for non-engineers to crack the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769c00c817f0398fc0d35"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/I-will-complete-my-graduation-in-2018-so-can-I-give-CAT-exam-in-2017?-",
    "answer" : "CAT 2017 aims to recruit students for MBA 2018–2020 batch at different IIMs and other B-Schools of India which starts from July. So if you are completing your graduation on or before July 2018 without any back you should appear for 2017 CAT only, unless you don’t want to waste a year in preparation. For effective preparation and score high in CAT , you can visit SMARG , Delhi. You you shall have learning outcome based coaching and most comprehensive mentor ship for all the stages of CAT and other admission processes . Priyanka Kaul",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:11:28.868Z"),
    "question" : "I will complete my graduation in 2018 so can I give CAT exam in 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769fc0c817f0398fc0e19"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-years-did-IIM-Bangalore-conduct-CAT-exam-before-2016?-",
    "answer" : "Prasenjit Nath  Priyanka Kaul",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:12:28.537Z"),
    "question" : "Which years did IIM Bangalore conduct CAT exam before 2016? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a230c817f0398fc0ef3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-easy-to-score-100-percentile-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Prateek Bajpai 61",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:13:07.156Z"),
    "question" : "Is it easy to score 100 percentile in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a370c817f0398fc0f05"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Does-IMT-ghaziabad-reopen-registration-after-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Yes, IMT Ghaziabad reopens registrations after the CAT exam too. Last year, in 2020, IMT Ghaziabad started the registration process Phase 1 on 14 September 2020 and ended it on 27 November 2020. After the CAT exam, the institute has started its registration process Phase 2 from 4 January 2021. If you want to become a successful Management Professional in the Corporate World then don't miss this opportunity. IMT Ghaziabad stands among the top B-schools in India for rendering high-quality management courses with a practical approach and make the students gain advanced skills. Alongside the classroom lectures, IMT G conducts seminars, conferences, and Real-life projects that make the students think out of the box. Visit its admission page for more information and apply online- https://www.imt Continue Reading Yes, IMT Ghaziabad reopens registrations after the CAT exam too. Last year, in 2020, IMT Ghaziabad started the registration process Phase 1 on 14 September 2020 and ended it on 27 November 2020. After the CAT exam, the institute has started its registration process Phase 2 from 4 January 2021. If you want to become a successful Management Professional in the Corporate World then don't miss this opportunity. IMT Ghaziabad stands among the top B-schools in India for rendering high-quality management courses with a practical approach and make the students gain advanced skills. Alongside the classroom lectures, IMT G conducts seminars, conferences, and Real-life projects that make the students think out of the box. Visit its admission page for more information and apply online- https://www.imt Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:13:27.405Z"),
    "question" : "Does IMT ghaziabad reopen registration after CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a4a0c817f0398fc0f16"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-crack-the-CAT-exam-in-the-first-attempt-as-a-fresher?-",
    "answer" : "Yes there are some important tips through which you can prepare the CAT exam much more easily and will help you to plan for the exam. .Time management: Proper time Management is a crucial factors that play an important role in preparing this toughest exam. Candidates are required to manage time well with full concentration on each subject. You need to stick to that particular time schedule in order to prepare for this exam well. Focus on futuristic goals:First you need to focus on the bigger goals that are essential for your life Instead of giving more concentration on your exam. Just think once hat if you will be able to crack the CAT exam, then the day is not far when you will be working in any big company in future. Never forget “Practice makes a man perfect”:Follow the learning strategy th Continue Reading Yes there are some important tips through which you can prepare the CAT exam much more easily and will help you to plan for the exam. .Time management: Proper time Management is a crucial factors that play an important role in preparing this toughest exam. Candidates are required to manage time well with full concentration on each subject. You need to stick to that particular time schedule in order to prepare for this exam well. Focus on futuristic goals:First you need to focus on the bigger goals that are essential for your life Instead of giving more concentration on your exam. Just think once hat if you will be able to crack the CAT exam, then the day is not far when you will be working in any big company in future. Never forget “Practice makes a man perfect”:Follow the learning strategy th Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:13:46.693Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to crack the CAT exam in the first attempt as a fresher? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a5e0c817f0398fc0fda"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-the-CAT-exam-good-for-a-BSc-student?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:14:06.492Z"),
    "question" : "Is the CAT exam good for a BSc student? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a840c817f0398fc0ffc"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-there-any-easy-way-to-crack-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "CAT is an aptitude based exam. Maa Saraswati is the goddess of knowledge. You can devote 5–6 hours per day (for the next 3 months) to please her to give you the knowledge required to crack CAT. The 6-hour puja can be divided into 3 parts: Although Maa Saraswati loves Sanskrit, in modern times to please her you need to read English literature. You need to develop a complete understanding of the paragraphs. To test it answer the questions based on paragraphs. Understand how to find the correct order of the sentences if their order is changed. Find the summary of the paragraphs. You have to learn these all to please her.Maa Saraswati wants you to be a problem solver so you need to learn how to solve puzzles. The Puzzles of form wherein a situation is given you have to find the solution. PracticContinue Reading CAT is an aptitude based exam. Maa Saraswati is the goddess of knowledge. You can devote 5–6 hours per day (for the next 3 months) to please her to give you the knowledge required to crack CAT. The 6-hour puja can be divided into 3 parts: Although Maa Saraswati loves Sanskrit, in modern times to please her you need to read English literature. You need to develop a complete understanding of the paragraphs. To test it answer the questions based on paragraphs. Understand how to find the correct order of the sentences if their order is changed. Find the summary of the paragraphs. You have to learn these all to please her.Maa Saraswati wants you to be a problem solver so you need to learn how to solve puzzles. The Puzzles of form wherein a situation is given you have to find the solution. PracticContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:14:44.093Z"),
    "question" : "Is there any easy way to crack the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a9a0c817f0398fc10c3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-coaching-for-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:15:06.927Z"),
    "question" : "Which are the best coaching institutes in India for CAT 2020? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376aaf0c817f0398fc10d3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-prepare-for-the-CAT-exam-at-home?-",
    "answer" : "Here we bring you 10 success tips for succeeding in CAT 2017. 1. Take mock tests in online environment You must take computer-based mock CAT 2017 so that you are familiar with the actual test environment. Taking the mock CAT in real environment will make you completely prepare to take the computer-based test on your CAT day and save any wastage of time on understanding the mode of test. You can also join CAT test series to take a few mock CAT online. Also, you must re-visit previous year CAT sample paper and solve it to have an actual feel of the test. Putting yourself in the actual testing environment will help you to take CAT on the test centre on your D-day. Sandeep Manudhane, PT Education Chairman states, “Taking mocks is one of the most important factor behind your success. Attempt at l Continue Reading Here we bring you 10 success tips for succeeding in CAT 2017. 1. Take mock tests in online environment You must take computer-based mock CAT 2017 so that you are familiar with the actual test environment. Taking the mock CAT in real environment will make you completely prepare to take the computer-based test on your CAT day and save any wastage of time on understanding the mode of test. You can also join CAT test series to take a few mock CAT online. Also, you must re-visit previous year CAT sample paper and solve it to have an actual feel of the test. Putting yourself in the actual testing environment will help you to take CAT on the test centre on your D-day. Sandeep Manudhane, PT Education Chairman states, “Taking mocks is one of the most important factor behind your success. Attempt at l Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:15:27.819Z"),
    "question" : "How should I prepare for the CAT exam at home? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ac40c817f0398fc10e9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Should-I-prepare-for-SBI-PO-and-CAT-exam-simultaneously?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Sunil Agarwal 4",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:15:48.573Z"),
    "question" : "Should I prepare for SBI PO and CAT exam simultaneously? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ad80c817f0398fc11a9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-get-180-200-marks-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:16:08.924Z"),
    "question" : "How do I get 180-200 marks in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376b160c817f0398fc128f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-DATA-INTERPRETATION-for-CAT-exam-2015?-",
    "answer" : "Prasad Sawant Hey. Thanks for the A2A. For Data Interpretation, you must solve as many sets as possible (that's quite obvious) and understand various question types.  For example: In a graph based set, the questions can be 1. Absolute/percentage difference in two years2. Absolute/percentage difference over the entire period3. Above or below Average/Minima/Maxima over the period4. Future projection5. Increase/decrease and so on Once you solve 7-8 graph based sets, you will understand that the questions start to repeat. Do this exercise for all other types (pie charts, line graphs, bar graphs, big tables, etc.) That's the only way in which you can prepare for this section.  Solve past CAT papers and take as many mocks as you can. Expose yourself to more questions and question types. The other important p Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:17:10.257Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare DATA INTERPRETATION for CAT exam 2015? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376b3b0c817f0398fc12b3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-one-crack-the-CAT-exam-if-one-starts-preparing-4-months-before-the-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Akshay Bhandari 4 months is enough time to commence the preparation for the CAT. Prepare a time table and study for at least 6–7 hours a day. There are 3 sections asked in the Examination. Analyze your strengths and weaknesses. Make a list- what are the topics you are good at and what topic needs to be studied more. I started with quantitative aptitude, and made a whole list of the topics which are to be improved and gave enormous amount of time to grasp the topics. Personally I feel VARC is the toughest among the three. So I give most of my time to reading. I read a few novels and solve at least 4–5 passages per day. Don't stress on your Vocabulary. Give a little importance to grammar but not much. 22–24 questions are from RC. And 2–3 are para summary. 2–3 are para jumbles. So by improving your reading habi Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:17:47.436Z"),
    "question" : "Can one crack the CAT exam if one starts preparing 4 months before the exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376b4f0c817f0398fc1377"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-topic-in-quants-have-more-weightage-for-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which topic in quants have more weightage for CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:18:07.106Z"),
    "question" : "Which topic in quants have more weightage for CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376b630c817f0398fc1389"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-I-do-after-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "After taking CAT, if you have to appear in other exams like SNAP, IIFT or XAT, then prepare for them. Else, keeping in mind that you will have to appear for GD-PI processes of various colleges, you can try these: Widen your knowledge base in fields like Economics, History, Politics, General Awareness etc.Scan your personality and try to make it better.Find out your strengths and weaknesses.Work on your weaknesses to make them your strengths.Work on your communication and language skills.Keep a watch on the happenings in India as well as around the world.Start putting your thoughts into words.Attend mock interviews and group discussions.Last but not the least, enjoy your life a lot. You might have missed it while preparing for CAT and you may not get a chance to do so once you are admitted iContinue Reading After taking CAT, if you have to appear in other exams like SNAP, IIFT or XAT, then prepare for them. Else, keeping in mind that you will have to appear for GD-PI processes of various colleges, you can try these: Widen your knowledge base in fields like Economics, History, Politics, General Awareness etc.Scan your personality and try to make it better.Find out your strengths and weaknesses.Work on your weaknesses to make them your strengths.Work on your communication and language skills.Keep a watch on the happenings in India as well as around the world.Start putting your thoughts into words.Attend mock interviews and group discussions.Last but not the least, enjoy your life a lot. You might have missed it while preparing for CAT and you may not get a chance to do so once you are admitted iContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:18:27.787Z"),
    "question" : "What should I do after CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376b800c817f0398fc144e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-hours-did-Aviral-Bhatnagar-study-for-the-CAT-exam?--",
    "answer" : "I’ve elaborated on my strategy for the CAT in detail and to some extent I began to embody my CAT strategy in my daily life. The exam is essentially about: SpeedAccuracyIn sum, being efficient. This is also how I prepared: I divided my time over what I needed to do in a pre planned mannerI executed what I was supposed to do when I decided to do itI spent roughly 3–4 hours a day on tests (the duration of an exam)I tried not to waste time on frivolous activitiesIn sum, being efficient by planning and executing (which is like the exam) To do all this you need to be healthy both physically and mentally. I sleep more than the average human being and so I did 8+ hours (also at BSchool). Do not compromise on sleep. If you’re sleeping less it’s most likely you’re not prioritizing. Life’s too short to try to do everything. Vinan Patwa",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:18:56.032Z"),
    "question" : "How many hours did Aviral Bhatnagar study for the CAT exam?  ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376bac0c817f0398fc1479"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-succeed-in-CAT-exam-by-self-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "How? By SELF-DETERMINATION. Just make sure you never give up, no matter how bleak the light looks. Make a schedule and try to stick to it. Also, be clear why you want to do a MBA. 2",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:19:40.887Z"),
    "question" : "How can I succeed in CAT exam by self-preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376bc20c817f0398fc153e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-you-prepare-for-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "For someone who has answered on CAT preparation in bits and pieces in the past, compiling all the previous inputs and answering a question like this is rather difficult. But, I’ll try to pen them down into 10 short chapters: Chapter 1 - The Beginning I was pursuing B Com (H) from Kirori Mal College and in the first semester, I got myself Arun Sharma’s QA book for CAT. Then somewhere towards the end of the first year, I purchased Arun Sharma’s other books. At that time, I knew I might need to take coaching, yet I purchased self-prep books, 6 months in advance so that: I could familiarize myself with the pattern & syllabus of the exam.I could identify my weak spots and bring them up to the mark.Chapter 2 - Six Months Later I had certainly not solved even the easiest level of questions, let alone Continue Reading For someone who has answered on CAT preparation in bits and pieces in the past, compiling all the previous inputs and answering a question like this is rather difficult. But, I’ll try to pen them down into 10 short chapters: Chapter 1 - The Beginning I was pursuing B Com (H) from Kirori Mal College and in the first semester, I got myself Arun Sharma’s QA book for CAT. Then somewhere towards the end of the first year, I purchased Arun Sharma’s other books. At that time, I knew I might need to take coaching, yet I purchased self-prep books, 6 months in advance so that: I could familiarize myself with the pattern & syllabus of the exam.I could identify my weak spots and bring them up to the mark.Chapter 2 - Six Months Later I had certainly not solved even the easiest level of questions, let alone Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:20:02.220Z"),
    "question" : "How did you prepare for CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376bd80c817f0398fc1552"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-one-score-98-prcentile-and-above-in-cat-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How can one score 98 prcentile and above in cat exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:20:24.219Z"),
    "question" : "How can one score 98 prcentile and above in cat exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c110c817f0398fc1634"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-the-correct-age-for-preparing-for-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Well there is no perfect age to start preparing for CAT but the perfect time to start preparing should be prefinal year of your graduation, so that you can give best shot after graduation and immediately join B-school, even if you fail after graduation, prepare while working here it saves a lot of time for second preparation, because preparing with job is difficult So the best time to start is pre-final year of graduation I hope this helps Thanks",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:21:21.763Z"),
    "question" : "What is the the correct age for preparing for CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c370c817f0398fc1709"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-book-should-I-buy-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Sarvesh K Verma for Aptitude. Previous year papers for LR/DI along with mocks. Again previous year papers for Verbal, try to practice parajumbles without options, read editorial section of good newspaper daily along with mocks. Join one or two test series like IMS, Testfunda or Endeavor. Avoid CL test series. Ria Kotian",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:21:59.858Z"),
    "question" : "Which book should I buy for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c500c817f0398fc171e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-website-for-practicing-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Sankar Kallepalli 3",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:22:24.179Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best website for practicing for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c770c817f0398fc17f6"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-important-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How tough is the CAT?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:23:03.046Z"),
    "question" : "What is important for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c8b0c817f0398fc1808"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-transparency-percent-of-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Vishal Kumar, former Student at Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur (2017-2019)Updated 1 year agoWhich exam is tougher: CAT or GATE? Vishal Kumar Comparison between CAT and GATE . To get into an old IIT M.Tech you need to get a rank of around 1500 in Mechanical Engineering (For inter disiplinary branches even higher ranks can be considered ). To get into an old IIM you need to get atleast 98 ile for general category and good experience . So chances of getting into iits for m.tech is much higher than for getting into iims.For Computer Science student getting into IIT for M.Tech or IIM for mba is nearly equally tough as they have limited branches for M.Tech in IIT.If you will compare the salary structure of student passing out from IITs after M.Tech/ getting a PSU through GATE VS old IIMs, IIMs clearly get a lead here. Even those pursuing mba in top iims may have a M.Tech degree or Psu experience before hand.If you have financial constContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:23:23.759Z"),
    "question" : "What is the transparency percent of the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c9e0c817f0398fc181a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-mocks-tests-one-should-appear-before-the-actual-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "The number of mocks that one can write before a CAT exam can range from 1 to 50. The number lies somewhere between this range. The actual number will vary from person to person. These mocks are basically time based full length tests that you write and does not include mocks you solve without keeping time limits or the ones where you solve only a particular section to improve your weakness. I will give a reasoning for extreme numbers. A lot of students prefer practicing for CAT by solving sums from various mocks, without actually solving the mocks with time limits. This is fine if you are excellent with your fundamentals and are able to solve the different sums that comes in different mocks with ease. In that case solving one mock just to get a feel of the exam and to plan paper strategy is  Continue Reading The number of mocks that one can write before a CAT exam can range from 1 to 50. The number lies somewhere between this range. The actual number will vary from person to person. These mocks are basically time based full length tests that you write and does not include mocks you solve without keeping time limits or the ones where you solve only a particular section to improve your weakness. I will give a reasoning for extreme numbers. A lot of students prefer practicing for CAT by solving sums from various mocks, without actually solving the mocks with time limits. This is fine if you are excellent with your fundamentals and are able to solve the different sums that comes in different mocks with ease. In that case solving one mock just to get a feel of the exam and to plan paper strategy is  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:23:42.983Z"),
    "question" : "How many mocks tests one should appear before the actual CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376cb10c817f0398fc18de"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-the-XAT-exam-tougher-than-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "No, CAT exam difficulty level is higher than XAT exam and CAT is way more tougher than XAT in terms of The major difference between Common Admission Test and Xavier Aptitude Test: Difficulty Level in XAT and CAT The difficulty of both the exam is high. The XAT is difficult due to its Decision Making and Quantitative Aptitude. The paper requires good reasoning skills. Whereas, CAT is difficult due to its Data Interpretation and Logical Reasoning Section. This appears to be a most challenging section of the exam. Time Limit for XAT and CAT In XAT there is no time limit, candidates have to attempt maximum out of 72 questions in the duration of 170 minutes. You are allowed to switch between sections in the given time window. Whereas, in CAT, there is the one-hour sectional limit for each section. Onc Continue Reading No, CAT exam difficulty level is higher than XAT exam and CAT is way more tougher than XAT in terms of The major difference between Common Admission Test and Xavier Aptitude Test: Difficulty Level in XAT and CAT The difficulty of both the exam is high. The XAT is difficult due to its Decision Making and Quantitative Aptitude. The paper requires good reasoning skills. Whereas, CAT is difficult due to its Data Interpretation and Logical Reasoning Section. This appears to be a most challenging section of the exam. Time Limit for XAT and CAT In XAT there is no time limit, candidates have to attempt maximum out of 72 questions in the duration of 170 minutes. You are allowed to switch between sections in the given time window. Whereas, in CAT, there is the one-hour sectional limit for each section. Onc Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:24:01.723Z"),
    "question" : "Is the XAT exam tougher than the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376cc60c817f0398fc18f0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-lessons-learnt-from-the-CAT-2019-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Sabari Santosh If there is one lesson I learnt from CAT 2019 ( probably a lesson I learnt for life too!) is do not attempt anything with a preconceived notion. Many a times it can become detrimental to you. Cat 2019 was my first attempt at any competitive exam ( I'm your average Joe who finished 12th, joined a tier-3 engineering college and ended up working for an IT service company). My preparation started almost a year back ( mind you there were several weeks , even months inbetween where I didn't touch my books). Since I started early , I had the liberty to prepare at my own pace. Also, i didn't join any coaching. I prepared by my own. I gave as many mocks as possible from two reputed coaching institutes. Throughout the mock season, my cat scores barely crossed 100. At times it peaked to 130s-140s, but  Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:24:22.463Z"),
    "question" : "What are the lessons learnt from the CAT 2019 exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376cd90c817f0398fc1904"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-get-self-motivation-for-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "This is one of my long posts. However, I felt it was important to set the backdrop so that readers clearly understand the message and its significance. This message has helped me. I hope, it will help you as well. Please read it only if when you are free and have time for reading. It was in March 2010 when Dhairya was discussing with his friends about their future. They were all telling what would they do after their exams of term-4 of the engineering get over. Some were about to join TIME to prepare for the CAT exam, while others were planning to join Made Easy or Engineering Circle to prepare for the GATE exam. Listening to their plans, Dhairya got worried as he still didn’t know what he wanted to do in his life. For days, he kept thinking about his future but couldn’t reach any conclusio Continue Reading This is one of my long posts. However, I felt it was important to set the backdrop so that readers clearly understand the message and its significance. This message has helped me. I hope, it will help you as well. Please read it only if when you are free and have time for reading. It was in March 2010 when Dhairya was discussing with his friends about their future. They were all telling what would they do after their exams of term-4 of the engineering get over. Some were about to join TIME to prepare for the CAT exam, while others were planning to join Made Easy or Engineering Circle to prepare for the GATE exam. Listening to their plans, Dhairya got worried as he still didn’t know what he wanted to do in his life. For days, he kept thinking about his future but couldn’t reach any conclusio Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:24:41.112Z"),
    "question" : "How do I get self motivation for CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376cfd0c817f0398fc19d3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-students-give-cat-exam-before-upsc?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:25:17.182Z"),
    "question" : "Why students give cat exam before upsc? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d0f0c817f0398fc19e2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-coaching-for-the-CAT-exam-necessary?-",
    "answer" : "No, if you are self motivated, if you can dream big, if you have a never give up attitude. You need not to opt for coaching. CAT is the exam which tests your reading ability and comprehension, your aptitude for secondary school mathematics and general data sets. If you have good reading skills, vocabulary and you are good at secondary school mathematics then you are almost done with the basic preparation. All you need to do is identify your weak areas(use mock tests) and try to overcome them. Do this until you feel comfortable with each and every topic. Yes, In case you are starting from scratch and you don't have any clue about the concepts then coaching institute might be helpful to you. They expedite the process of learning. All coaching institute could do is make you familiarize with the concepts and pattern, onus is on you to put some sincere efforts and master the concepts. Once you are good at the concepts start writing mock tests, build a test strategy, work on your weak areas. One thing to remember is, preparation is not going to be a joy ride. There will be times you score really less in the mocks, you should not get demotivated by such results. I personally feel that more than coaching a good mentor can make a huge difference, he can drive you in right direction and support you in the tough times.so find a good mentor and work with him closely. All the best. PS: I prepared myself for CAT 2018 and scored a 98 percentile. If someone need any guidance get in touch with me.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:25:35.260Z"),
    "question" : "Is coaching for the CAT exam necessary? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d290c817f0398fc1ab0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-be-the-preparation-strategy-in-the-week-before-the-actual-CAT-Exam?-",
    "answer" : "This, of course, assumes that you have been preparing for a while already and would like to further improve over the last week before CAT - the C-day. 1. Schedule You already know what time slot your test is in. Your body clock needs to be at peak performance during that slot. So your sleeping and waking times, meals, prep times should all be aligned. 2. Prepare in spurts I am going to assume you would have the remaining few days off till CAT. It is essential that you prepare in spurts instead to trying to dedicate full day to CAT prep. Instead of sitting in front of a computer screen all day, prepare for a 2–3 hours slot, take a break, prep, take a nap, prep, break. Here is a sample schedule for 9 AM slot: 7 AM - Wake up Be done with shower and breakfast by 8:45. 9 AM - 12 Noon - Mock test (or re Continue Reading This, of course, assumes that you have been preparing for a while already and would like to further improve over the last week before CAT - the C-day. 1. Schedule You already know what time slot your test is in. Your body clock needs to be at peak performance during that slot. So your sleeping and waking times, meals, prep times should all be aligned. 2. Prepare in spurts I am going to assume you would have the remaining few days off till CAT. It is essential that you prepare in spurts instead to trying to dedicate full day to CAT prep. Instead of sitting in front of a computer screen all day, prepare for a 2–3 hours slot, take a break, prep, take a nap, prep, break. Here is a sample schedule for 9 AM slot: 7 AM - Wake up Be done with shower and breakfast by 8:45. 9 AM - 12 Noon - Mock test (or re Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:26:01.257Z"),
    "question" : "What should be the preparation strategy in the week before the actual CAT Exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d3a0c817f0398fc1abd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-myself-for-the-CAT-exam-without-coaching?-",
    "answer" : "If you really want to prepare it by yourself then just purchase cat previous year question bank from Amazon and get in touch with some online channel like learn 4 exam ,Dinesh Miglani classes they are free online tutorial and just pay attention towards your studies everyday 4 to 5 hour throughly…That’& it …Hope it will help….",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:26:18.311Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare myself for the CAT exam without coaching? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d4c0c817f0398fc1ace"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-percentage-is-required-in-graduation-for-attending-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What percentage is required in graduation for attending the CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:26:36.939Z"),
    "question" : "What percentage is required in graduation for attending the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d600c817f0398fc1b8c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-first-step-of-preparation-of-cat-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Santosh Matala  Dear CAT Aspirant, First of all, You should go through the syllabus of the CAT Exam to have a better understanding of the topics, then check your basics on each of the topics likely to come in the exam. Make your schedule as per time left in target CAT exam. then give your best!!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:26:56.719Z"),
    "question" : "What is first step of preparation of cat exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d750c817f0398fc1ba5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-CAT-percentile-calculated?-",
    "answer" : "Naman Lumb To calculate the percentile, the institutions follow the CAT marking scheme. The answers will be checked & a total score will be determined. The total score will be adjusted through a process called “equating”. Then, the score will be normalized across different sections. Thereafter the normalized score secured by the candidates will be further converted into percentiles for the purposes of shortlisting. CAT MARKING SCHEME: Marking Scheme: 3 marks for each right answer. All the question (MCQ type and Non-MCQ type questions) contain equal marks.Negative Marking: For every wrong answer one marks will be deducted. However, there is no negative marking for Non-MCQ type questions.The top B-Schools have a higher range of CAT cut-offs, 90+ percentile, while the mid rung B-School cut-off range, 75 t Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:27:17.727Z"),
    "question" : "How is CAT percentile calculated? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d9d0c817f0398fc1c7b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Does-CAT-questions-repeat?-",
    "answer" : "Verbal and DILR questions do not repeat. Every year you will find a new set of questions which have not come before. But there were rare instances where quant question were repeated. This was especially when the number of slots for the CAT exams were 20 or 40. But now with the number of lots reduced we do not find repetition of questions. But concepts and methodology of solving do repeat. A similar concept could be asked in different ways. There is a function f(n+2) = f(n+1) - f(n) that has come twice in CAT and was represented differently both times. Similarly method of solving do repeat. Questions on one equation two variables with constraints has come three or four times where the way of solving is to convert the equation such that one variable is represented by the other and the substitut Continue Reading Verbal and DILR questions do not repeat. Every year you will find a new set of questions which have not come before. But there were rare instances where quant question were repeated. This was especially when the number of slots for the CAT exams were 20 or 40. But now with the number of lots reduced we do not find repetition of questions. But concepts and methodology of solving do repeat. A similar concept could be asked in different ways. There is a function f(n+2) = f(n+1) - f(n) that has come twice in CAT and was represented differently both times. Similarly method of solving do repeat. Questions on one equation two variables with constraints has come three or four times where the way of solving is to convert the equation such that one variable is represented by the other and the substitut Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:27:57.372Z"),
    "question" : "Does CAT questions repeat? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376daf0c817f0398fc1c90"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Does-the-CAT-exam-contain-only-Level-3-questions?-",
    "answer" : "A2A Historically, CAT has been perceived to be a difficult test by most of the aspirants. This is primarily because of the hype around the test (the process, tiny percentage of students who get through the IIMs and other top institutes, the hefty packages offered at these institutes, etc.) and the fact that there are many ‘experts’ who want to sell their ‘expertise’ to the aspirants. The short answer to your question is no, CAT does not contain only level 3 questions (I guess you mean the questions of the highest level of difficulty when you say level 3). Ergo, it is not recommended that you fall for the immense number of JEE and Olympiad level questions that are solved across groups probably to make you feel insecure about your level of prep. Even in the years when CAT was at its most diffic Continue Reading A2A Historically, CAT has been perceived to be a difficult test by most of the aspirants. This is primarily because of the hype around the test (the process, tiny percentage of students who get through the IIMs and other top institutes, the hefty packages offered at these institutes, etc.) and the fact that there are many ‘experts’ who want to sell their ‘expertise’ to the aspirants. The short answer to your question is no, CAT does not contain only level 3 questions (I guess you mean the questions of the highest level of difficulty when you say level 3). Ergo, it is not recommended that you fall for the immense number of JEE and Olympiad level questions that are solved across groups probably to make you feel insecure about your level of prep. Even in the years when CAT was at its most diffic Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:28:15.791Z"),
    "question" : "Does the CAT exam contain only Level-3 questions? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376dc20c817f0398fc1ca0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-I-know-about-CAT-Exam?-",
    "answer" : "The Common Admission Test (CAT) is an all-India test conducted by the Indian Institutes of Management (IIMs) as an entrance exam for admission to the Post-graduate and Fellow Programs in management courses of several management institutes all over India including the IIMs. This year CAT is going to be held on December 4, 2016 in 2 slots. Eligibility The candidate must hold a Bachelor’s Degree, with at least 50% marks or equivalent CGPA[45% in case of the candidates belonging to Scheduled Caste (SC), Scheduled Tribe (ST) andPersons With Disability (PWD) categories], awarded by any University or educationalinstitution as incorporated by an Act of the Parliament or State legislature in India ordeclared to be deemed as a University under Section 3 of the UGC Act, 1956, or possess anequivalent quaContinue Reading The Common Admission Test (CAT) is an all-India test conducted by the Indian Institutes of Management (IIMs) as an entrance exam for admission to the Post-graduate and Fellow Programs in management courses of several management institutes all over India including the IIMs. This year CAT is going to be held on December 4, 2016 in 2 slots. Eligibility The candidate must hold a Bachelor’s Degree, with at least 50% marks or equivalent CGPA[45% in case of the candidates belonging to Scheduled Caste (SC), Scheduled Tribe (ST) andPersons With Disability (PWD) categories], awarded by any University or educationalinstitution as incorporated by an Act of the Parliament or State legislature in India ordeclared to be deemed as a University under Section 3 of the UGC Act, 1956, or possess anequivalent quaContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:28:34.994Z"),
    "question" : "What should I know about CAT Exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376dea0c817f0398fc1d76"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-is-speed-crucial-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "“How would you win in a race if you have no speed?” If you have the answer to this then you can probably understand why speed is a crucial factor in CAT. It tests your knowledge on the topic while you can find right solution in a certain time limit. MBA schools doesn’t want to know how efficient you’re in grasping a topic in 10 days, they want to know how efficiently you can evaluate a problem given in stressful environment and solve it. Best Example for this? Candidate A has answered 30 questions in total with accuracy of 95% in 3 hrs will score much better percentile as compared to Candidate B who has answered 45 questions with 80% accuracy. As we see there’re only 3 months left for the CAT 2018 and you might want to consider how to prepare for better score? This answer will help you out in t Continue Reading “How would you win in a race if you have no speed?” If you have the answer to this then you can probably understand why speed is a crucial factor in CAT. It tests your knowledge on the topic while you can find right solution in a certain time limit. MBA schools doesn’t want to know how efficient you’re in grasping a topic in 10 days, they want to know how efficiently you can evaluate a problem given in stressful environment and solve it. Best Example for this? Candidate A has answered 30 questions in total with accuracy of 95% in 3 hrs will score much better percentile as compared to Candidate B who has answered 45 questions with 80% accuracy. As we see there’re only 3 months left for the CAT 2018 and you might want to consider how to prepare for better score? This answer will help you out in t Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:29:14.475Z"),
    "question" : "Why is speed crucial in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e0f0c817f0398fc1e42"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Do-registrations-for-the-CAT-exam-affect-percentile-scores?-",
    "answer" : "Hi, NO, Registration for CAT does not affects the Percentile Score anyhow.There are no connection between CAT Registration and CAT Percentile. CAT Registration is  only for applying CAT Exam, whereas CAT Percentile depend according to your performance of your exam. For more details, Visit Collegedekho Website. Thanks. Bharat Patodi",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:29:51.755Z"),
    "question" : "Do registrations for the CAT exam affect percentile scores? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e280c817f0398fc1e5c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-one-can-get-100-percentile-on-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Shashank Prabhu As far as your question goes, there is not single way to ensure that you get a 100 percentile in the CAT (if there were, everybody would have scored a 100, which would mean that no one would have scored a 100). You can only prepare the basics well and hope that the following things happen: You have prepared your backside off and have covered almost everything that was there to be coveredThe test is completely designed to suit your strengthsYou are in an amazing frame of mind when you are taking the testAll but 10 - 12 people perform worse than youNormalization works in your favourNow, when people say that if you prepare hard you will get a good score of course they are talking about the first point. If you put in a strong effort, cover your basics well, solve a large number of quality quest Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:30:16.531Z"),
    "question" : "How one can get 100 percentile on the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e3a0c817f0398fc1e6c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Do-luck-matters-in-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Jyoti Ranjan Padhiary 1",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:30:34.556Z"),
    "question" : "Do luck matters in CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e4e0c817f0398fc1f2e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-books-for-improving-grammar-and-vocabulary-to-excel-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Swaminathan Ravikumar Since you asked specifically for the CAT, I would say: There is no need to excel in grammar or vocabulary in the CAT exam. The CAT does not care too much about either grammar or vocabulary (less about vocab than grammar). In CAT 2014 and 2015, there wasn't a single vocab based question. Even before that, the emphasis was always on testing to see if a candidate had a decent reading habit, and not whether they had excellent language or vocab.  The CAT has always used passages that are very pleasant to read. These will hardly ever have obscure words that are not used in regular parlance. So long as you have a healthy reading habit (i.e., you read for 45 mins to an hour every day), you will do well for the Verbal Section.  Trying to improve your grammar or vocab from a single book (or books mean Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:30:54.779Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best books for improving grammar and vocabulary to excel in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e640c817f0398fc1f46"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-sort-of-work-experience-is-needed-for-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:31:16.067Z"),
    "question" : "What sort of work experience is needed for CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e760c817f0398fc1f56"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-study-materials-for-the-CAT-exam-preparation-and-interview?-",
    "answer" : "Aman Patni For preparation you can refer the following reference books as per your choice. 1) How to prepare for Quantitative Aptitude for the CAT. How to prepare for Data Interpretation for the CAT. How to prepare for Logical Reasoning for CAT. How to prepare for Vetbal Ability and Reading Comprehension for CAT by ARUN SHARMA 2) Pearson Guide to Quantitative for CAT by Nishit Sinha. Pearson Guide to Quantitative and Data Interpretation by Nishit Sinha. Pearson Giude to Logical Reasoning for Cat by Nishit Sinha. Pearson Guide to Vetbal Ability and Readinv Comprehension by Nishit Sinha. There are many other books like Word Power made easy by Norman Lewis, High School English Grammer and Composition by Wren and Martin etc. to help you for preparation. You can join various institute like TIMES, CL, IMS etc Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:31:34.328Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best study materials for the CAT exam preparation and interview? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e8b0c817f0398fc2018"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-are-CAT-exams-held?-",
    "answer" : "CAT 2016 Exam Dates Online Application Form Starts - 6th August to 20th September 2016 Admit Card download window - 25th October till Exam date Exam Date - 29th November 2016 CAT 2015 Exam Dates CAT 2015 Application Deadline extended till - Friday, September 25, 2015 CAT 2015 Admit Card Download starts - Sunday, October 25, 2015 CAT 2015 Exam Date - Sunday, November 29, 2015 CAT 2015 Result Date - Friday, January 8, 2016",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:31:55.881Z"),
    "question" : "When are CAT exams held? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e9d0c817f0398fc202e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-online-materials-should-I-refer-to-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Usually, coaching classes can provide the best study material for preparation as they have concise and updated notes. Apart from that, here are some good study materials online - Word Power Made Easy by Norman Lewis. This will help you in the verbal section. https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLtMMdSqG5Rhz4Zj1_IdMWjDsgB6KQvCMqHome - Wordpandit https://wordpandit.com/http://Classmint.com http://classmint.com/Free resources of CATKing https://catking.in/free-resources/",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:32:13.865Z"),
    "question" : "Which online materials should I refer to for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ec00c817f0398fc2053"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-new-pattern-of-GMAT-and-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "The GMAT is a tough test to crack, not just because it needs a skilled approach but also because most of the applicants are shaken by the pressure of the big day. However, GMAT is the number one choice for MBA aspirants all over the world. Here is everything you need to know about the exam pattern of GMAT: All you need to know about GMAT ! Stand out and mark a difference, Educolada - India's Eductaion Portal",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:32:48.345Z"),
    "question" : "What is the new pattern of GMAT and CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ed80c817f0398fc2118"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-cat-exam-be-delayed-this-year?-",
    "answer" : "As per the information by the central government, IIT JEE exams are expected to be conducted in the month of July. This means the government is expecting things to return to near normal before that. If you look at it as of May, government has already started some manufacturing and other economic activity. Over a period of time it is expected that the economy will further open up. The whole cycle of MBA entrance exam starts with CAT. Delay in CAT would delay the MBA admission cycle. CAT is an entrance exam for many MBA colleges apart from IIMs. Delay in CAT will mean delay in the process for all these colleges, some of the colleges like SP Jain have their round 2 process beginning before the IIMs. Considering these factors, CAT will not be delayed. Patrick Dsouza 6 times CAT 100%iler",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:33:12.192Z"),
    "question" : "Will cat exam be delayed this year? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376eec0c817f0398fc2128"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-questions-are-there-in-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "Thanks for A2A Here is my section wise attempt and correct incorrect breakup in CAT 2018: VARC total attempts: 34 correct: 28 wrong (negatives): 4 wrong (non negatives): 2 Scaled score: 82.5, Percentile: 99.77 DILR total attempts: 18 Correct: 17 wrong (negatives): 0 wrong (non negatives): 1 Scaled score: 53.03, Percentile: 99.73 QA total attempts: 20 Correct:16 wrong (negatives): 1 wrong (non negatives): 3 Scaled score: 46.85, Percentile: 97.87 Overall scaled score: 182.37, Overall percentile: 99.82%ile",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:33:32.874Z"),
    "question" : "How many questions are there in CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f040c817f0398fc21ea"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-make-quants-section-easy-in-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Hi, I would suggest you to start your preparation by brushing up your fundamentals.After your fundamentals are thorough, you can start attempting mock tests and gain speed and accuracy. also after each mock test, you will gain more insights into areas where you are weak and needs more attention. Ability in Maths is one of the most important in management entrance tests. If one considers Data Interpretation as part of maths, then the quantitative portion is 2/3rd of the paper. People who are weak in maths need not fear since a logical approach will help clear this section quite easily. Topics like number systems, percentages, profit and loss, time and distance, must be thoroughly done. A large part of the paper has algebra too, so the student must have complete knowledge of quadratic equation Continue Reading Hi, I would suggest you to start your preparation by brushing up your fundamentals.After your fundamentals are thorough, you can start attempting mock tests and gain speed and accuracy. also after each mock test, you will gain more insights into areas where you are weak and needs more attention. Ability in Maths is one of the most important in management entrance tests. If one considers Data Interpretation as part of maths, then the quantitative portion is 2/3rd of the paper. People who are weak in maths need not fear since a logical approach will help clear this section quite easily. Topics like number systems, percentages, profit and loss, time and distance, must be thoroughly done. A large part of the paper has algebra too, so the student must have complete knowledge of quadratic equation Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:33:56.222Z"),
    "question" : "How can I make quants section easy in CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f150c817f0398fc2202"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-much-do-I-have-to-score-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Short answer: 100! Long answer: Your profile looks pretty okay to me and if you score anything north of a 99%ile, you should have a fair chance at at least a few of the old IIMs and FMS at least. It could be even lower for something like an MDI or a NITIE (the latter would also require you to have a good split across sections). XLRI, NMIMS, JBIMS, IIFT, SIBM should also be possible. In fact, if I am not wrong you might sneak in through the mystery that is the SPJIMR shortlist. So, bottom line, you are pretty much good to go with that profile. An advice which I give to almost everyone who asks me for cutoffs, predictions, etc: I see you have done very well in your acads till now. Don’t limit yourself with random numbers which people might throw at you. Prepare as much as you can and score as many as you are able to. From what I understand of the processes, you are already at a level that would place you above at least 95–97% of the test takers at the moment. So, take a few mocks, figure out where you are at the moment, ask someone who knows the process where you could go from there, and work accordingly. Hope that helps. All the best!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:34:13.210Z"),
    "question" : "How much do I have to score in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f280c817f0398fc2212"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-job-opportunities-after-qualifying-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:34:32.880Z"),
    "question" : "What are the job opportunities after qualifying CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f3e0c817f0398fc22dc"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-a-commerce-student-crack-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Patrick Dsouza Most of my students are from non engineering background and most of them do ace the CAT. The topper of my batch last year was a commerce student with around 99.9%ile and made it to IIM A. As a matter of fact it is easier to teach a non engineer as they come with the idea that they do not know much and are open to learning new methods and techniques. At the onset I feel it is wrong to classify the students as Engineer, Commerce, Arts or any other background. The ability of the students to crack the exam does not depend on background. This classification just puts a mental block in some of the students. Understand the topics covered is all school level which all students no matter what background, have covered it. There is no advantage for engineers. Unfortunately some of the books and classe Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:34:54.268Z"),
    "question" : "Can a commerce student crack the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f6b0c817f0398fc230d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-do-I-read-every-day-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "If you are a beginner and have a lot of time in hand: For starters, read anything you like. This creates an interest in reading, makes you curious to read more and develops your habit of reading. If you read books of your interest you won’t feel sleepy or lose interest or procrastinate (as all these happens with me and I am a procrastinator of highest level). Once you are comfortable with reading, start reading articles from newspaper(specially editorials) and books of your favourite genre. Over the time your reading will improve and so will the curiosity to read about something new. If you have a habit of reading books and articles of your interest and have time in hand:Start reading articles and books of different genres such as philosophy, arts, science, technology, sports, politics, h Continue Reading If you are a beginner and have a lot of time in hand: For starters, read anything you like. This creates an interest in reading, makes you curious to read more and develops your habit of reading. If you read books of your interest you won’t feel sleepy or lose interest or procrastinate (as all these happens with me and I am a procrastinator of highest level). Once you are comfortable with reading, start reading articles from newspaper(specially editorials) and books of your favourite genre. Over the time your reading will improve and so will the curiosity to read about something new. If you have a habit of reading books and articles of your interest and have time in hand:Start reading articles and books of different genres such as philosophy, arts, science, technology, sports, politics, h Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:35:39.324Z"),
    "question" : "What do I read every day for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f7c0c817f0398fc23c6"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-there-any-reservation-for-CA-students-writing-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "No, there is no reservation for CA students.  But if you have work experience, then it will be added advantage at the time of GD/PI as sometimes IIMs look for better batch composition and your credentials may fit in. More details about reservation were given in CAT advertisement:Page on iimcat.ac.in",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:35:56.066Z"),
    "question" : "Is there any reservation for CA students writing CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f910c817f0398fc23dd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-calculation-tips-for-cat-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:36:17.494Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best calculation tips for cat exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376fa80c817f0398fc23f7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/From-where-can-I-get-all-the-shortcuts-and-formulas-required-for-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "You can check the formula book that I created during CAT 2017 here - CAT Formula Book. Having shared the link, I want to remind you that using a ready-made formula book doesn’t help in the CAT exam. When you solve questions, you need to create your own formula book by noting down the shortcuts and tricks you come across. That’s the only way you’ll be able to apply them the next time a similar question appears in the exam. You can use this book as a reference to see how a formula book can be created. But, would strongly suggest creating one on your own. Subhikhya Sethi",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:36:40.564Z"),
    "question" : "From where can I get all the shortcuts and formulas required for CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376fe50c817f0398fc24df"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-plan-my-career-after-taking-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Manas Chaturvedi",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:37:41.157Z"),
    "question" : "How do I plan my career after taking the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ff70c817f0398fc25ad"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/From-which-class-can-we-start-preparation-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Parth Jain",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:37:59.731Z"),
    "question" : "From which class can we start preparation for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037700c0c817f0398fc25c2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-Thejaswi-Udupa-prepare-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "I'm rather surprised that this question exists. Short answer, I did not prepare. Doing an MBA was never really part of my plan. Buying the CAT application form was an impulsive decision taken on a day when I was accompanying a friend of mine when he was buying his. I even regretted the decision a bit later that day as it meant lesser money to spend on books and music. The only \"preparation\" was attempting the sample paper that came as part of the application. And writing one mock-test done by one of these coaching centre types--I don't remember which one, but the exam was at Stracey's right opposite Koshys. And I do not remember what resulted from it either. The CAT was in the middle of NLS's college fest, and all I remember is rushing back in time to attend some quiz there. I missed all the hoopla of discussing answers right after and trying to figure out where you may stand. And until the results came, I was fairly certain I had done pretty badly (there was a point in time during the exam, towards the end, where all I could think about was taking a leak--so fairly certain I wasn't my sharpest for the last 10 minutes or so) So, do I put down my CAT score to luck? Not much. I think the nature of CAT, with its emphasis on English, maths and solving problems quickly, happened to match with things I was already good at. Because I used to read a lot, because I would get kicks out of solving puzzles of various sorts and had seen enough to quickly detect patterns, etc. So \"preparation\" in a sense had happened over the course of many years, without having CAT in mind. It was useful that CAT played to my strengths, that is all. Would a similar approach have worked for, say, GATE for me--definitely not.  If this question was asked with the intent of finding useful advice, skip my answer. What worked for me may not work for you.  If it were to just sate curiosity, I hope it answers your question.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:38:20.358Z"),
    "question" : "How did Thejaswi Udupa prepare for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770230c817f0398fc25dd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-be-my-approach-and-CAT-percentile-to-get-into-IIMs?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What should be my approach and CAT percentile to get into IIMs?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:38:43.198Z"),
    "question" : "What should be my approach and CAT percentile to get into IIMs? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770360c817f0398fc26a1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-percentile-is-calculated-in-the-CAT-exams-per-section?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Nikhil Lunia",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:39:02.523Z"),
    "question" : "What percentile is calculated in the CAT exams per section? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037704d0c817f0398fc26b5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Was-the-AIMCAT-1813-LRDI-section-equivalent-to-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Nitesh Goyal, 99.93 %ile in CAT 2019Updated 9 months agoHow did you prepare for LRDI for the CAT exam? Nitesh Goyal It’s a game of mindset !! LRDI is considered as the toughest and the most challenging section of CAT. But let us leave aside these notions for once and read this out, I’ll tell you how was I able to shoot up my score from 98.4 %ile in CAT’17 LRDI to 99.96 %ile in CAT’19 LRDI. As all other sections, I’ll split the answer in two parts - Preparation and Test Strategy. Preparation Start with any study material, preferably, Arun Sharma for LR or any coaching modules. Solve questions on basic topics like Seating arrangements, Rankings, Venn Diagram, Games and Tournaments, Puzzles, Quantitative Reasoning etc. These questions are never asked directly in CAT , but a lot of practice on these topics will help you in developing the logic required for questions asked in CAT.You don’t need to prepare for DContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:39:25.588Z"),
    "question" : "Was the AIMCAT 1813 LRDI section equivalent to CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770620c817f0398fc26c9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-comes-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers 1",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:39:46.658Z"),
    "question" : "What comes in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770930c817f0398fc27a1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-CAT-with-job?-",
    "answer" : "Pranay Mehra If you prefer self study rather than coaching and starting your preparation from scratch and looking for good study material at one place that can fetch you a good score in exams then have a look to the below mentioned PDFs which I am selling : Past year papers:CAT - 1990 – 2019, SNAP - 2004-2018, TISS – 2014,2016 – 2018, IIFT - 2007-2019, XAT - 2008-2020 & MAT,NMAT,CMAT etc. Past year Mocks :Time (Aimcat) - 2007 – 2019, Cl - 2010 – 2018, IMS (Simcat) - 2014 – 2016,2019 Quant Massive material:Number system full concepts II Handy formulae and short tricks for Quantitative aptitude II RS Agarawal Quant II Number system by Nishit K Sinha II Arun sharma Quant II Quantum CAT II Quicker maths Practice book by Tyra II Kundan Quant II Alzebra Formulae II Remainders all Theorems II Fast track objectiv Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:40:35.622Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for CAT with job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770ab0c817f0398fc286a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-apply-for-BBA-course-without-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Geetanjali Kalra Yes, You can app;y for BBA without CAT. The basic minimum criteria to get admission in maximum institutes is 50% aggregate marks in 10+2. BBA is a stepping stone to the high value postgraduate course, MBA. Intermediates study the graduation course in Business Administration to get basic idea on the business principles and strategies. The course helps an individual to gain essential knowledge about the corporate world and also the fundamentals of administration. The main thing is from where you pursue studies to give a start to your career. Be wise while choosing institute or university, there are some good Universities like: Christ University Lovely Professional University KIIT University Amity University Manipal University These institutes/ Universities offer you good practical and industrial exp Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:40:59.652Z"),
    "question" : "Can I apply for BBA course without CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770f50c817f0398fc2963"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-a-BCom-student-crack-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Yes. The “B-Com” student must have a good understanding of class 10th level Maths and English or should work hard for 12–16 months to build that understanding. 33% of IIM A batch of 2017–19 is non engineers. So, of course can be done!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:42:13.001Z"),
    "question" : "Can a BCom student crack the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037712d0c817f0398fc2a4b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-IMS-for-preparation-of-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "GammaClasses Cat",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:43:09.790Z"),
    "question" : "How is IMS for preparation of CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037714f0c817f0398fc2a6a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-college-registration-closes-before-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:43:43.425Z"),
    "question" : "Which college registration closes before the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037716b0c817f0398fc2b38"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-have-you-learnt-from-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What have you learnt from CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:44:11.985Z"),
    "question" : "What have you learnt from CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771850c817f0398fc2b4e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-book-for-verbal-ability-for-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "The usual and the most popular confusion MBA Aspirants have regarding CAT Preparation is about books/study material for CAT Exam. The choice of books is vast and quite varied. But what MBA Aspirants need to understand is that it is not the choice of books that they refer to but how they refer to these books. All books available in the market are very similar in the nature of their content of study material but the important thing is what you make of it. Here are some of the best books for CAT preparation Quantum CAT:Arihant Publications2. High School English Grammar and Composition Book: Wren and Martin 3. Word Power Made Easy:Norman Lewis 4. Past Years' CAT Questions:G.K. Publications Best books for Verbal Ability: How to Prepare for Verbal Ability and Reading Comprehension for CAT:Arun Sharma Continue Reading The usual and the most popular confusion MBA Aspirants have regarding CAT Preparation is about books/study material for CAT Exam. The choice of books is vast and quite varied. But what MBA Aspirants need to understand is that it is not the choice of books that they refer to but how they refer to these books. All books available in the market are very similar in the nature of their content of study material but the important thing is what you make of it. Here are some of the best books for CAT preparation Quantum CAT:Arihant Publications2. High School English Grammar and Composition Book: Wren and Martin 3. Word Power Made Easy:Norman Lewis 4. Past Years' CAT Questions:G.K. Publications Best books for Verbal Ability: How to Prepare for Verbal Ability and Reading Comprehension for CAT:Arun Sharma Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:44:37.039Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best book for verbal ability for the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037719c0c817f0398fc2c17"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-we-improve-our-speed-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How can we improve our speed in the CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:45:00.800Z"),
    "question" : "How can we improve our speed in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771b10c817f0398fc2c2a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-type-of-questions-are-there-in-general-studies-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "there will be no section allotted to general studies in cat..it had only three sections they are quant, logical reasoning, verbal ability",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:45:21.914Z"),
    "question" : "Which type of questions are there in general studies in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771db0c817f0398fc2d02"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-get-some-good-coaching-for-CAT-exam-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "All the best for your this year's exam. However if you really want to excel this exam (in case you get another opportunity to crack this exam) then go for BYJU classes without giving a second thought. Mr. Byju Raveendran, two times 100 percentiler has a unique and unconventional way to teach quant section. Also Mr. P N Santosh, the English section trainer is probably one of the best in India. You take their demo class once (it is free) or else some YOUTUBE videos (believe me they are the best and you will say the same thing after seeing them) and  if you find it worth then join or else curse me for telling you such an option. CAUTION:- They are completely against conventional teaching and rote learning and have their unique way towards this exam. So be ready and let's face it.   All the bes Continue Reading All the best for your this year's exam. However if you really want to excel this exam (in case you get another opportunity to crack this exam) then go for BYJU classes without giving a second thought. Mr. Byju Raveendran, two times 100 percentiler has a unique and unconventional way to teach quant section. Also Mr. P N Santosh, the English section trainer is probably one of the best in India. You take their demo class once (it is free) or else some YOUTUBE videos (believe me they are the best and you will say the same thing after seeing them) and  if you find it worth then join or else curse me for telling you such an option. CAUTION:- They are completely against conventional teaching and rote learning and have their unique way towards this exam. So be ready and let's face it.   All the bes Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:46:03.098Z"),
    "question" : "How can I get some good coaching for CAT-exam preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772230c817f0398fc2df4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-tips-and-tricks-to-clear-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Here you go: First 4 to 5 set of questions will be of Reading Comprehension. You must know how to read the passage fast (Speed reading techniques must be followed). To master this art you must read the newspaper daily and also try to understand the section which you have read in one go. You must try and solve the RC’s within 35 mins so that the rest 25 mins can be given to the VR questions and the grammar part.Now for DI section, you must be familiar with all possible graphs and charts. You must know how to read them and infer data from it. DI is not that tough provided that you are real fast with your calculations. While practicing try doing all the calculations by yourself. Avoid the use of calculators.LR can only be solved with rigorous practice. Keep your head cool while solving it and Continue Reading Here you go: First 4 to 5 set of questions will be of Reading Comprehension. You must know how to read the passage fast (Speed reading techniques must be followed). To master this art you must read the newspaper daily and also try to understand the section which you have read in one go. You must try and solve the RC’s within 35 mins so that the rest 25 mins can be given to the VR questions and the grammar part.Now for DI section, you must be familiar with all possible graphs and charts. You must know how to read them and infer data from it. DI is not that tough provided that you are real fast with your calculations. While practicing try doing all the calculations by yourself. Avoid the use of calculators.LR can only be solved with rigorous practice. Keep your head cool while solving it and Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:47:15.765Z"),
    "question" : "What are some tips and tricks to clear the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772390c817f0398fc2e0b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-colleges-accept-CAT-scores?-",
    "answer" : "A few colleges that you can target if you are aiming at a percentile of 95 and above. 1. FMS, Delhi 2. XLRI, Jamshedpur (conduct their own test) 3. MDI, Gurgaon 4. IIFT, Delhi (conduct their own test) 5. NMIMS, Mumbai (conduct their own test) 6. SIBM, Pune and SCMHRD, Pune (conduct their own test) 7. NITIE, Mumbai (if you are interested in operations and are from an engineering background) 8. DoMS of various IITs (popular ones being SJMSOM, IIT D and VGSOM) 9. Latest IIMs (they might be less picky when it comes to shortlisting students but you would need a good score to be shortlisted ~96%ile) You can have a look at the list of good institutes that offer an MBA programme with the probable cut-offs and the tests they accept here: Post CAT 2015 result | Which institutes to apply to? - Learningroots Do  Continue Reading A few colleges that you can target if you are aiming at a percentile of 95 and above. 1. FMS, Delhi 2. XLRI, Jamshedpur (conduct their own test) 3. MDI, Gurgaon 4. IIFT, Delhi (conduct their own test) 5. NMIMS, Mumbai (conduct their own test) 6. SIBM, Pune and SCMHRD, Pune (conduct their own test) 7. NITIE, Mumbai (if you are interested in operations and are from an engineering background) 8. DoMS of various IITs (popular ones being SJMSOM, IIT D and VGSOM) 9. Latest IIMs (they might be less picky when it comes to shortlisting students but you would need a good score to be shortlisted ~96%ile) You can have a look at the list of good institutes that offer an MBA programme with the probable cut-offs and the tests they accept here: Post CAT 2015 result | Which institutes to apply to? - Learningroots Do  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:47:37.296Z"),
    "question" : "Which colleges accept CAT scores? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772500c817f0398fc2eda"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-difference-between-CET-and-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the difference between CET and CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:48:00.433Z"),
    "question" : "What is the difference between CET and CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037728e0c817f0398fc2fc3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Would-coaching-for-the-CAT-also-help-in-preparation-of-the-Bank-PO-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Yes it does. For a sharp student, aptitude means aptitude and CAT aptitude is at a higher level than banking. Thus, preparing for CAT aptitude makes your concepts clear for banking - not all but most concepts. If you are preparing for MAT and CMAT along with CAT then you are more likely to complete most concepts for BANK PO as well. Banking awareness, General awareness and Reasoning sections have some additional topics and need more focus - actually all good CAT coaching institutes have good content for most of these topics as well - you should make sure you utilize the content. For example, at B-Factory, we give a student login which contains daily 3–4 Current affairs update and has 250+ GS tests. If you are a banking candidate as well, you must cover this. Additionally, you should take a te Continue Reading Yes it does. For a sharp student, aptitude means aptitude and CAT aptitude is at a higher level than banking. Thus, preparing for CAT aptitude makes your concepts clear for banking - not all but most concepts. If you are preparing for MAT and CMAT along with CAT then you are more likely to complete most concepts for BANK PO as well. Banking awareness, General awareness and Reasoning sections have some additional topics and need more focus - actually all good CAT coaching institutes have good content for most of these topics as well - you should make sure you utilize the content. For example, at B-Factory, we give a student login which contains daily 3–4 Current affairs update and has 250+ GS tests. If you are a banking candidate as well, you must cover this. Additionally, you should take a te Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:49:02.739Z"),
    "question" : "Would coaching for the CAT also help in preparation of the Bank PO exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772a60c817f0398fc2fd7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-preparing-for-the-CAT-enough-for-admission?-",
    "answer" : "100%iler GEM - Rejected from ABC 99.98%iler GEM- Rejected from AC. No call from B. 99.78 G-NE-M- Rejected from C. No call from B. 99.76 GEM- Rejected from C no AB call 99.92 G-NE-M - rejected from AC. No B call.. 99.90 G-NE-M- Rejected from C. No AB calls. 99.81 GEM- Rejected from C. No AB calls. 99.89 G-NE-M- Rejected from C,no AB calls. 99.60 G-NE-M- Rejected from A. No BC calls. 99.98 GEF- No A call. 99.62 GEM- Rejected from C. No AB calls. 99.86 GEM- Rejected from AC. No B call. Hell,no Indore call. And the list goes on and on. This is only from this year. Happens every year. Admission? LMAO. You'll be lucky to get a call. I'm one of the GEMs in the list above. Aim for XAT/GMAT/MDI or max FMS via CAT if your acads are bad. I can only imagine how the others in the list must be feeling right now. It hur Continue Reading 100%iler GEM - Rejected from ABC 99.98%iler GEM- Rejected from AC. No call from B. 99.78 G-NE-M- Rejected from C. No call from B. 99.76 GEM- Rejected from C no AB call 99.92 G-NE-M - rejected from AC. No B call.. 99.90 G-NE-M- Rejected from C. No AB calls. 99.81 GEM- Rejected from C. No AB calls. 99.89 G-NE-M- Rejected from C,no AB calls. 99.60 G-NE-M- Rejected from A. No BC calls. 99.98 GEF- No A call. 99.62 GEM- Rejected from C. No AB calls. 99.86 GEM- Rejected from AC. No B call. Hell,no Indore call. And the list goes on and on. This is only from this year. Happens every year. Admission? LMAO. You'll be lucky to get a call. I'm one of the GEMs in the list above. Aim for XAT/GMAT/MDI or max FMS via CAT if your acads are bad. I can only imagine how the others in the list must be feeling right now. It hur Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:49:26.713Z"),
    "question" : "Is preparing for the CAT enough for admission? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772c10c817f0398fc309f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-type-of-English-is-used-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:49:53.004Z"),
    "question" : "Which type of English is used in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772dd0c817f0398fc30bd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-clear-CAT-exam?-What-are-some-books?-",
    "answer" : "There is no easy way to clear CAT. But there are some pointers which might be helpful- Find out your strong areas ( even chapters within a area) and work on them. They will become your marks earners. Find your weak subjects and make sure they don't bring down your marks (negative marking is a silent killer)Don't try to study from too many sources. Focus on 1 source - it may be your coaching class material or books suggested by some mentor or notes of a ex-CAT giverLearn the BASIC CONCEPTS. Short cuts are useless without them. If you know why something is done probably you have better chances to decipher the question.PRACTICE ! Alas, There is no substitute for that. You have to practice to get speed, accuracy and confidence of attempting a question. Regular practice will also help you in unContinue Reading There is no easy way to clear CAT. But there are some pointers which might be helpful- Find out your strong areas ( even chapters within a area) and work on them. They will become your marks earners. Find your weak subjects and make sure they don't bring down your marks (negative marking is a silent killer)Don't try to study from too many sources. Focus on 1 source - it may be your coaching class material or books suggested by some mentor or notes of a ex-CAT giverLearn the BASIC CONCEPTS. Short cuts are useless without them. If you know why something is done probably you have better chances to decipher the question.PRACTICE ! Alas, There is no substitute for that. You have to practice to get speed, accuracy and confidence of attempting a question. Regular practice will also help you in unContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:50:21.774Z"),
    "question" : "How can I score in CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772f20c817f0398fc30d3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-learnings-by-a-CAT-100-percentiler-from-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "This season for exams is over. So thought about sharing my learning from the various exams I have given. To start with, let me put forward my results for this year (some scorecards attached). I had given three exams in all. CAT16 – 100%ile (Scored 100%ile in CAT for the third time) XAT17 – 99.999%ile - Rk 1 (second time in a row) CET17 – 99.99%ile – (CET does not give out a 100 %ile, the top scorers get 99.99%ile)   The results were special as the score in CAT was around 250, which is actually around 30 marks more than most of the 100%ilers many of them have scored in the bracket of 219 and 220. This itself was an achievement to be able to perform better than the best in a very competitive exam. To add to this, coming first in XAT exam for the second time in a row and being able to ace CET was icing in the cake. There are a lot of learning from the CET exam I gave, but in this article I would want to focus on the learning from the CAT exam. Let me start with my CAT15 results - Scored an overall of 99.99%ile with 99.93%ile in VA, 99.67%ile in DILR and 99.98%ile in QA. As far as I know, I missed the 100%ile by less than a mark in CAT15. Learning from DILR section: Though I was happy with the CAT15 result, what I was not happy that time was my DILR result. I am quite strong with respect to logic and do well in Maths mainly because of tackling the questions logically. I have scored 100%ile twice before in both the DILR section and the Maths section and I usually am able to attempt all the questions in the two sections with some time to spare in most of my previous CAT attempts. But CAT15 was a nightmare with regards to DILR. I went back and analysed. I realised that I did the same mistake what I tell others not to do. I tell students not to predict the paper before the exam and go with an open mind. I went with an assumption that I would be able to solve all the questions of DILR as I have usually done. So I did go sequentially without bothering to pick the easy ones. That was not a good decision and it resulted in me attempting the tough questions first and then leaving out the easy ones in the end. This I rectified in my CAT16 paper. I chose the questions correctly and was not able to attempt all the sets but the fact that I left the most difficult questions helped me to score a 100%ile in the DILR section for the third time. So one of the main contributors of increasing my score from 99.99%ile to being 30 marks more than the some of the other students who scored 100%ile was DILR. And the change happened only because of change in mindset and the change in strategy. Learning – Don’t try to predict the CAT paper – don’t take it for granted. Strategy plays an important role in optimising your marks in the paper. Learning from Quant section: I clearly remember discussing questions of Maths with one of my friends who is amazing at Quant. This was just before CAT16 results were out. When he told me some of his methods I realised, how less I know about Maths. It actually shattered my confidence with regards to Maths section. This also happens when I see questions from the various forums where they discuss CAT Maths questions. I hardly can solve half of them. But when the CAT17 results were out, my confidence in my methods was restored. I scored a 99.96%ile in Maths section in CAT16 and have scored a 99.98%ile in CAT15 and have scored twice a 100%ile in the Quant section. I also realised that I who am scoring decent marks in the Quant section, gets scared with such questions, I wonder what is the plight of average students who go through these forums. What I have realised is CAT Maths is not pure Maths, but involves simple methods to crack the exam. Unfortunately students instead of focussing on methods focus on learning formulae. Learning – CAT Math is easier than it looks if you learn the right techniques Learning from Verbal section: I always knew that reading is the most important aspect about improving your Verbal section. I always used to recommend students to read editorials of newspapers, magazines and topics which students are not comfortable with. Last 2 years I have been a little lazy about reading editorials. But I have picked up reading something that I like just before the exams. Read Lord of the Rings, P G Wodehouse and other books that I like reading. I still managed to score high in CAT Verbal section in both 2015 and 2016. What I realised is that it is not only important to read but also enjoy what you read. Learning – Read a lot. But more important to enjoy what you read. Website: PatrickCAT100Percentile To join WhatsApp Group - WhatsApp to 09821314788 Facebook Group : Log into Facebook | Facebook (CAT 100 percentile group)",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:50:42.671Z"),
    "question" : "What are the learnings by a CAT 100 percentiler from the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037730d0c817f0398fc319a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-books-for-GK-for-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "GK for CAT ?? Strange!! Are you kidding me?? Dear, there is no portion of GK to be asked in CAT… CAT consists of four portions to study: VerbalAptitudeData InterpretationLogical ReasoningWishes!! Deepak Pandey",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:51:09.126Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best books for GK for CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773430c817f0398fc327d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-worth-having-tension-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Vijay Rajeev, Writes about CAT, MAT, XAT, SNAP-IIMs & other some B schoolsUpdated 2 years ago · Author has 71 answers and 301.3K answer viewsIs it worth having tension for the CAT exam? Vijay Rajeev Definitely!!! Only 2 types of people have no tension- the ones who studied everything(which doesn’t exist since this is CAT and there is no end to limit to studying) and the ones who write CAT for no reason(maybe they paid for fun and decided to wing it). If you are stressed, my friend, you have put some amount of work at the least. You might also notice time is going very fast(there was 1 month left for CAT 2 days back but all of a sudden, now there’s only 2 weeks). These are obvious signs that you have studied quite a bit and was involved in some activities. Stress for CAT is very good in a sense, because it makes you realize you have more to work on and you will do that eventually. But if you stress too much, you might even give up, which is not an ideal thing. I’m also writing CAT, I’m also Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:52:03.168Z"),
    "question" : "Is it worth having tension for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773620c817f0398fc3295"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-prepare-for-the-MBA-CET-2018-after-completing-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How should I prepare for the MBA CET 2018 after completing the CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:52:34.806Z"),
    "question" : "How should I prepare for the MBA CET 2018 after completing the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773780c817f0398fc335f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-colleges-are-worth-taking-through-the-CAT-exam-other-than-the-IIMs?-",
    "answer" : "There are many other top B-Schools in India through CAT other than IIMs. Some of them are: Faculty of Management Studies (FMS Delhi)Department of Management Studies, IIT DelhiShailesh J. Mehta School of Management, SOM, IIT BombayDepartment of Management Studies, IIT MadrasManagement Development Institute, GurgaonSP Jain Institute of Management and Research (SPJIMR), MumbaiXavier Institute of Management, Bhubaneswar (XIMB)Institute of Management Technology, GhaziabadNational Institute of Industrial Engineering (NITIE)T.A. Pai Management Institute (TAPMI), ManipalLoyola Institute of Business Administration (LIBA), ChennaiSymbiosis International University, Pune, India.SVKM's Narsee Monjee Institute of Management Studies, HyderabadAurora's Business School Hyderabad,All The Best!!!!!!!!!!!!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:52:56.787Z"),
    "question" : "What colleges are worth taking through the CAT exam other than the IIMs? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773950c817f0398fc337d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-was-your-height-of-dedication-for-CAT-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Priyanka, M.Sc in Applied Maths from Jadavpur University (2020)Updated 1 year ago · Author has 80 answers and 1.7M answer viewsWhat was your height of dedication for CAT preparation? Priyanka This is the first time I am sharing this. It's for those who think they are average and CAT or B-Schools aren't for them. It's for those who think they have no talent. Because I was your average CAT aspirant. It is for those who are willing to fight to prove their worth. The evening when I entered my CAT details in IIM Kozhikode's website. I can not explain the adrenaline rush and the overwhelming feeling when it showed I am eligible for the next round. I literally choked and lumps barred my words from escaping my mouth. I needed to get support to even stand on my own feet. Then one by one, came all the result and except for 3, I managed to get a call from all of the IIMs. Dedication? You say! That was March 2018 when I decided I should really start preparing now. The first mock test I took,  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:53:25.283Z"),
    "question" : "What was your height of dedication for CAT preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773af0c817f0398fc339c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-reason-behind-the-CAT-exam-syllabus?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:53:51.054Z"),
    "question" : "What is the reason behind the CAT exam syllabus? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773e90c817f0398fc3480"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-the-CAT-exam-in-15-days?-",
    "answer" : "The best way to prepare for CAT in 15 days is plan to take last 10 years CAT papers and don't worry about changing exam pattern. After taking first mock find out your score and see what went right and what went wrong and do the analysis of it. Let's take first Quant section, see which chapters sums you got wrong and if you see sums from chapters permutation and combination, Probability, inequality, modulus, graphs, co-ordinate geometry going regularly wrong chuck these chapters because chances of getting sums from these chapters is below average. Now find out from which others chapters you are majorly getting sums wrong and see whether you are conceptually weak in it or you are not able to interpret the sums or you are not able to develop an approach to do a sums or under pressure you perfo Continue Reading The best way to prepare for CAT in 15 days is plan to take last 10 years CAT papers and don't worry about changing exam pattern. After taking first mock find out your score and see what went right and what went wrong and do the analysis of it. Let's take first Quant section, see which chapters sums you got wrong and if you see sums from chapters permutation and combination, Probability, inequality, modulus, graphs, co-ordinate geometry going regularly wrong chuck these chapters because chances of getting sums from these chapters is below average. Now find out from which others chapters you are majorly getting sums wrong and see whether you are conceptually weak in it or you are not able to interpret the sums or you are not able to develop an approach to do a sums or under pressure you perfo Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:54:49.623Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for the CAT exam in 15 days? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603774110c817f0398fc3550"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-MBA-through-CAT-exam-help-me-to-move-abroad?-",
    "answer" : "Abhijit Mukherjee Haneesha Honey Hunter Vasu",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:55:29.711Z"),
    "question" : "Can MBA through CAT exam help me to move abroad? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037742a0c817f0398fc3617"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-CAT-exam-and-how-can-I-clear-it?-",
    "answer" : "Hi You have approx 9 months for this CAT 2016. Let us see the things that you can do by spending approx 180 minutes everyday and with 24 hours per week of study. 1. Read a newspaper online daily. It can done in your spare time. It could be The Hindu or Firstpost. You can also read selective articles from NYTime or Washington Post. Also start Word Power Made Easy by Norman Lewis. 2. Start watching lectures online. The website of EduSaathi can help you in that. Watch videos of all topics sequentially and solve questions. This will help you to get your basics correct. Continue the above two steps for 2 months. For self study, you can also go for the following books, For Quant, you can go for either Arun Sharma or Nishith Sinha or Quantum CAT by Sarvesh Verma. For LRDI, you can go for Arun Sharma or Continue Reading Hi You have approx 9 months for this CAT 2016. Let us see the things that you can do by spending approx 180 minutes everyday and with 24 hours per week of study. 1. Read a newspaper online daily. It can done in your spare time. It could be The Hindu or Firstpost. You can also read selective articles from NYTime or Washington Post. Also start Word Power Made Easy by Norman Lewis. 2. Start watching lectures online. The website of EduSaathi can help you in that. Watch videos of all topics sequentially and solve questions. This will help you to get your basics correct. Continue the above two steps for 2 months. For self study, you can also go for the following books, For Quant, you can go for either Arun Sharma or Nishith Sinha or Quantum CAT by Sarvesh Verma. For LRDI, you can go for Arun Sharma or Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:55:54.194Z"),
    "question" : "What is CAT exam and how can I clear it? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037743d0c817f0398fc362d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-sectional-cut-off-for-each-section-in-CAT-Exam?-",
    "answer" : "Srinivas Arks  It varies from institute to institute. Different colleges keep different sectional and overall cutoffs. For instance IIMA has kept sectional at 70 and overall at 80 for general category admissions for 2017–19 batch. You can also check for other colleges by going through their admission criteria. http://www.iima.ac.in/users/admission/files/Admission%20Procedure_2017_2019_Aug01.pdf",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:56:13.401Z"),
    "question" : "What is the sectional cut off for each section in CAT Exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603774540c817f0398fc3643"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Has-anyone-cleared-the-CAT-exams-only-by-studying-books-of-Arun-Sharma?-",
    "answer" : "It is possible. You need to understand the concepts  and if you do, then there are adequate number of questions for practice. If you are able to understand by yourself, then there is no need of coaching and you can score good percentile enough for calls from top institutes. PS: I got 99.2 percentile with self study only but I had used Bulls Eye's material.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:56:36.362Z"),
    "question" : "Has anyone cleared the CAT exams only by studying books of Arun Sharma? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037746a0c817f0398fc3708"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-there-any-age-limitation-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Sambit Halder 4",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:56:58.546Z"),
    "question" : "Is there any age limitation for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603774830c817f0398fc371f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-free-online-tutorials-to-crack-the-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "Amitendra Kumar, Product Head - LST and After XII@Career LauncherAnswered 5 years ago · Author has 165 answers and 215.6K answer viewsWhat are the best free online tutorials to crack the CAT exams? Amitendra Kumar While deciding about an exam like CAT to get access to your dream B-Scool, you must look for quality of content. Not everything free will offer a world class experience and reliability. More over, it is not neccessary that you may get the doubts cleared in such platforms. CL mocks are closest to CAT and is geared up to the new pattern. CL offers Smart CAT Cracker-a comprehensive online module with video lessons and customised to suit your requirements.  It has 240 hours of video lessons to help prepare for CAT. You may select the variant of the program as per your need. You can chose only video lesson module or the complete package with Test Series and Topic Tests. Visit website and check for Smart CAT Cracker under MBA tab.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:57:23.083Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best free online tutorials to crack the CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603774ab0c817f0398fc37fb"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-exams-which-can-be-written-easily-if-we-prepare-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "With CAT being one of the toughest exams with Quantitative ability, Reasoning and Verbal ability you can write many exams of many kinds easily just preparing for CAT . Some examples related to different fields are Bank Exams : IBPS, SBI PO & CLERKS RBI grade b officer Staff selection commission only GK is the extra thing for these If you are a engineering student and aspiring for software job : Exams like AMCAT, ELITMUS and COCUBES will be easier for you And all the written tests conducted in campus placement like TCS , INFOSYS, TECH MAHINDRA etc.... You will feel very comfortable attempting these exams if you prepare well for CAT. It may also mostly help you if you want to prepare for GRE or GMAT",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:58:03.254Z"),
    "question" : "What are the exams which can be written easily if we prepare for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603774c10c817f0398fc380f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-quantitative-book-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Rahul Anand 11",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:58:25.122Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best quantitative book for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603774d70c817f0398fc3825"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-use-of-writing-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is a CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:58:47.118Z"),
    "question" : "What is the use of writing the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603774f10c817f0398fc38ef"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-get-over-my-nervousness-before-giving-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How do I get over my nervousness before giving CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:59:13.515Z"),
    "question" : "How do I get over my nervousness before giving CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603775070c817f0398fc38ff"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Has-anyone-cracked-the-CAT-exam-by-online-course-of-Cracku?-",
    "answer" : "Disclaimer: I am one of the co-founders of Cracku. Cracku offers the best online coaching for CAT. The content is prepared by IIM alumni who have taken CAT multiple times and know how to ace the exam. We receive testimonials on a regular basis that our videos were truly beneficial and that our CAT mocks were the closest to actual CAT. Following are some of the testimonials received from our students. Sai Teja- 100.0%le (CAT 2020): “My initial preparation was solely based on taking mocks. Not preparing in a structured manner meant that there were glaring gaps in my understanding of a few concepts. So, I signed up for the Crash Course. The concise concept videos helped me fill these gaps in a short period of time. I also benefitted a lot from sectional tests which allowed me to try out different test-taking strategies. I appreciate the effort put in by your extremely self-driven and passionate team.” Parag Agrawal- 99.84%le (CAT 2020): “Cracku's revision videos were a godsend during the last days of my preparation. They helped me plug the holes in my knowledge and gave me a great overview of the sections as a whole.” Shivam Gupta- 99.68%le (CAT 2020): “I Joined Cracku in June 2020. I was very impressed by the quality of content they provided. Daily targets, study room, easy portal and mocks, all are very good. I took video lessons, the effort given to clarify questions by Sayali ma'am was very helpful. Never got doubts while even watching pre-recorded sessions. Video solutions to questions are there, live youtube sessions with Maruti sir always a plus.” Arvind Malav- 99.82%le (CAT 2020): “Cracku was my one and only source of preparation. I didn't waste any time elsewhere looking for multiple videos on the same topics or books for the same. I also didn't go on a crusade to collect all possible test series by all possible sources. Cracku fulfilled all my requirements at one place in terms of material, mocks and previous year papers. Cracku's daily targets and daily tasks helped me be consistent. I religiously did all daily targets and mocks. My daily study time was very rarely above 3 hrs but the consistency in my preparation which Cracku provided me made a difference of day and night for me. Lastly, the doubts were also proactively answered by cracku guys within a few days. One may at times differ to their provided answers but they never shied away from constructive discussion on the same. A very big heartily Thank you from my end to the whole team of Cracku for their tireless efforts throughout the whole year.” Supriya Murdia- 99.59%le (CAT 2020): “Best practice questions. Some of them were exactly what came in the actual paper, for example, the parallelogram question on coordinate systems.” Ajay- 99.6%le (CAT 2020): “The best thing about Cracku is their daily test which gives you an idea about your preparation level and the loopholes or weak areas in your preparation. Their study room is the most organized questions bank you will ever see! The number of questions, their contents and difficulty is in sync with the cat preparation. Cracku's app has been very handy and easy to use throughout the year so I would say cracku is enough for all your needs!” Mayank Bhartia- 99.91%le (CAT 2020): “Cracku has been of great help to me during my CAT's prep. They have brilliantly designed their mock tests and section tests. You won't get such good resources at such reasonable prices anywhere else. Kudos!” And many more... Please check out our website cracku.in for more such success stories. You can also check out this answer by one of our students. CAT 2021 aspirants, do check out the following free resources that will help you understand our pedagogy better: • Three FREE CAT mocks: This is taken by thousands of students and is a good way to gauge your areas of strength as well as assess your performance against others. • One test on each topic (VARC, DILR, Quant) every day, which we call the CAT Daily Target. • We also give the formula PDFs for all Quant topics for CAT. • Around 25 solved previous papers of CAT. • CAT Percentile Predictor.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:59:35.690Z"),
    "question" : "Has anyone cracked the CAT exam by online course of Cracku? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603775250c817f0398fc39cd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Where-can-I-find-a-study-partner-for-the-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:00:05.057Z"),
    "question" : "Where can I find a study partner for the CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603775530c817f0398fc3aa5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-be-my-daily-routine-while-preparing-for-cat-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:00:51.943Z"),
    "question" : "What should be my daily routine while preparing for cat exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037758e0c817f0398fc3ae2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-I-study-first-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "To answer this question, one has to dig deep and find out where he/she is at this moment of time. If you are a beginner and have no real experience of mocks and CAT, then I would suggest first to start with the basics. One can do that through following means :- CAT Books - You can probably start with books on Quants, DI & LR and VA/RC. Arun Sharma is a good one. There are others as well.CAT Prep Materials - You can join or take materials from any of the good coaching institutes that are available. Time, CL and IMS materials are all good for this.Online Materials - You can start going through notes from Handa ka Funda or Total Gadha and they can help improve your basics.Once you are done with all the basics and confident about your approach about problem solving, then you can move ahead with giving Mocks, which are the most important part of one's CAT preparations. One says that the best way to Bell the CAT is to Mock - Analyse - Repeat. TIME AIMCATs will be the best due to better normalization of scores and good students appearing in it. IMS Simcats are also good for prep. Happy preparing :) Best of luck…",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:01:50.883Z"),
    "question" : "What should I study first for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603775aa0c817f0398fc3ba8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-will-happen-if-I-failed-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "There are few more allied questions in this regard . 1. What should a student NOT DO to get into IIM?2. Why people fail to get into IIMs despite working hard?3. Does a student need to leave everything (almost everything including his job, social life etc.) in order to prepare for CAT? Well, let’s begin with the last question. The answer to that one is a definitive no. Students do not need to leave everything in order to crack CAT. What you need to do instead is make sure you prepare in a systematic manner and ensure you tick all the boxes required for preparing well. A balanced preparation is required. In case you are a working professional, and are struggling to find time, then probably you need to ask yourself how desperately you wish to crack CAT and can you make some sacrifices for it. Continue Reading There are few more allied questions in this regard . 1. What should a student NOT DO to get into IIM?2. Why people fail to get into IIMs despite working hard?3. Does a student need to leave everything (almost everything including his job, social life etc.) in order to prepare for CAT? Well, let’s begin with the last question. The answer to that one is a definitive no. Students do not need to leave everything in order to crack CAT. What you need to do instead is make sure you prepare in a systematic manner and ensure you tick all the boxes required for preparing well. A balanced preparation is required. In case you are a working professional, and are struggling to find time, then probably you need to ask yourself how desperately you wish to crack CAT and can you make some sacrifices for it. Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:02:18.705Z"),
    "question" : "What will happen if I failed the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603775be0c817f0398fc3bbc"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-does-one-have-to-sacrifice-to-crack-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:02:38.919Z"),
    "question" : "What does one have to sacrifice to crack the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603775d90c817f0398fc3c8b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-get-a-good-percentile-in-the-CAT-exam-within-a-month-of-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "First and foremost the statement, ‘good percentile' is too mainstream. You need to specific in your target. Secondly, I am not an optimist neither a pessimist, but a rationalist, so my answer might not be soothing to your eyes to read. A person who is aiming for any old IIM or FMS, for him/her, a good percentile is 98+2. A person who is aiming for new IIMs and IITs, 96+ percentile is a good catch 3. A person who is aiming for a college amongst top 40 , 90+ is good catch. 1 and 2 are abstruse to achieve in one month, not possible but it all depends upon our skill level prior to the preparation. 3 is possible with one month preparation. In the year 2017, I have managed to get an 85+ percentile with three weeks of preparation which is the key reason to my confidence for this year's preparation. I Continue Reading First and foremost the statement, ‘good percentile' is too mainstream. You need to specific in your target. Secondly, I am not an optimist neither a pessimist, but a rationalist, so my answer might not be soothing to your eyes to read. A person who is aiming for any old IIM or FMS, for him/her, a good percentile is 98+2. A person who is aiming for new IIMs and IITs, 96+ percentile is a good catch 3. A person who is aiming for a college amongst top 40 , 90+ is good catch. 1 and 2 are abstruse to achieve in one month, not possible but it all depends upon our skill level prior to the preparation. 3 is possible with one month preparation. In the year 2017, I have managed to get an 85+ percentile with three weeks of preparation which is the key reason to my confidence for this year's preparation. I Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:03:05.269Z"),
    "question" : "Can I get a good percentile in the CAT exam within a month of preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603775ed0c817f0398fc3c9d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-a-17-year-old-take-up-CAT-exam-for-IIM?-",
    "answer" : "Through this question I assume you to be passionate to enter into IIM at an early age. Beware of the fact that PGP is a post graduate program and you surely need to qualify graduation to enter into these institutes. As a previous answer cites a person, who has done is 10th, 12th, and graduation before attaining the age of 17 are rare to be found. if you are such a guy, then I would give you a thumbs up. If not, don't worry my friend, as you have another option I think only a few of them are aware. IIM - INDORE has an integrated program in management studies that provide an opportunity for students t enter into IIM Indore at a young age i.e., after completion of 12th.For details please through the following link http://www.iimidr.ac.in/academic-programmes/five-year-integrated-programme-in-m Continue Reading Through this question I assume you to be passionate to enter into IIM at an early age. Beware of the fact that PGP is a post graduate program and you surely need to qualify graduation to enter into these institutes. As a previous answer cites a person, who has done is 10th, 12th, and graduation before attaining the age of 17 are rare to be found. if you are such a guy, then I would give you a thumbs up. If not, don't worry my friend, as you have another option I think only a few of them are aware. IIM - INDORE has an integrated program in management studies that provide an opportunity for students t enter into IIM Indore at a young age i.e., after completion of 12th.For details please through the following link http://www.iimidr.ac.in/academic-programmes/five-year-integrated-programme-in-m Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:03:25.305Z"),
    "question" : "Can a 17 year old take up CAT exam for IIM? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603776010c817f0398fc3cb1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-the-CAT-exam-really-tough-for-an-arts-student?-",
    "answer" : "No. It is not. But one thing needs to be taken care of here. You try to cope up with the subject that takes most of the time to prepare in the same time span engineers prepare for the same. Engineers who have already prepared for Quantitative Aptitude and have a good hand in mathematics. So, please do start preparation at least 1 year before the exam to get a good grip over that subject. Also, do not go for the online coachings with more than 1000 students in a batch. You won't be able to cope up there. Do try for a coaching or mentor who has a small batch to give extra attention to you. You would already be losing the money you spent this year if you don't pass. We have been providing help to arts background students for 2 years now. If you want any specific help regarding CAT prep, feel fre Continue Reading No. It is not. But one thing needs to be taken care of here. You try to cope up with the subject that takes most of the time to prepare in the same time span engineers prepare for the same. Engineers who have already prepared for Quantitative Aptitude and have a good hand in mathematics. So, please do start preparation at least 1 year before the exam to get a good grip over that subject. Also, do not go for the online coachings with more than 1000 students in a batch. You won't be able to cope up there. Do try for a coaching or mentor who has a small batch to give extra attention to you. You would already be losing the money you spent this year if you don't pass. We have been providing help to arts background students for 2 years now. If you want any specific help regarding CAT prep, feel fre Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:03:45.382Z"),
    "question" : "Is the CAT exam really tough for an arts student? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037762b0c817f0398fc3d86"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-start-preparing-for-the-CAT-exam-for-IIMB?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How do I prepare myself for CAT?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:04:27.395Z"),
    "question" : "How should I start preparing for the CAT exam for IIMB? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037763f0c817f0398fc3d9c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-is-the-registration-date-for-CAT-exam-2018?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Rohit Chavan Quora User",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:04:47.820Z"),
    "question" : "When is the registration date for CAT exam 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603776620c817f0398fc3e6d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-happen-if-two-candidate-have-same-score-in-cat-exam?-",
    "answer" : "In short, if two or more students get the same score (overall or in a particular section), they get the same percentile (overall or the sectional as the case may be).  Percentile is just the rank portrayed in a different manner. So if two students have the same score, they would get the same percentile. There are some exams which rank students differently even with the same overall score – based on their scores in each section. The same thing happens in almost all Engineering CETs to prepare the merit list. For students with the same set of scores, there is a clear tie breaker rule. However, CAT does not discriminate between the sections (After computing the scaled scores). Among MBA exams CMAT is an exam which clearly has guidelines to break a tie in case of same overall scores.  Thanks for Continue Reading In short, if two or more students get the same score (overall or in a particular section), they get the same percentile (overall or the sectional as the case may be).  Percentile is just the rank portrayed in a different manner. So if two students have the same score, they would get the same percentile. There are some exams which rank students differently even with the same overall score – based on their scores in each section. The same thing happens in almost all Engineering CETs to prepare the merit list. For students with the same set of scores, there is a clear tie breaker rule. However, CAT does not discriminate between the sections (After computing the scaled scores). Among MBA exams CMAT is an exam which clearly has guidelines to break a tie in case of same overall scores.  Thanks for Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:05:22.792Z"),
    "question" : "What happen if two candidate have same score in cat exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603776760c817f0398fc3e81"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-aptitude-chapters-more-important-for-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:05:42.302Z"),
    "question" : "Which aptitude chapters more important for CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037768d0c817f0398fc3f47"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-CAT-exam-for-MBA-conducted-online-or-offline?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Tajinder Mehta 5",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:06:05.430Z"),
    "question" : "Is CAT exam for MBA conducted online or offline? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603776a10c817f0398fc3f59"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Should-I-give-the-CAT-exam-being-a-third-year-engineering-student?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:06:25.950Z"),
    "question" : "Should I give the CAT exam being a third year engineering student? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603776bb0c817f0398fc3f79"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-should-we-take-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Deepak Saini  TOMORROW IS TOO LATE, YESTERDAY IS OVER AND NOW IS EXACTLY THE RIGHT MOMENT SO START CAT Preparation may take 10–12 months for a person with average past academic record, 6–8 months for a person with above average past academic record and 3–4 months for a person with excellent past academic record. As CAT is usuallyheld in end of November/December, so December 2017 or January 2018 is the best time to start your preparation. HOPE YOU GOT YOUR ANSWER",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:06:51.510Z"),
    "question" : "When should we take the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603776e80c817f0398fc4049"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-AIMCAT-differentiated-from-CAT-Exam?-",
    "answer" : "Thanks for A2A, Actually they are not. CAT as I have said quite a few times is very unpredictable. 180 can be 99.4 to 99.8, there is enough variation in marks vs percentile. AIMCATs or any other mocks series aims tries to build mocks of different difficulty so you are ready for the real CAT. Some mocks are easier than CAT some mocks are difficult. If you talk about percentiles obviously you will get a better percentile in CAT if you perform in a similar fasion as in mocks. This is because of the fact that mocks are usually taken by serious test takers and on the D-day there are far many test takers which takes your percentiles up. When I gave AIMCATs and I attempted almost each and every of them, I saw 99th percentile vary from 140 marks to 190 marks. So you see the mocks ready you for the un Continue Reading Thanks for A2A, Actually they are not. CAT as I have said quite a few times is very unpredictable. 180 can be 99.4 to 99.8, there is enough variation in marks vs percentile. AIMCATs or any other mocks series aims tries to build mocks of different difficulty so you are ready for the real CAT. Some mocks are easier than CAT some mocks are difficult. If you talk about percentiles obviously you will get a better percentile in CAT if you perform in a similar fasion as in mocks. This is because of the fact that mocks are usually taken by serious test takers and on the D-day there are far many test takers which takes your percentiles up. When I gave AIMCATs and I attempted almost each and every of them, I saw 99th percentile vary from 140 marks to 190 marks. So you see the mocks ready you for the un Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:07:36.290Z"),
    "question" : "How is AIMCAT differentiated from CAT Exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603777280c817f0398fc413c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-a-student-with-average-mathematical-skills-crack-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How can a student with average mathematical skills crack the CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:08:40.459Z"),
    "question" : "How can a student with average mathematical skills crack the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603777520c817f0398fc4213"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Has-anyone-tried-using-CTRL+F-on-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "I tried and Exam ended abruptly there only . I had to loose a year for next CAT exam. Humble request its not your TIME aimcat, or IMS SIMCAT where your control F other shortcuts workout. PLS dont try this a humble request to all serious Aspirant. Aakash Jain",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:09:22.290Z"),
    "question" : "Has anyone tried using CTRL+F on the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037777d0c817f0398fc42eb"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-chapters-should-I-start-preparing-in-the-quant-section-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Sarthak Dash Thanks for A2A. For QA section, the chapter that you should start with depends a lot on your area of interest. In most of the coaching institutes, the course starts with Number System. But I would advise you to start with Arithmetic first. Arithmetic - Geometry - Number System - Algebra - Modern Maths Your preparation involves 3 phases on a mental level: Interest -> Excitement -> Confidence If you start with your area of interest, then you will have that will power to sit and read regularly. And once the momentum sets in, you will start enjoying the problem-solving part. This is very important because when you enjoy the process instead of taking too much stress, then your confidence automatically goes up. So, prepare well and practice a lot! For a detailed strategy, you can read this post. CAT -  Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:10:05.289Z"),
    "question" : "Which chapters should I start preparing in the quant section for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603777940c817f0398fc4300"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-engineers-tackle-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "Engineers are generally good at quant, but not me. So they can score good marks in quant section. They concentrate more on verbal and IR. And what do you mean by engineer? A student who is working or studiying? I attempted CAT in both phases. So I will share my experiences in both these phases. My First attempt at CAT is in my final year of engineering. I prepared by taking classes at TIME. The classes were thrice weekly. So I attended them and on other days I practised the material given by institute. It was hectic in the beginning but I got used to it.But somehow my preparation was not enough and didn't score well. The second and third attempts were given while I was working. These both times I was on my own. So I dedicated a daily quota of 2 to 3 hrs to prepare for CAT. Second time I atten Continue Reading Engineers are generally good at quant, but not me. So they can score good marks in quant section. They concentrate more on verbal and IR. And what do you mean by engineer? A student who is working or studiying? I attempted CAT in both phases. So I will share my experiences in both these phases. My First attempt at CAT is in my final year of engineering. I prepared by taking classes at TIME. The classes were thrice weekly. So I attended them and on other days I practised the material given by institute. It was hectic in the beginning but I got used to it.But somehow my preparation was not enough and didn't score well. The second and third attempts were given while I was working. These both times I was on my own. So I dedicated a daily quota of 2 to 3 hrs to prepare for CAT. Second time I atten Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:10:28.161Z"),
    "question" : "How do engineers tackle CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603777a60c817f0398fc4313"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-students-appeared-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:10:46.353Z"),
    "question" : "How many students appeared for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603777bd0c817f0398fc43dc"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-necessary-to-have-job-experience-to-appear-for-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is it necessary to have job experience to appear for CAT?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:11:09.724Z"),
    "question" : "Is it necessary to have job experience to appear for CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603777d60c817f0398fc43ef"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-CAT-exam-in-a-short-time?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:11:34.396Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for CAT exam in a short time? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603778070c817f0398fc44cf"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/If-my-score-in-CAT-exam-is-between-93-96-percentile-then-will-I-get-any-decent-college?-",
    "answer" : "Sanjana Srinivas At the end of the day, your profile plays a significant role in deciding what colleges you get a call from. I have a friend with a 99.5 percentile who did not secure a call from IIM A or C (Gen Male with average acads), while another friend with a 95.4 secured a call from IIM C (Gen female, OBC-NC with good acads). So with the percentile range you have mentioned, if you're a general category student(male and engineer at that), IIM calls can be difficult. However, there are other decent B-schools with lower cutoffs and with lesser weightage to profile/acads. You can find their eligibility criteria and such on Google.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:12:23.158Z"),
    "question" : "If my score in CAT exam is between 93-96 percentile then will I get any decent college? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603778200c817f0398fc44ee"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Does-the-CAT-exam-have-general-knowledge-questions?-",
    "answer" : "Usually most competitive examinations of this stature dedicate a section to GK questions, and the students just go nuts updating their knowledge. However, CAT spares you in a big way as it does not involve general knowledge questions, so, you do not have to mug up answers staying up all night. You will be tested on Verbal & Reading Comprehension, Data Interpretation & Logical Reasoning, along with Quantitative Aptitude. However, just because you won't need to answer any GK questions that does not mean you would not bother about staying updated about what's going on around you. Because, during personal interviews and for group discussion round you would need the knowledge.  Continue Reading Usually most competitive examinations of this stature dedicate a section to GK questions, and the students just go nuts updating their knowledge. However, CAT spares you in a big way as it does not involve general knowledge questions, so, you do not have to mug up answers staying up all night. You will be tested on Verbal & Reading Comprehension, Data Interpretation & Logical Reasoning, along with Quantitative Aptitude. However, just because you won't need to answer any GK questions that does not mean you would not bother about staying updated about what's going on around you. Because, during personal interviews and for group discussion round you would need the knowledge.  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:12:48.481Z"),
    "question" : "Does the CAT exam have general knowledge questions? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037783b0c817f0398fc45b7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-start-my-preprations-for-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Can I start my preprations for CAT exams?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:13:15.027Z"),
    "question" : "Can I start my preprations for CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603778590c817f0398fc45d5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-happens-if-you-leave-the-CAT-exam-blank?-",
    "answer" : "Rohit Thomas Koshy  N. Sathyanarayan",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:13:45.964Z"),
    "question" : "What happens if you leave the CAT exam blank? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603778a30c817f0398fc4776"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/At-51-percentile-in-CAT-exam-which-college-will-be-the-best-for-doing-MBA?-",
    "answer" : "Soumyadeep Banerjee  Hi there...Sorry for being brutal n honest..51%ile means your absolute score will be near to zero...So I will personally suggest you to reconsider your decision to pursue the Mba course specially with this score...   Just a free advice... what you do with this advice will depend on you only... P.S. let me know if you want to work on improvement aspects :)",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:14:59.412Z"),
    "question" : "At 51 percentile in CAT exam which college will be the best for doing MBA? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603778b60c817f0398fc478e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-good-is-career-launcher-for-CAT-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "For CAT there are three premier institutes namely Career Launcher, TIMES, and ACE. In my 6th semester I join TIME coaching as 70% of CAT aspirants in my college went to TIMES, but in TIMES the batch size is of 60+ also there are only few premier batches which have good faculty. It’s very difficult to talk to the faculty for any doubts after the classes as there are many centers and they have to take classes in other centers also. That year I scored 90.58 percentile. However one of my friends who have studied from career launcher suggested me to go there, so in my drop year I choose career launcher. My friend also gifted me a Gift Card of Career Launcher which he has brought from eLitmus platform using the points which he got for taking there test and also for getting placed through eLitmus  Continue Reading For CAT there are three premier institutes namely Career Launcher, TIMES, and ACE. In my 6th semester I join TIME coaching as 70% of CAT aspirants in my college went to TIMES, but in TIMES the batch size is of 60+ also there are only few premier batches which have good faculty. It’s very difficult to talk to the faculty for any doubts after the classes as there are many centers and they have to take classes in other centers also. That year I scored 90.58 percentile. However one of my friends who have studied from career launcher suggested me to go there, so in my drop year I choose career launcher. My friend also gifted me a Gift Card of Career Launcher which he has brought from eLitmus platform using the points which he got for taking there test and also for getting placed through eLitmus  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:15:18.915Z"),
    "question" : "How good is career launcher for CAT preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603778c90c817f0398fc47a1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-disadvantages-of-CAT-exam-conducted-by-the-IIMs?-",
    "answer" : "Krishna Bharadwaj",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:15:37.191Z"),
    "question" : "What are the disadvantages of CAT-exam conducted by the IIMs? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603778df0c817f0398fc4864"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-score-90-percentile-in-CAT-with-4-months-preperation?-",
    "answer" : "Yes sufficient for percentile you are targetting. Also ,there are books, which helps you, largely mastering skills for CAT. However, there are times when we fail understanding few concepts or quickly learn few of them, as a beginner we might also not be aware of few tips and tricks. This is where online/offline courses help. If you were in search for an effective course that helps you with your self-preparation, I would recommend you to enroll in “Handa Ka Funda” online course. Few pointers which I will suggest you to prepare for CAT exams are as follows- Firstly ,Make a note of your weak areas in a excel sheet .Mark them as red.Work more on those red areas if required start from scratch .Start from basics ,give sectional mock test and analyse what went right and what went wrong . For that you  Continue Reading Yes sufficient for percentile you are targetting. Also ,there are books, which helps you, largely mastering skills for CAT. However, there are times when we fail understanding few concepts or quickly learn few of them, as a beginner we might also not be aware of few tips and tricks. This is where online/offline courses help. If you were in search for an effective course that helps you with your self-preparation, I would recommend you to enroll in “Handa Ka Funda” online course. Few pointers which I will suggest you to prepare for CAT exams are as follows- Firstly ,Make a note of your weak areas in a excel sheet .Mark them as red.Work more on those red areas if required start from scratch .Start from basics ,give sectional mock test and analyse what went right and what went wrong . For that you  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:15:59.610Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to score 90 percentile in CAT with 4 months preperation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037791d0c817f0398fc4953"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Do-engineers-have-any-drawback-in-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "N. Sathyanarayan, Academic head - iQue ideas (Entrance Test Preps)Answered 4 years ago · Author has 3K answers and 2.7M answer viewsDo engineers have any drawback in CAT exam? N. Sathyanarayan It’s something called diversity that is hitting GEMs. (General category, Engineers, Males) The IIMs have been inundated with a lot of GEMs and wish to have more diversity on campus. Hence, they are willing to admit students who do not belong to the afore mentioned category. It’s a sad fact that is hitting the deserving candidates. One would wish that there be a veil of ignorance in the selection process. The truth is, there isn’t one. So do General Category, Male Engineers have any drawbacks in the CAT exam. No. Do they have one in the selection process? YES - They were born in the wrong gender, in the wrong family and selected the wrong stream to graduate in.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:17:01.756Z"),
    "question" : "Do engineers have any drawback in CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603779350c817f0398fc4967"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-1-year-of-self-study-for-the-CAT-exam-enough?-",
    "answer" : "Shishir Vishwakarma",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:17:25.095Z"),
    "question" : "Is 1 year of self-study for the CAT exam enough? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603779520c817f0398fc4a35"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-prepare-for-CAT-to-secure-a-seat-in-the-IIMs?-",
    "answer" : "Not a question to be asked on Quora (I mean too broad), nevertheless I'll give it a try. First things first, the question should be \"How should I prepare for CAT/IIMs?\" and not \"How can I do IIM preparations?\". See, the problem here is that you are translating your Hindi thoughts into English rather than thinking in English, a practice which will result in better sentence formation. Now, as for the preparation tips (and I'll mention things apart from the regular quant and English practice), here it goes: Think in English (all the time), to the extent of imagining and day dreaming in EnglishRead newspapers daily, especially the editorials and the business section; try and learn at least 5 new words from the newspapers dailyRead one good book (novel or not) every fortnight. Pick up writers likContinue Reading Not a question to be asked on Quora (I mean too broad), nevertheless I'll give it a try. First things first, the question should be \"How should I prepare for CAT/IIMs?\" and not \"How can I do IIM preparations?\". See, the problem here is that you are translating your Hindi thoughts into English rather than thinking in English, a practice which will result in better sentence formation. Now, as for the preparation tips (and I'll mention things apart from the regular quant and English practice), here it goes: Think in English (all the time), to the extent of imagining and day dreaming in EnglishRead newspapers daily, especially the editorials and the business section; try and learn at least 5 new words from the newspapers dailyRead one good book (novel or not) every fortnight. Pick up writers likContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:17:54.198Z"),
    "question" : "How should I prepare for CAT to secure a seat in the IIMs? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603779660c817f0398fc4a4d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-is-the-CAT-exam-so-stupid?-",
    "answer" : "Chandan Mishra I have taken CAT twice and also got calls from IIM. I think I know what it takes to crack CAT and I will try to explain it .. Lets look at on what basis CAT tests us : -  1. Quantitative Aptitude - It tests your problem solving skills. Whether you are able to solve problems in appropriate time with the best method. It is different from mathematics where you have more formulas and calculations.2. Logical Reasoning - As the name suggests it tests our logic. Based on our logical ability we deduce the solution. Some questions will seriously turn your head upside down. Some will be based on more than one possibility.3. Data Interpretation - This tests our calculation and approximation skills. Nowdays DI section is filled with Logical DIs which require great brainstorming.4. Reading Compr Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:18:14.525Z"),
    "question" : "Why is the CAT exam so stupid? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037797e0c817f0398fc4a66"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Are-LORs-required-for-an-MBA-through-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "No, none of the colleges I know of, admitting to MBA programs through CAT in India, require Letters of Recommendations. However, there are a few foreign colleges that are now accepting CAT scores for admission to their MBA/MiM programs which may ask you for LORs. To confirm, you can check with the admissions department at the colleges you're willing to apply to.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:18:38.507Z"),
    "question" : "Are LORs required for an MBA through the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603779940c817f0398fc4b2e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-carry-some-little-chocolates-in-my-pocket-with-a-water-bottle-at-CAT-exam-centre?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Can I carry some little chocolates in my pocket with a water bottle at CAT exam centre?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:19:00.981Z"),
    "question" : "Can I carry some little chocolates in my pocket with a water bottle at CAT exam centre? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603779ab0c817f0398fc4b41"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-much-is-the-level-of-maths-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Subham Nayak 2",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:19:23.196Z"),
    "question" : "How much is the level of maths in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603779bf0c817f0398fc4b57"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-we-prepare-for-the-CAT-exams-at-home-without-any-coaching?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Can we prepare for the CAT exams at home without any coaching?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:19:43.590Z"),
    "question" : "Can we prepare for the CAT exams at home without any coaching? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603779d30c817f0398fc4c1d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Should-I-take-the-IAS-exam-or-CAT-exam-and-do-an-MBA-after-graduating?-",
    "answer" : "This is a question that you,my friend only can answer. It's about what u want and what u can give. MBA - More chances of getting selected since seats are more, chances of having more money(white), business minded people can go much ahead than they would in civil services. Prestige comes but ‘generally’ not instantly( unlike IAS ) but can supersede that of an IAS and much more. IAS is more about the service of the nation considering you are not amenable to the evil of corruption. If u have a bent of mind for social service,joining the civil services is one of the most popular ways to do it especially for middle class people like me(not that businessmen don't think about the service of the nation).From what I know it is maybe tougher than the CAT exam. So mainly it's about what your mind wants and can practically do.But once decided,give your all towards that direction. All the best! ☺ 10",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:20:03.322Z"),
    "question" : "Should I take the IAS exam or CAT exam and do an MBA after graduating? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603779e30c817f0398fc4c2c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-CAT-exam-books-should-I-take?-",
    "answer" : "For any mba based exam or especially CAT you should consider Arun Sharma's books. For QA: How to Prepare for Quantitive Aptitude for CAT For VA&RC:How to Prepare for the verbal ability and reading comprehension for the CAT I am not sure for LR and DI books but for other two sections Arun Sharma's these books are good enough to prepare for CAT.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:20:19.829Z"),
    "question" : "Which CAT exam books should I take? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603779f90c817f0398fc4c43"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-is-the-CAT-exam-every-year?-",
    "answer" : "Ginni Tyagi",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:20:41.560Z"),
    "question" : "When is the CAT exam every year? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377a140c817f0398fc4d0c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-a-back-student-be-eligible-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Dear all Back Student can also eligible for CAT exam. As per eligibility criteria general candidates must be graduate with minimum 50% marks and for SC/ST it is 45%. Candidate have to clear their exam at the time of admission. Check below the Eligibility criteria of CAT Bachelor’s degree - Bachelor’s degree in Engineering/Technology (4 years after 10+2/Post B.Sc./Post Diploma) or B.E/B. Tech equivalent examinations, of Professional Societies, recognized by MHRD/UPSC/AICTE (e.g. AMIE by Institution of Engineers-India, AMICE by the Institute of Civil Engineers India).Equivalent to Bachelor’s degree - Any Qualification recognized by Association of Indian Universities, New Delhi which is equivalent to a Bachelor’s Degree awarded by UGC recognized University/Institutions.Other - Cases not coveredContinue Reading Dear all Back Student can also eligible for CAT exam. As per eligibility criteria general candidates must be graduate with minimum 50% marks and for SC/ST it is 45%. Candidate have to clear their exam at the time of admission. Check below the Eligibility criteria of CAT Bachelor’s degree - Bachelor’s degree in Engineering/Technology (4 years after 10+2/Post B.Sc./Post Diploma) or B.E/B. Tech equivalent examinations, of Professional Societies, recognized by MHRD/UPSC/AICTE (e.g. AMIE by Institution of Engineers-India, AMICE by the Institute of Civil Engineers India).Equivalent to Bachelor’s degree - Any Qualification recognized by Association of Indian Universities, New Delhi which is equivalent to a Bachelor’s Degree awarded by UGC recognized University/Institutions.Other - Cases not coveredContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:21:08.171Z"),
    "question" : "Can a back student be eligible for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377a2b0c817f0398fc4d21"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-200-the-average-score-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Sreenjoy Mallick Having this mindset is why people sometimes do not perform well in CAT. As there is no set rule of what the average marks or the CAT cutoff I going to be. It completely depends on the toughness of the exam and how prepared the candidates are. Now let me talk facts to back my answer: CAT 2016 saw a major shift in the CAT exam. It saw a drastic increase in the level of difficulty of the LRDI section, such that a guy who got 14 answers right in LRDI in CAT 2016 scored around 98 percentile in the section as compared to getting around 20–22 questions correct to get the same percentile in CAT 2015. Thus, as we can see the average marks or the cutoff decreased in 2016 as compared to 2015. Now in CAT 2017, the level of difficulty of CAT overall was the same. The difficulty level of the LRDI section wa Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:21:31.865Z"),
    "question" : "Is 200 the average score in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377a540c817f0398fc4dfd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-I-study-2-days-before-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "This is what you should do two three days before exam . Revise important formulae and reattempt important questions Forget about the topics you have not touched so far. It is not the time to get into any new concepts now. Forget about how to improve your accuracy in one particular topic. Your focus should be overall improvement by staying in the flow of preparation and by staying positive and confident. You should focus on revising all the formulae. Either go through the notes that you have made throughout your preparation or go through the summary of topics given in study material/books that you have prepared from. In case you have marked some typical questions that you think are relevant and have important concepts then revise/reattempt them as well. Give 1 mock test and keep solving questi Continue Reading This is what you should do two three days before exam . Revise important formulae and reattempt important questions Forget about the topics you have not touched so far. It is not the time to get into any new concepts now. Forget about how to improve your accuracy in one particular topic. Your focus should be overall improvement by staying in the flow of preparation and by staying positive and confident. You should focus on revising all the formulae. Either go through the notes that you have made throughout your preparation or go through the summary of topics given in study material/books that you have prepared from. In case you have marked some typical questions that you think are relevant and have important concepts then revise/reattempt them as well. Give 1 mock test and keep solving questi Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:22:12.241Z"),
    "question" : "What should I study 2 days before CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377a9a0c817f0398fc4eef"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-we-change-CAT-examination-centre?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Rahul Chaurasia",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:23:22.310Z"),
    "question" : "Can we change CAT examination centre? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377aae0c817f0398fc4f05"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-hardest-section-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Vaishali Piplani  LR and Quant",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:23:42.953Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the hardest section in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377ac50c817f0398fc4fc9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-starting-salary-of-coaching-faculty-for-cat-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:24:05.254Z"),
    "question" : "What is the starting salary of coaching faculty for cat exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377adb0c817f0398fc4fdd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-prepare-for-the-CAT-with-100-days-to-go?-",
    "answer" : "Note: The below answer is not meant for those who have just started preparing for CAT and are looking for a plan to crack CAT in 100 days. It is that time of year when CAT is almost knocking at your door and you my friends are ready to put that “bell” of yours on it. So far you have done an amazing work; you have covered most of the topics, have taken a good number of mocks, some of you have attended lengthy classes; and most of you have managed your CAT preparation along with your office/college. Cheers to all your hard work!! Each minute that you have spent till now is going to count and you deserve a pat on your back for the effort so far. But, as the saying goes “It's not over till it's over”; these two-three months remaining to the CAT exam are going to have a good amount of say in your Continue Reading Note: The below answer is not meant for those who have just started preparing for CAT and are looking for a plan to crack CAT in 100 days. It is that time of year when CAT is almost knocking at your door and you my friends are ready to put that “bell” of yours on it. So far you have done an amazing work; you have covered most of the topics, have taken a good number of mocks, some of you have attended lengthy classes; and most of you have managed your CAT preparation along with your office/college. Cheers to all your hard work!! Each minute that you have spent till now is going to count and you deserve a pat on your back for the effort so far. But, as the saying goes “It's not over till it's over”; these two-three months remaining to the CAT exam are going to have a good amount of say in your Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:24:27.340Z"),
    "question" : "How should I prepare for the CAT with 100 days to go? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377af20c817f0398fc4ffa"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-someone-give-me-an-idea-about-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:24:50.559Z"),
    "question" : "Can someone give me an idea about CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377b140c817f0398fc50c7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-process-of-applying-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Saurebh Its through online registration ,the notification is generally out in the month of July. You will need a photocopy of signature,photograph. The application fee could be upto 2000 INR. You will have fill details of your 10,12,Graduation,Post-Graduation(if applicable). You will have the choice to select which IIMs you want to apply on the form . If you are starting with your CAT preparation , here are few of the pointer I will suggest you to kickstart your preparation Firstly take an diagnostic test for CAT(or solve past year paper) to know where you stand in terms of level of your Maths,English ,LR/DI . Its just like pre-board where you get to know your strong and weak areas and work upon them by the time before your main boards. You can maintain excel sheet and note down you strong and weak are Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:25:24.787Z"),
    "question" : "What is the process of applying for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377b500c817f0398fc51b1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-crack-the-CAT-exam-in-2-years-without-joining-classes?-",
    "answer" : "Thanks for A2A. Cracking CAT and joining coaching classes are two very different things. Their interdependence is entirely subjective on mental acumen, dedication, clarity of road map and familiarity with subjects. CAT can be cracked without coaching classes, in 2 months with above attributes on one hand. On the other hand even a whole lifetime with multiple coachings can not ensure a remarkable score. Coachings are nothing but an ensuing medium to guide preps on right track, building concepts, comparative analysis and continuous flow of mental dedication. “All in all a coaching is just a catalyst.” Now come to the point of the time luxury you possess. Two years are more than required to not only fetch a good score but also to master the subject matter. Pivotal is to use this time strategicall Continue Reading Thanks for A2A. Cracking CAT and joining coaching classes are two very different things. Their interdependence is entirely subjective on mental acumen, dedication, clarity of road map and familiarity with subjects. CAT can be cracked without coaching classes, in 2 months with above attributes on one hand. On the other hand even a whole lifetime with multiple coachings can not ensure a remarkable score. Coachings are nothing but an ensuing medium to guide preps on right track, building concepts, comparative analysis and continuous flow of mental dedication. “All in all a coaching is just a catalyst.” Now come to the point of the time luxury you possess. Two years are more than required to not only fetch a good score but also to master the subject matter. Pivotal is to use this time strategicall Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:26:24.883Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to crack the CAT exam in 2 years without joining classes? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377b6a0c817f0398fc51ce"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-long-would-it-take-to-prepare-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Normally if one sincerely devotes six months for preparation of CAT exam, it should be enough for an intelligent student.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:26:50.221Z"),
    "question" : "How long would it take to prepare for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377b7c0c817f0398fc528e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-writing-the-CAT-exam-really-beneficial?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is writing the CAT exam really beneficial?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:27:08.518Z"),
    "question" : "Is writing the CAT exam really beneficial? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377ba20c817f0398fc52b5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-you-prepare-for-the-CAT-exam-from-the-11th-class?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Can you prepare for the CAT exam from the 11th class?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:27:46.327Z"),
    "question" : "Can you prepare for the CAT exam from the 11th class? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377bb80c817f0398fc537a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-crack-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How should I prepare for the CAT?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:28:08.126Z"),
    "question" : "How should I prepare for the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377bf40c817f0398fc5460"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-books-to-crack-the-CAT-2019?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are the best books to crack the CAT 2019?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:29:08.221Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best books to crack the CAT 2019? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377c1d0c817f0398fc548a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-institutes-that-accept-CAT-scores-should-I-apply-to-before-taking-CAT-exam-in-Dec-2016?-",
    "answer" : "There are many institutes which accept CAT score. Applying for colleges depends on two things- How you are doing in your mocks?How much are you expecting in CAT 2016?Most of the private colleges close their application before the CAT exam date. Following are a few colleges you can apply for- To be applied before CAT i.e 4 Dec 2016- Colleges - Expected cut off ( Gen) FMS - 98. 5+MDI - 96+S P JAIN - 85+XIMB - 92+ *(10 Dec is the last date)IMT - 90+These are a few top colleges. All other colleges like IIT’s, DFS, JBIMS etc you can apply after CAT. Anuj Goyal",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:29:49.892Z"),
    "question" : "What institutes that accept CAT scores should I apply to before taking CAT exam in Dec 2016? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377c300c817f0398fc554a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-institute-for-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "The best institute that would prepare you for CAT and other B School entrance examinations is, without a single doubt, KITABEE, Jhandewalan, New Delhi. Having outperformed myself in the exams I took in 2017, I would like to justify this as per below: First and foremost reason to join Kitabee is the amazing faculty (Neeraj Sir and Prateek Sir). They will punish you, motivate you, clear all your doubts and most importantly devise a tailor made strategy for you to ace the exams. The shortcuts and easy, effective question solving techniques taught to me by Neeraj Sir were something that helped me solve most difficult questions with ease. It would be a gross injustice if I don’t mention that Neeraj Sir is undoubtedly the best Quant trainer in Delhi. The small batch size(15–20) and constant intera Continue Reading The best institute that would prepare you for CAT and other B School entrance examinations is, without a single doubt, KITABEE, Jhandewalan, New Delhi. Having outperformed myself in the exams I took in 2017, I would like to justify this as per below: First and foremost reason to join Kitabee is the amazing faculty (Neeraj Sir and Prateek Sir). They will punish you, motivate you, clear all your doubts and most importantly devise a tailor made strategy for you to ace the exams. The shortcuts and easy, effective question solving techniques taught to me by Neeraj Sir were something that helped me solve most difficult questions with ease. It would be a gross injustice if I don’t mention that Neeraj Sir is undoubtedly the best Quant trainer in Delhi. The small batch size(15–20) and constant intera Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:30:08.025Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best institute for the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377c420c817f0398fc5559"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-learn-better-English-in-a-short-period-of-time-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Shilpa Guleria, BTech Computer Science, Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha UniversityAnswered 3 years agoHow can I learn better English in a short period of time for the CAT exam? Shilpa Guleria Learning English is a very practical process.One just don't need to sit and mug up the rules and stuff like that. It comes from within..once you start to use it on a regular basis.Use English in your daily routine, read English newspapers, magazines,articles on the Internet,watch English Videos, documentaries..and moreover try speaking up English regularly. When you do such activities, you tend to learn more of the new things on a large scale.Gradually things will become easier for you. But, for the CAT preparation, besides these activities you could try solving out their comprehensions and study a bit for the vocab part. Hope the answer was beneficial. :)",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:30:26.893Z"),
    "question" : "How can I learn better English in a short period of time for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377c580c817f0398fc5576"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-Abhishek-TR-crack-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "AnonymousAnswered 4 years agoCan an average student crack CAT? Let me introduce myself. I consider myself an average student. I went to IIT (just got in, to be precise). I took CAT 4 times. I managed 99+ twice in CAT, without any coaching. My lowest sectional score was 75 percentile. With some efforts, I managed well above 99 percentile in that section in my last attempt. I have had interview calls from all IIMs except Bangalore. (No, I did not go to IIM for an MBA).  Answer in short : Yes. You can.  But, Work hard Long Answer: Firstly, I presume you want to get admission in an IIM. For that, clearing CAT will not suffice. Believe me, I got rejected in half a dozen interviews and I know 100 percentilers rejected by IIM.  Clearing CAT: As you would know, there are three sections in CAT exam. Prepare for all of them.  The Quant section was easy last time. T Continue Reading Let me introduce myself. I consider myself an average student. I went to IIT (just got in, to be precise). I took CAT 4 times. I managed 99+ twice in CAT, without any coaching. My lowest sectional score was 75 percentile. With some efforts, I managed well above 99 percentile in that section in my last attempt. I have had interview calls from all IIMs except Bangalore. (No, I did not go to IIM for an MBA).  Answer in short : Yes. You can.  But, Work hard Long Answer: Firstly, I presume you want to get admission in an IIM. For that, clearing CAT will not suffice. Believe me, I got rejected in half a dozen interviews and I know 100 percentilers rejected by IIM.  Clearing CAT: As you would know, there are three sections in CAT exam. Prepare for all of them.  The Quant section was easy last time. T Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:30:48.837Z"),
    "question" : "How did Abhishek TR crack the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377c810c817f0398fc5648"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-site-can-be-useful-for-learning-English-grammar-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which site can be useful for learning English grammar for the CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:31:29.062Z"),
    "question" : "Which site can be useful for learning English grammar for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377c960c817f0398fc5662"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-breakfast-is-recommended-before-my-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the difference between the CAT and GMAT syllabus?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:31:50.360Z"),
    "question" : "What breakfast is recommended before my CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377cb90c817f0398fc572b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-happens-if-a-question-is-unattended-in-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Asmita Ase Tfda",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:32:25.648Z"),
    "question" : "What happens if a question is unattended in the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377ccc0c817f0398fc5745"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-a-third-year-student-take-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "A student in Final year of graduation can take the CAT Exam . That means for 3 year graduation programs , third year happens to be the final year therefore YES. For four year degree programs , 3rd year happens to be the Pre Final year , in that case NO. Dhruvesh Shah",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:32:44.731Z"),
    "question" : "Can a third-year student take the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377cf90c817f0398fc581a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-necessary-to-study-math-for-acing-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is it necessary to study math for acing the CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:33:29.212Z"),
    "question" : "Is it necessary to study math for acing the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d0b0c817f0398fc5830"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-does-anyone-prepare-for-the-CAT-exam-for-English?-",
    "answer" : "Hello readers! Focus on building contextual understanding of the English language. All questions in CAT English are based on comprehension and logic - be it VRC or Verbal Reasoning. Learn to note word meaning and write down central idea of paragraphs as you read articles. Practice reading on different genres - philosophy, psychology, art etc. etc. Study relevant to the exam pattern. Sharing some sample links which will give you idea on how to plan and read. Go through these links, you will get a fair idea! How to improve accuracy in CAT Verbal Reading Comprehension? RC A Day - Bfactory | Blog How to improve your reading? PJ love! - Bfactory | Blog Happy learning! Rahul Sir CAT Coach",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:33:47.715Z"),
    "question" : "How does anyone prepare for the CAT exam for English? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d1f0c817f0398fc58f5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-new-words-are-enough-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Hi Praveen New word learning is not the key for CAT English. Instead you should focus on contextual word learning. CAT is a reading and understanding based exam; not a memory based exam. I classify words into three categories: SWAGy words: The big ones that you learn and use just to show off - Example: bacchanalian - it means heavily drunk or prone to heavy drinking. So, I can write: I disprove of your bacchanalian friends. Such words are not EXPECTED to be known by CAT aspirants.DICTIONARY words: Words that you learn to enlarge your word tummy. For example, learning words from a word list or a word card set. You learn: abate - to reduce, abide - to agree to etc. etc. Even if you form sentences with these words, it is quite difficult to use these words and to gain enough so as to be able to rContinue Reading Hi Praveen New word learning is not the key for CAT English. Instead you should focus on contextual word learning. CAT is a reading and understanding based exam; not a memory based exam. I classify words into three categories: SWAGy words: The big ones that you learn and use just to show off - Example: bacchanalian - it means heavily drunk or prone to heavy drinking. So, I can write: I disprove of your bacchanalian friends. Such words are not EXPECTED to be known by CAT aspirants.DICTIONARY words: Words that you learn to enlarge your word tummy. For example, learning words from a word list or a word card set. You learn: abate - to reduce, abide - to agree to etc. etc. Even if you form sentences with these words, it is quite difficult to use these words and to gain enough so as to be able to rContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:34:07.438Z"),
    "question" : "How many new words are enough for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d490c817f0398fc5922"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-in-40-days-for-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How do I prepare in 40 days for CAT exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:34:49.253Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare in 40 days for CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d5c0c817f0398fc59e2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-cracku-for-CAT-exam-helpfull?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:35:08.412Z"),
    "question" : "Is cracku for CAT exam helpfull? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d700c817f0398fc59f4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/among-the-Cat-exam-and-rbi-grade-b-exam-which-one-is-more-tough?-",
    "answer" : "Before answering to which exam is difficult to appear, let's first identify what actually makes an exam difficult to one n easy to another. In this era of competitive examinations, there r 3 basic ways that make an exam difficult to candidates appearing for it, namely: The level of questions in exam is out of the reach and thus most candidates sitting in examination hall think that this exam can't be cracked.The number of candidates appearing for that examination is so large that you can't imagine getting ahead of each n every one of them, thus u think this exam can't be cracked.The number of vacancies or seats available after cracking that examination.Let me elaborate on these points by taking example of CAT and RBI Grade B examinations. In CAT, the level of examination is very high and most Continue Reading Before answering to which exam is difficult to appear, let's first identify what actually makes an exam difficult to one n easy to another. In this era of competitive examinations, there r 3 basic ways that make an exam difficult to candidates appearing for it, namely: The level of questions in exam is out of the reach and thus most candidates sitting in examination hall think that this exam can't be cracked.The number of candidates appearing for that examination is so large that you can't imagine getting ahead of each n every one of them, thus u think this exam can't be cracked.The number of vacancies or seats available after cracking that examination.Let me elaborate on these points by taking example of CAT and RBI Grade B examinations. In CAT, the level of examination is very high and most Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:35:28.878Z"),
    "question" : "among the Cat exam and rbi grade b exam which one is more tough? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d840c817f0398fc5a0d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-are-Percentilers-mocks-for-non-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "Anjali Khanna, pgdm Marketing, Indian Institute of Management Bangalore (2018)Answered 8 months agoHow are Percentilers mocks for non-CAT exams? Anjali Khanna I am glad that someone asked this question. I would suggest the best resource available for non-cat exams like NMAT, SNAP, XAT. While deciding the best test series for these exams, you should care of: The number of mocks they provided( you need a good number of practice here as most of them are mostly speed based exams, then just accuracy driven like CAT).Level of Mocks they provide.Lastly the analysis and the Prediction of cutoffs. And how does GK question in the mocks stay relevant and useful to you in the actual exam?Considering all the above parameters, I personally choose Percentilers mock test series because they provide AI-based mock (50+ full length mocks). And the analysis that I get of each and every mocks is different from any of the test series available in the market. Hope this h Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:35:48.390Z"),
    "question" : "How are Percentilers mocks for non-CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377dac0c817f0398fc5ae9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-we-use-Quora-as-a-reading-material-for-cat-exam?-",
    "answer" : "No. Most answers on Quora are short - barely a few sentences to a couple of paragraphs long. They are not always in grammatical English either - either because the writer is not a native English speaker and/or because he/she is using slang/colloquialisms. There are some excecptions to this, of course - some top writers write long and comprehensive answers in excellent English, and some are even professional writers themselves. But these kind of answers are the exception, not the rule on Quora. On the other hand, for CAT, you need to learn to read and understand long and complex articles and books, written by professionals in formal and grammatically correct English.  That said, Quora is a good place to practise writing English, if your command over is it not too good. The best way to gain pr Continue Reading No. Most answers on Quora are short - barely a few sentences to a couple of paragraphs long. They are not always in grammatical English either - either because the writer is not a native English speaker and/or because he/she is using slang/colloquialisms. There are some excecptions to this, of course - some top writers write long and comprehensive answers in excellent English, and some are even professional writers themselves. But these kind of answers are the exception, not the rule on Quora. On the other hand, for CAT, you need to learn to read and understand long and complex articles and books, written by professionals in formal and grammatically correct English.  That said, Quora is a good place to practise writing English, if your command over is it not too good. The best way to gain pr Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:36:28.952Z"),
    "question" : "Can we use Quora as a reading material for cat exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377dbe0c817f0398fc5afe"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-syllabus-for-the-CAT-exam-for-CSE-students?-",
    "answer" : "Taniya Siddiqui This is the most frequent question asked when one starts preparing for CAT. CAT is a test with no predefined syllabus, however past trends suggest that CAT tests in general aptitude including Verbal Ability (English), Quant Ability (Mathematics), Logical Reasoning (LR) and Data Interpretation (DI) skills. Similar to CAT, there are other admission tests - MAT, XAT, CMAT and SNAP. There are some B-Schools (like IIFT and IRMA) which conduct their own exam. And there are state level entrance tests for admission to colleges in respective states. English or Verbal Ability Reading comprehension, verbal reasoning, syllogisms, analogies, antonyms and synonyms, fill in the blanks, sentence correction, idioms, etc. Maths or Quant Ability Number systems, geometry, trigonometry, probability, permutation com Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:36:46.422Z"),
    "question" : "What is the syllabus for the CAT exam for CSE students? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377dd40c817f0398fc5bc7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-prepare-for-cat-exam-at-home-by-self-study?-",
    "answer" : "Maruti Konduri CAT is an exam that tests the basic aptitude and critical thinking capacity of a candidate. Cracking CAT is not a tough job, provided one is fairly thorough with the concepts learnt during high school. It is definitely possible to prepare for this exam at home via a self-structured preparation strategy. The catch: it requires a great deal of discipline, a well-drafted time-table tailored to your needs, and religiously sticking to the set plan. While preparing from home, it is essential to take a structured online CAT preparation program. CAT online preparation can help aspirants from remote areas, working professionals, and final-year college students greatly improve their grasp of the concepts. The time frame required to gain a decent grasp of the tested concepts varies from person to perso Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:37:08.329Z"),
    "question" : "How do prepare for cat exam at home by self study? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377de80c817f0398fc5bd9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-maths-compulsory-to-crack-the-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "CAT 2018 exam would be divided in to three separate sections of 1 hour each. Section 1 – Verbal Ability and Reading Comprehension (34 questions) Section 2 – Logical Reasoning and Data Interpretation (32 questions) Section 3 – Quantitative Aptitude (34 questions)As far as CAT syllabus is concerned, probably the Quantitative Aptitude section is the most well defined and the most voluminous as well. So you gotta do math to crack CAT If you’re facing some issues, you may take help of these youtube videos.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:37:28.750Z"),
    "question" : "Is maths compulsory to crack the CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377e380c817f0398fc5ce0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-should-I-apply-for-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:38:48.330Z"),
    "question" : "When should I apply for CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377e650c817f0398fc5db7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-kit-for-cat-exam-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Nice Question  Sawon Giri.  You can concentrate on following for CAT: Quantitative Ability, Data Interpretation & Logical Reasoning, Verbal and Reading Comprehension   You can join IMS, handa ka funda, PT, Career Launcher, Bulls Eye, Mindworkzz, Career Forum, Endeavor Careers, Vidyamandir, BYJU's CAT Classes, Brilliant Tutorials and more   Or you can buy their material for study at home too.  I have also written answer to this question before. Antra Anapindi's answer to How do I prepare for the CAT entrance test?   So best of luck for your exam preparation. John Miler",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:39:33.014Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best kit for cat exam preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377e9c0c817f0398fc5ea0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-qualifications-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "CAT eligibility criteria vary depending on reservation norms. You can go through this file to get detailed idea on the same. https://iimcat.ac.in/per/g01/pub/756/ASM/WebPortal/1/PDF/CAT_Eligibility_2016.pdf Best wishes Rahul Sir CAT Coach CAT PREP with IIM A Alumni",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:40:28.401Z"),
    "question" : "What are the qualifications for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377eb40c817f0398fc5f67"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Does-it-make-sense-to-give-a-third-attempt-at-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "I hope it helps because deep down inside I also wanted to go to JOKA  .Finally I settled my dream with NITIE .  I can see my glimpse in you Chandresh Kakliya",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:40:52.931Z"),
    "question" : "Does it make sense to give a third attempt at the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377ec80c817f0398fc5f7f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Did-any-candidate-score-in-the-100th-percentile-without-coaching-classes-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Konanur Lakshminarayana",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:41:12.068Z"),
    "question" : "Did any candidate score in the 100th percentile without coaching classes for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f190c817f0398fc6077"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-500-hours-enough-to-be-fully-prepared-for-CAT-exam-for-an-average-person?-",
    "answer" : "Ritesh Kumar If you can follow below given preparation strategy in 500 hrs then I think you can make pretty much difference in your CAT percentile. Give back to back fundamental mock tests for CAT. I'll recommend initial papers of TIME test series as these questions are very comprehensive and covers almost all the topics. Don't try to give intermediate papers in the start as it'll appear quite tough and you'll lose motivation for preparing. From these mock tests point out the questions that were made very easily later those questions that were not easy but anyhow you solved. These questions are from topics which is your strength.Please note down the names of topic whose questions for you appeared easy. Make a promise to yourself you'll never let these topics slip out of your hand as even in CAT exam thes Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:42:33.193Z"),
    "question" : "Is 500 hours enough to be fully prepared for CAT exam for an average person? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f390c817f0398fc6150"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Are-marks-displayed-immediately-after-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "No",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:43:05.276Z"),
    "question" : "Are marks displayed immediately after the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f4c0c817f0398fc6164"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-crack-the-CAT-exam-easily-in-my-first-attempt?-",
    "answer" : "You can only crack CAT in your first attempt if you take CAT like you have appeared for it MULTIPLE TIMES. Before going forward I would warn you, this is not going to be an easy task. A lot of DEDICATION and hard work+smart work is required to bell the CAT. Now, since you are new to it I suggest you should first take a full length mock test of CAT, this would give you your raw aptitude score. The score will give you a rough idea of how much effort is required for you to reach your dream college. After this the other major factors that come in are chose a good coaching institute for yourself or rather I should say a ‘good teacher’ who can not only teach you the various formulas, tricks, time saving shortcuts but can also guide you personally, as in what should your ideal routine be, what sho Continue Reading You can only crack CAT in your first attempt if you take CAT like you have appeared for it MULTIPLE TIMES. Before going forward I would warn you, this is not going to be an easy task. A lot of DEDICATION and hard work+smart work is required to bell the CAT. Now, since you are new to it I suggest you should first take a full length mock test of CAT, this would give you your raw aptitude score. The score will give you a rough idea of how much effort is required for you to reach your dream college. After this the other major factors that come in are chose a good coaching institute for yourself or rather I should say a ‘good teacher’ who can not only teach you the various formulas, tricks, time saving shortcuts but can also guide you personally, as in what should your ideal routine be, what sho Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:43:24.242Z"),
    "question" : "How can I crack the CAT exam easily in my first attempt? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f600c817f0398fc617a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-strategy-I-have-to-follow-to-get-95+-score-in-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Here are some of my tips for CAT ,which I followed at the time of my prepration. First, try to improve your basics of quantitative aptitude, Data Interpretation , Logical Reasoning and Verbal ability.Once the topics are covered in a decent manner, next step is to practice. Try to solve question by your own using any of the book available in market like R.S Aggarwal , R.D Sharma and Arihant Publications or any other depending on your choice and usage.Give mocks regularly atleast 2 in week and increase it with the days.Only giving mocks will not help at all. You need to analyze your strength and weakness throughout the mock and try to rectify your errors.Analyzing mocks is more important than giving ample of mocks.Read 2 to 3 articles a day on different Topics there are many good websites whiContinue Reading Here are some of my tips for CAT ,which I followed at the time of my prepration. First, try to improve your basics of quantitative aptitude, Data Interpretation , Logical Reasoning and Verbal ability.Once the topics are covered in a decent manner, next step is to practice. Try to solve question by your own using any of the book available in market like R.S Aggarwal , R.D Sharma and Arihant Publications or any other depending on your choice and usage.Give mocks regularly atleast 2 in week and increase it with the days.Only giving mocks will not help at all. You need to analyze your strength and weakness throughout the mock and try to rectify your errors.Analyzing mocks is more important than giving ample of mocks.Read 2 to 3 articles a day on different Topics there are many good websites whiContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:43:44.449Z"),
    "question" : "What is the strategy I have to follow to get 95+ score in CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f730c817f0398fc6240"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-hard-is-it-to-get-90-above-percentile-in-the-CAT-exams?-",
    "answer" : "The instant answer is going to be ‘ it depends on your intellect and hard work.’ Yes, this is true and needs a little attention towards it too. You must first check out your capability of solving simple aptitude questions so that you can plan your preparation accordingly. If you are good at aptitude skills, you can switch to CAT preparation at least 6 months before the test else starting a little more early would be helpful. If you put in the right efforts as per your need it is not really difficult to score above 90 percentile in CAT. It tests you on basics with little twists and turns which can be easily decoded through the right course and a good practice. If you are thinking to take CAT’18 refer “Handa Ka Funda for a quick revision of entire topics and then skip to taking mocks. My answerContinue Reading The instant answer is going to be ‘ it depends on your intellect and hard work.’ Yes, this is true and needs a little attention towards it too. You must first check out your capability of solving simple aptitude questions so that you can plan your preparation accordingly. If you are good at aptitude skills, you can switch to CAT preparation at least 6 months before the test else starting a little more early would be helpful. If you put in the right efforts as per your need it is not really difficult to score above 90 percentile in CAT. It tests you on basics with little twists and turns which can be easily decoded through the right course and a good practice. If you are thinking to take CAT’18 refer “Handa Ka Funda for a quick revision of entire topics and then skip to taking mocks. My answerContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:44:03.586Z"),
    "question" : "How hard is it to get 90 above percentile in the CAT exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f890c817f0398fc6254"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-syllabus-for-the-CAT-2018-exam?-",
    "answer" : "CAT 2018 will be held on 25 Nov,2018 so guys prepare yourself according to the syllabus. IIM CAT 2018 Syllabus Verbal AbilityDI/LRQuantitative abilityVerbal Ability and Reading Comprehension Correction in Sentence, Grammar or English Usage, Synonyms, Antonyms, Fill in the blanks, Jumbled Paragraph and Close Passage, Analogies and Reverse Analogies, Meaning/Usage Match, Verbal Reasoning, Summary Questions, Reading Comprehension and Facts Inferences Judgements etc. Analysis Candidates may find difficulty in understanding this section at first but with regular practice, this section can be covered within a month easily. All you need to do is take at least 2 hours each day and cover the topics in either ascending order or descending order as mentioned here. You can start with grammar section becaus Continue Reading CAT 2018 will be held on 25 Nov,2018 so guys prepare yourself according to the syllabus. IIM CAT 2018 Syllabus Verbal AbilityDI/LRQuantitative abilityVerbal Ability and Reading Comprehension Correction in Sentence, Grammar or English Usage, Synonyms, Antonyms, Fill in the blanks, Jumbled Paragraph and Close Passage, Analogies and Reverse Analogies, Meaning/Usage Match, Verbal Reasoning, Summary Questions, Reading Comprehension and Facts Inferences Judgements etc. Analysis Candidates may find difficulty in understanding this section at first but with regular practice, this section can be covered within a month easily. All you need to do is take at least 2 hours each day and cover the topics in either ascending order or descending order as mentioned here. You can start with grammar section becaus Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:44:25.868Z"),
    "question" : "What is the syllabus for the CAT 2018 exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f9c0c817f0398fc6268"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-crack-the-CAT-exam-in-about-six-months-with-a-specific-strategy?-",
    "answer" : "Hi You have approx 6 months for this CAT. Let us see the things that you can do by spending approx 180 minutes everyday and with 25 hours per week of study. 1. Read a newspaper online daily. It can done in your spare time. It could be The Hindu or Firstpost. You can also read selective articles from NYTime or Washington Post. Also start Word Power Made Easy by Norman Lewis. 2. Start watching lectures online. The website of EduSaathi can help you in that. Watch videos of all topics sequentially and solve questions. This will help you to get your basics correct. Continue the above two steps for 2 months. For self study, you can also go for the following books, For Quant, you can go for either Arun Sharma or Nishith Sinha or Quantum CAT by Sarvesh Verma. For LRDI, you can go for Arun Sharma or Nish Continue Reading Hi You have approx 6 months for this CAT. Let us see the things that you can do by spending approx 180 minutes everyday and with 25 hours per week of study. 1. Read a newspaper online daily. It can done in your spare time. It could be The Hindu or Firstpost. You can also read selective articles from NYTime or Washington Post. Also start Word Power Made Easy by Norman Lewis. 2. Start watching lectures online. The website of EduSaathi can help you in that. Watch videos of all topics sequentially and solve questions. This will help you to get your basics correct. Continue the above two steps for 2 months. For self study, you can also go for the following books, For Quant, you can go for either Arun Sharma or Nishith Sinha or Quantum CAT by Sarvesh Verma. For LRDI, you can go for Arun Sharma or Nish Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:44:44.051Z"),
    "question" : "How do I crack the CAT exam in about six months with a specific strategy? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377fb10c817f0398fc6332"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-are-reading-comprehensions-so-tough-of-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Hello It is actually not these days. RC is the scoring section in CAT. Key is to practice three things properly: Contextual word learningCentral idea based readingElimination of optionsRefer to this answer: Rahul Anand's answer to What is the best approach to solve RC in CAT? Practice, RC is scoring and CAT 16 level was easy. I remember finishing the section 10 minutes before time. The level of English coming these days is simple, the options are confusing. So, practice well. Best wishes Rahul Sir Note: You can attend my Number system free webinar on 20th July. Link to register: CAT NUMBER SYSTEM WEBINAR 10",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:45:05.938Z"),
    "question" : "Why are reading comprehensions so tough of CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377fe60c817f0398fc640f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-certificates-required-for-cat-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Nishant Bhamare",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:45:58.710Z"),
    "question" : "What are the certificates required for cat exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377ffe0c817f0398fc642c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-app-for-the-GMAT-and-CAT-exam-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "For CAT I'd suggest the M-SIS app of Career launcher. You can practice through 5000+ questions. have an in-built vocab builder and get daily GK updates. It'll be very very beneficial for you!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:46:22.633Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best app for the GMAT and CAT exam preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780130c817f0398fc6442"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-1-year-enough-to-prepare-for-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "You may find it tough to digest but, yes it's completely worth to spend one year for the CAT exam. See, if you are in the final year of your graduation, then preparing for CAT is the nost beneficial at this time. CAT is an exam which has questions of high difficulty level. It might not be wrong to say that CAT is one of the most difficult MBA entrance examinations alongside XAT. So giving a year for CAT is like giving a year for all MBA entrance exams provided you take them. If you have prepared hard for this, then other exams will feel like a snap of fingers. You can easily clear the written round of your campus recruitments. So, if you see from this point of view, it does have a lot of advantages. Now you have to have 3 qualities, besides preparation which would help you in acing it. DediContinue Reading You may find it tough to digest but, yes it's completely worth to spend one year for the CAT exam. See, if you are in the final year of your graduation, then preparing for CAT is the nost beneficial at this time. CAT is an exam which has questions of high difficulty level. It might not be wrong to say that CAT is one of the most difficult MBA entrance examinations alongside XAT. So giving a year for CAT is like giving a year for all MBA entrance exams provided you take them. If you have prepared hard for this, then other exams will feel like a snap of fingers. You can easily clear the written round of your campus recruitments. So, if you see from this point of view, it does have a lot of advantages. Now you have to have 3 qualities, besides preparation which would help you in acing it. DediContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:46:43.628Z"),
    "question" : "Is 1 year enough to prepare for the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037804e0c817f0398fc652c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-do-freshers-take-cat-exams?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Kumar Ishu 1",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:47:42.581Z"),
    "question" : "When do freshers take cat exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780610c817f0398fc65f8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-does-it-take-to-clear-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "CAT Preparation: An IIM Dream A rockstar, in his jet-black attire, presiding over a meeting in a swanky conference room, is how Indian Cinema portrays management professionals. This is the MBA dream, chasing which thousands of aspiring students take the Common Admission Test (CAT) every year. These points are for those dream chasers and how they can stand out of the crowd: 1. Take a CAT diagnostic test See where you stand take CAT mock tests It is always necessary to know where you stand and where your strengths and weaknesses lie. For exams like CAT, people of different backgrounds take the test and analysing your position and preparing a study plan accordingly would surely lead you to success. 2. More practice and less theory More practice, less theory for CATGoing through the portions, one th Continue Reading CAT Preparation: An IIM Dream A rockstar, in his jet-black attire, presiding over a meeting in a swanky conference room, is how Indian Cinema portrays management professionals. This is the MBA dream, chasing which thousands of aspiring students take the Common Admission Test (CAT) every year. These points are for those dream chasers and how they can stand out of the crowd: 1. Take a CAT diagnostic test See where you stand take CAT mock tests It is always necessary to know where you stand and where your strengths and weaknesses lie. For exams like CAT, people of different backgrounds take the test and analysing your position and preparing a study plan accordingly would surely lead you to success. 2. More practice and less theory More practice, less theory for CATGoing through the portions, one th Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:48:01.945Z"),
    "question" : "What does it take to clear CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780750c817f0398fc660a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-convert-my-33percentile-in-CAT-exam-to-a-90percentile?-",
    "answer" : "Sumit Singh Gandhi - (Rahul ), CATKing Founder and CEO, CAT Mentor, SPJIMR Graduate, HARVARD Executive MBAAnswered 4 years ago · Author has 1.3K answers and 3.7M answer viewsHow should I convert my 33percentile in CAT exam to a 90percentile? Sumit Singh Gandhi - (Rahul )",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:48:21.841Z"),
    "question" : "How should I convert my 33percentile in CAT exam to a 90percentile? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780880c817f0398fc661f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-coaching-is-good-for-a-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:48:40.043Z"),
    "question" : "Which coaching is good for a CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037809e0c817f0398fc66e8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-approach-to-learning-LRDI-for-the-CAT-exam-online?-",
    "answer" : "in 2017, there were more than 500 persons who were able to climb the Mount Everest. BUT, there was NOT a single person in the country who could get 100% marks (96 out of 96) in DILR section of CAT 2017. Welcome to the world of DILR -Data Interpretation and Logical Reasoning - the most terrifying, gut-wrenching section in CAT. When you start preparing for this section, very soon you will realize that climbing Mount Everest is an easier task when compared to getting 100% in DILR. So, Nobody got 100% marks in DILR in CAT 2017. So does that imply that that it is IMPOSSIBLE to get to IIMs ? Does that imply there is NO point going for CAT ? OK !! Let’s get to some facts pertaining to last year 2017. A net score of 67 + marks (out of 96) in DILR -> 100 percentile.A net score of 48 marks -> 99 percentileA net score of 36 marks -> 95 percentile.The numbers speak all. YES !! It is all about a right strategy !! Deep knowledge, a good strategy, practising all possible variants + a dose of luck are what is required to be able to cross 95 percentile. It can be seen that anyone solving 3 sets (out of 8 sets) CORRECTLY would have moved to 95 + percentile. One need NOT get 100% marks. Even 60% marks is a MASSIVE score !! Immense Respect !! Let’s try and understand the section. There is a great deal of randomness and high level of uncertainty when it comes to DILR section. Even if you complete all the qs from all the books in Universe (related to DI/LR), there will still be something new, something very different which you may come across in the exam. Why is it that the section is so obnoxious ? One of the major reasons is the questions (in DI/LR) are designed set based (and not individual qs like which are there in Quant. By set based qs, I mean some information will be provided in the form of caselet or charts and followed by 4 qs). While, the decision to leave a Quant question can happen very fast (say in about 30 sec or max of about 1 min per question). But here, in DI/LR, you can never be sure as to when to quit (You might have spent about 12 mins on a particular set and then you feel like enough is enough, there is no point in going ahead with this set, the set is way too difficult and you just want to leave that set, you have already consumed about 12 mins. But then you never know.. had you spend may be one more minute that set would have been all yours. So, it's a very tricky situation. To be able to decide when to quit !! Just imagine, if you spend about 10 mins in decoding every set so as just to come to conclusion whether to attempt the set or leave the set, this can be disastrous. We will land up spending about 40-50 mins (out of 60 mins) in figuring out which all sets are difficult and without any major break through!! (So, as a remedy for the same, one has to discipline oneself in not spending unnecessary amount of time and fix an upper limit of say 5 mins on any set and in case, no breakthrough is happening in that 5 mins, one has to come out of that set quickly). The second perspective from where the set has become very difficult is even if we do crack the set and are able to decode the subtleties of the same, still there are bound to be at least 1 question (out of 4 qs) per set which will be extremely difficult (which will have a tendency to demoralize even seasoned professionals). So, the question is how to tackle such uncertain, ambiguous and highly volatile scenarios. Tell me some good news !! The good news is out of 100% of DI/LR section, there is that 50% which is still doable (and one can figure those out during the exam). So, the challenge is NOT about doing difficult sets but about finding easy sets from a pool of qs and focusiing only on those sets. In other words, one can say (with a reasonably high level of accuracy) that if you can crack 4 sets completely (out of max 8 sets), 97 percentile minimum (worst case scenario) is not gone anywhere. For each of the last 3 years, this has been the norm. A) PREPARATION FOR DI PART 1) Calculations, Calculations and Calculations Half of DI is sheer calculations. The other half is Comprehension. Practice Speed Maths - regular practice required (Daily about 5-10 mins) (Speed Maths related to calculations (Addition, subtraction, % calculations, comparison of fractions). This builds confidence especially dealing with Calculation Intensive qs. For e.g, on that front, you got to practice basic things like (Note: The following are very elementary things, the qs of these types can never be asked in exam but the absence of these can simply dampen the prospects of speeding up the prep level). a) Tables upto 20 (For e.g, what is 126 as a product of two numbers in all possible forms). If you are taking more than 10 seconds, that means you have to work on this front. b) Squares upto 25. Ofcourse, for other numbers (in general squares of any other number, be it a 2 digit, 3 digit, 4 digit, you should be able to arrive at in max of 15 sec). c) Fractions and multiples. You cannot ignore this one. This is so so important, almost half of DI questions are built around percentage calculations. A good command over Percentage calculations is such an important prerequisite. Just check this how comfortable you are on this front. For e.g, any of the following calculations should be done in less than 20 seconds (for each question). a) 44% of 972 b) 37% of 864 c) What is 48% of 80 ? d) What % of 48 is 80 ? d) A number changes by 20%, 30%, -10% and then again by -10% successively. What is one single change equivalent to that (without using pen and pencil) Don’t worry if you have not been able to get the answers for the above questions in the time limit as specified. A high degree of mental toughness is required. Work hard and you will DO it !! We all are blessed with infinte level of mental toughness. We should just believe in that. For the points as mentioned above, spend about 10 mins (daily) but be consistent about that. You be creator of the questions and you be the judge (in terms of the time you are taking to solve qs) II) COMPREHENSION Considering the nature of qs coming across, many a times it so happens that the entire set gets missed out because we are not able to understand a “particular line/word in the set of about 15 lines” in that caselet. That could be very painful. Consider the following words. -> “Only”, “At least”, “At most”, “Not greater than”, “Not lesser than”, “Unless”, “Only if” etc. Again, this is one area where you have to practice so much that even the intricate lines can be comprehended with ease. Just read a lot (just read and read and read and read) from variety of topics especially Business newspapers, different games (like Football, Hockey etc) -that will help in visualizing what happens in qs related to Games and tournaments or just about any article and every article. Basically, you have to develop a likingness towards large chunk of data (given in any form). III) LOGIC BASED Questions: Out of 4 sets in DI (16 qs in DI), you can expect about 8 Calculation intensive qs and 8 so difficult logic based qs which can put even the champions to sleep. The only thing is not to fall in the trap of such qs (which are time guzzlers). Early identification of such qs (generally such qs are easier to identify as you will not find too much of information leading to hundreds of cases to start with to finally leading to one or two cases after a great range of iterations). Some sets look harmless in the beginning but there are so much of complexities inbuilt there. We just need to be extremely cautious about such sets. The only way to practice is a sort of recognition before hand that there are bound to be qs of such types (qs are intentionally designed like that to check not the intelligence level of the candidates but to check if you can identify such qs and leave these qs early on or not). IV) Maxima, Minima types qs: Generally, the qs can be classified as “qs which have unique answer” or “Qs which have a range of answers” hence leading to “Maxima or minima”. Usually, these types of qs come with a flavour of “Venn diagram” model. For e.g 100 students like Maths, 200 students like Physics while there are 250 students. Find the “MAXIMUM” or “MINIMUM” number of students who like either “Maths or Physics” OR something like “Maths & Physics”. Once, you are very comfortable with all these models of qs (related to 2 variables, 3 variables, 4 variables or even advanced cases) that will have a tremendous impact when you are solving qs (may not be of this kind but related to something else V) Exposure to different charts Learn about basic models of qs surrounding Pie charts, lines, Tables, 3 D charts. B) PREPARATION FOR LOGICAL REASONING -some of the topics as enlisted below. Distribution (Matching)Venn DiagramSeating Arrangement (Linear)Seating Arrangement (Circular)Quant based ReasoningCubes (In 2015 (One set - 4 qs came across)Binary Logic, Selection, Comparison,Solve 3–4 good sets in DI LR on a daily basis from the above set of models. But Be mentally prepared for any maverick set coming across much different from types as outlined earlier. Have a deep desire to master this area and that’s what matters !! As someone has rightly said → And when you want something, the entire UNIVERSE conspires in helping you to achieve it !! -Paulo Coelho GO GET IT !!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:49:02.575Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best approach to learning LRDI for the CAT exam online? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780b20c817f0398fc66f8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-much-time-should-be-given-in-each-section-of-the-CAT?-",
    "answer" : "Invalid question. This year each section has fixed amount of time allotted: 60 mins. So you have \"60 minutes to fame\" for each of the three sections: QA, DILR & VARC.  When you practice before your CAT, time your test for 1 hr & divide each hour of test in 2 parts-50 mins of answering followed by 10 mins of revision. [Note: The question of revision only arises if you complete the section in 50 mins. Complete it means completing all the answers which you know correctly. Do not guess! If you don't complete your known and/or do-able portions within 50 mins, then forget revision & work on the other questions.]",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:49:22.967Z"),
    "question" : "How much time should be given in each section of the CAT? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780c40c817f0398fc670d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/For-which-engineering-branch-do-most-students-appear-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Saurebh",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:49:40.437Z"),
    "question" : "For which engineering branch do most students appear for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780dc0c817f0398fc67d4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-the-CAT-exam-useful-for-architecture?-",
    "answer" : "The Common Admission Test (CAT) is an online test for admission in a graduate management program. The test consists of three sections: Verbal Ability and Reading Comprehension (VARC), Data Interpretation and Logical Reasoning (DILR), and Quantitative Ability (QA). Overall it’s a three-hour online exam divided into one hour each section. The Indian Institutes of Management (IIMs) started this exam and use the test for selecting students for their business administration programs (MBA or PGDM). The test is conducted every year by one of the IIMs based on a policy of rotation. CAT exam is not useful if you are keen on getting into architecture.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:50:04.160Z"),
    "question" : "How is the CAT exam useful for architecture? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603781020c817f0398fc67fa"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-are-the-years-did-IIM-Bangalore-conduct-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Kumar Sumit",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:50:42.406Z"),
    "question" : "Which are the years did IIM Bangalore conduct the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603781150c817f0398fc68c1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-is-the-CAT-exam-conducted?-",
    "answer" : "Questions 1",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:51:01.586Z"),
    "question" : "When is the CAT exam conducted? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603781670c817f0398fc69b6"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Do-you-think-Narendra-Modi-has-the-intelligence-to-crack-the-CAT-exam-and-get-into-IIMs?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Satyam Bhardwaj 3",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:52:23.614Z"),
    "question" : "Do you think Narendra Modi has the intelligence to crack the CAT exam and get into IIMs? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037818c0c817f0398fc6a91"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-the-CAT-exam-designed-in-such-a-way-that-it-benefits-engineering-students-more-than-commerce-students?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is the CAT exam designed in such a way that it benefits engineering students more than commerce students?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:53:00.755Z"),
    "question" : "Is the CAT exam designed in such a way that it benefits engineering students more than commerce students? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037819f0c817f0398fc6aa1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-benefit-of-preparing-for-the-CAT-exam?-",
    "answer" : "There is no benefit of preparing for the CAT exam one scores quite high percentile so that one can get admission in MBA in one of the top IIMs of the country or about 2 or 3 other Non-IIMs of the country.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:53:19.540Z"),
    "question" : "What is the benefit of preparing for the CAT exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603781b20c817f0398fc6abd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-write-the-CAT-exam-without-the-intention-to-do-an-MBA-but-just-to-get-a-high-profile-job?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:53:38.837Z"),
    "question" : "Can I write the CAT exam without the intention to do an MBA but just to get a high-profile job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
